<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ew</transcriber>
    <date>2007-?-?</date>
    <place>Ukya, Nasarawa, Nigeria</place>
    <author><gender>?</gender><age>18</age><ethnic-group>?</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>STORY TELLING</heading>
    <p>Once upon a time there was a man named 
    <x-anonym-x type="first-name"/> who grew many farm products in his 
    farm, and there he was known as the greatest farmer amongst the 
    nearest Com<punctuation>-</punctuation>munities. <x-anonym-x type="first-name"/> 
    grew yams, <error corrected="sweet">suit</error> potatoes 
    <error corrected=",">.</error> rice and other food crops in his 
    farm but <deleted>1 word</deleted> he had no child or 
    <error corrected="grandson">grand son</error> in his alive family 
    <error corrected=".">,</error> He was the man that the villagers 
    kno<punctuation>-</punctuation>wn as the <deleted>man</deleted> person who gathered 
    the crops each harvesting period but never share to poors. One day 
    he was travelling on his foot all the way to a nearest village 
    beside his village. There he saw a lorry passing by and stop the 
    lorry to take the rescue of his hardship since he could not walked 
    long <deleted>1 word</deleted> hence he was getting old as a 
    <deleted>1 word</deleted> man of 78 <error corrected="years">
    yrs</error> old. <error corrected="Mr">mr</error> Lorry stop and 
    had a pit<punctuation>-</punctuation> <deleted>l</deleted>y of the old man 
    <error corrected=".">,</error> He picked him up his lorry to the 
    <unclear words="1"/> village, but on <error corrected="their">
    there</error> way to the village there was a big river which it 
    harden the lorries to cross to the next edge of the river 
    <error corrected="."/> when they get there they stop and asked the 
    old man to get down before they <error corrected="would">
    wuld</error> cross slowly<error corrected=".">,</error> as the old 
    man get down he <error corrected="fell">felt</error> 
    <error corrected="inside">in side</error> the water which he asked 
    for a <deleted>resuce</deleted> rescue but the driver and the motor 
    boys answered <deleted>we</deleted> we cannot take <deleted>2 
    characters</deleted> donkey to the river and force it to drink, 
    meaning we have <error corrected="shorten">short</error> your 
    Journey and here we worry about <deleted>1 word</deleted> our lorry 
    which <unclear words="1"/> us than you. it possible you should find 
    <deleted>a</deleted> a solution to remove yourself from the water 
    so that you will not get <deleted>1 word</deleted> drown.</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
