<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ew</transcriber>
    <date>2007-05-23</date>
    <place>Ukya, Nasarawa, Nigeria</place>
    <author><gender>m</gender><age>18</age><ethnic-group>Hausa</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <p>House Number 12,</p>
    <p>Block D, prince</p>
    <p><x-anonym-x type="first-name"/> Modern</p>
    <p>Estate, <x-anonym-x type="location"/>.</p>
    <p><x-anonym-x type="location"/> Nigeria<punctuation>.</punctuation></p>
    <p>23rd May, 2007<punctuation>.</punctuation></p>
    <p>Dear <x-anonym-x type="first-name"/><punctuation>.</punctuation></p>
    <p>Hello<error corrected=","/> dearest friend.</p>
    <p>How are you and <deleted>1 character</deleted> how are you 
    coping with the cold weather over there in the States
    <error corrected="?">.</error> I know <error corrected="it&apos;s">
    its</error> been long we&apos;ve not heard from one another 
    <error corrected=","/> but not to worry much. all is fine. My 
    reasons of writing this letter to you is to know how you are doing 
    over there and to intimate or inform you about the last 
    populat<punctuation>-</punctuation>ion and housing Census which took place here in 
    <error corrected="Nigeria">nigeria</error>. 
    <x-anonym-x type="first-name"/>, I want you to know that it was a 
    different thing <error corrected="altogether">all together</error>, 
    quite different from the previous ones. the reason is because
    <error superfluous="yes">,</error> the just concluded census does 
    not only care to know about the number of people alone, but it 
    cared to know about the number of houses, the number of people 
    living in each room, in short<error corrected=","/> it inquired 
    <deleted>abat</deleted> about the standard of living of the people. 
    The nation and the citizens stands to gain <error corrected="a lot">
    alot</error> from the just concluded Census.</p>
    <p>The first benefit I want to talk about is this. The just 
    concluded census will help the government in times of future 
    <error corrected="planning">planing</error>. Since the government 
    knows the number of people and their standard of living, it will 
    help the government to know the type of economic 
    <error corrected="programmes">programes</error> to 
    <error corrected="embark">emback</error> on in order to improve the 
    people&apos;s standard of living.</p>
    <p>Secondly, The just concluded population and housing Census will 
    help the government in the efficient and equitable distribution of 
    fiscal allocations and other national benefits. The census will 
    help the government to know the areas that are much populated and 
    those which are less populated<error corrected=","/> so that in 
    times of distributing or allocating resources and other things no 
    part will be cheated.</p>
    <p>finally, The last population and housing Census will make the 
    government have accurate information on the entire economic, social 
    and educat<punctuation>-</punctuation>ional level of the country. the Census will 
    provide the government <error corrected="with">will</error> the 
    number of unemployed graduates, the number of undergraduates, the 
    estimate or possible growth of the population in the few coming 
    years and other important informations that will be useful to the 
    government is <error corrected="planning">planing</error> for their 
    economic strategies. So <x-anonym-x type="first-name"/>, you see 
    the benefit the country stands to get out of the just concluded 
    Census. please make sure you return <error corrected="home">
    hom</error> during the summer holiday because we really missed 
    you.</p>
    <p>Thanks<error corrected="."/></p>
    <p><error corrected="yours">Your&apos;s</error> Affectionate</p>
    <p>friend, <x-anonym-x type="first-name"/></p>
    <p>(The Don <x-anonym-x type="first-name"/><punctuation>.</punctuation>)</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
