<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>lc</transcriber>
    <date>2005</date>
    <place>Ile-Ife</place>
    <author><gender>f</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>Yoruba</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <p>The classical or traditional grammar was the grammar of the 
    ancient Greeks (Latin). This grammar was ‚Äòcase based‚Äô, that is, the 
    function of the word varies in a sentence as whether a subject, an 
    object or an indirect object. This means that the function of a 
    word is based on the appropriateness of the inflections. English 
    for specific purposes emerged after the classical or traditional 
    grammar or description model and as such, the description model did 
    not have or rather does not have a strong hold on ESP (English for 
    specific purposes). However there are contributions of this 
    description model that ESP largely drew from.</p>
    <p>The first contribution of this description model is the Register 
    analysis, which is among the development of ESP. The notion that 
    language varies according to context gave rise to the need of a 
    particular language for a particular language situation. Register 
    analysis therefore proves relevant in designing a syllabus for a 
    particular language context. However, the content of a syllabus 
    cannot be solely based on the register analysis of the particular 
    field in that, there can be similarities between one field and 
    another. Take for instance, the teaching of simple sentences 
    <coll for="and">&amp;</coll> compound sentences can be included in 
    the syllabus of a science subject like Chemistry, so also simple 
    and compound sentences can also be included in the syllabus of 
    Grammar for English students. What this means is that although 
    Register analysis is relevant in designing a syllabus for various 
    fields or subjects, it should not be the only basis for selecting 
    and sequencing items in a syllabus.</p>
    <p>Another contribution of the classical description model is in 
    the area of structures and forms. That is, the structures and forms 
    of a language was introduced by this model and it‚Äôs description by 
    the model is still being alluded to. English for Specific purposes 
    also draws from this as learners are being taught the structure and 
    forms of the language in order to fully understand the language. 
    Mere teaching the language or a language without teaching its 
    structure and forms is like teaching only what the language can do 
    without teaching what basically holds the language. That is, the 
    structure and form serves as the basis which should not in any way 
    be neglected.</p>
    <p>The structural description or structuralism came after the 
    classical or traditional description and it proved useful to a 
    language like English which is a word-ordered language. Its 
    contributions to English from which ESP draws from is the ‚Äòslot and 
    filter‚Äô form, which can also be referred to as the substitution 
    table. Here, words are arranged in a way that some are left to be 
    arranged, that is, learners are asked to find substitutes to the 
    words arranged. They are to include words that can be used in place 
    of the original word and then arrange them accordingly. This will 
    enable them to think and carry out the task.</p>
    <p>Another contribution of the structural description is the 
    structural syllabus. In the structural syllabus, items to be taught 
    are arranged in the form of the simple and immediately used ones 
    are taught before the complex ones. This means that those forms or 
    items that will seem relevant or useful to the immediate needs of 
    the learners are taught before those that are not needed 
    immediately. Teaching the simple items before the complex ones will 
    enable learners learn faster and easily as learners approach a 
    field with items that they are more familiar with. This will also 
    make them interested in the teaching process, that is, it will 
    ignite their motivation to learn.</p>
    <p>Structural description also introduced the surface level of 
    language description which deals with the 
    <deleted>competence</deleted> performance one has in a language. 
    That is, it is the surface level that accounts for the performance 
    of a learner in a language. Though, the surface level accounts for 
    the performance but something enables the surface level to be able 
    to account for the performance and this is the deeper level of 
    meaning. It is of good importance when one has proficiency in a 
    language but it is also of great importance if one or the learner 
    knows the rules that enable him or her to be able to generate rules 
    from the deeper level. Thus, the grammar of a language is not the 
    surface level of a language but the rules that enables learners to 
    generate the surface level from the deeper level. The structural 
    description however did not lay much emphasis on the deeper level 
    but only the surface level of meaning.</p>
    <p><deleted>&quot;English for Specific purposes (ESP=) is not a 
    variety of English but rather an approach to language learning in 
    which all decisions as to content and method are based on learners 
    reasons for learning&quot;.</deleted></p>
    <p><deleted>Hutchinson</deleted></p>
    <p>‚ÄúEnglish for specific purposes (ESP) is not a variety of English 
    but rather an approach to language learning in which all decisions 
    as to content and method are based on 
    <error corrected="learners&apos;">learners</error> reason for 
    learning.‚Ä?</p>
    <p>Hutchinson et al 1987</p>
    <p>The above quotation simply states what ESP is about, that is, 
    the essence of ESP is to meet the specific needs of the learners. 
    ESP asserts needs and strategies motivation in which subject matter 
    and relevant skills are taught. That is, the needs of the learners 
    are found out and met, the motivation of the learner is required to 
    do this and the particular skill(s) the learner needs are 
    taught.</p>
    <p>General English is more like the English everyone is taught, the 
    basics of the language. The structure, the forms that make up the 
    language. That is, the rudiments of the English language. General 
    English is more of the academic purpose, that is, it is usually 
    learnt in school, it is taught to students.</p>
    <p>English for specific purposes (ESP) and General English share 
    some similarities in that learners of ESP and General English must 
    or should know the rudiments of the language. ESP assumes that its 
    learners must have a knowledge of the language, they are only in an 
    ESP class because they need a skill to be proficient and efficient 
    in their place of work. ESP learners are professionals who as I 
    mentioned earlier needs English to meet their specific needs. 
    Another similarity between ESP and general English is that in 
    either case, a particular skill is taught. In general English all 
    the four skills of listening, speaking, reading and writing are 
    taught but in ESP a particular skill is taught. It still boils down 
    to the fact that a skill is being taught whether all or one.</p>
    <p>English for specific purposes (ESP) and general English also 
    differ in some areas. ESP learners are intermediate or adult 
    learners who are learning English to improve their proficiency and 
    efficiency in their place of assignment, while general English 
    learners are pupils, students who are learning English in order to 
    be competent in the language. This shows that while ESP is geared 
    towards commercial purposes, organising seminars for learners, 
    General English is geared towards academic purposes.</p>
    <p>ESP centers on language in context. It is particular about the 
    context where the learners will use the language. It is geared 
    towards making the learners excel well in their area of speciality. 
    General English therefore is aimed at making the learners good 
    users of the language, using it to excel in their academic pursuit 
    and good communicators in the language.</p>
    <p>In English for specific purposes (ESP), a particular skill is 
    taught to the learner, this is the skill that the learner needs to 
    succeed in his/her place of jurisdiction. The skill can either be a 
    speaking, listening, writing or reading skill. The reading skill 
    however is seldom taught to ESP learners. In General English on the 
    other hand, all the four skills of reading, speaking, listening and 
    writing are taught to the learners, this is because they are 
    expected to be an ‚Äòall rounder‚Äô, that is to know and excel in all 
    the skills.</p>
    <p>ESP is usually learner centered as against General English that 
    is language centered. That is, it is the learner that is the focus 
    of the ESP expert, the learner is what is at the back of his mind, 
    how to teach the learner and enable him or her to excel and for his 
    or her needs to be met. In the General English on the other hand, 
    it is the language that is paramount to the teacher, how to teach 
    the language to the students to make them comprehend it.</p>
    <p>ESP learners approach the study field through the areas that 
    they are familiar with. The interest of the learners is ignited 
    once they see the <deleted>need</deleted> use of the learning 
    learning to meet their immediate needs. General English is however 
    not for immediate needs, it can be for future needs.</p>
    <p>While general English is taught in school, ESP can be taught in 
    halls, hotels, as long as the environment is conducive for 
    learning.</p>
    <p>a) The origin of ESP</p>
    <p>Three factors are responsible for the origin of ESP and they 
    are:</p>
    <p>1. A brave new world</p>
    <p>2. A revolution in linguistics</p>
    <p>3. A focus on the learner</p>
    <p>1. A brave new world: The end of the second world war in 1945 
    brought about an age of unprecedented expansion in the technical, 
    economic and scientific activity which was unified by two 
    dominating forces; technology and commerce. The unrelenting 
    progress of these two forces saw the need of an international 
    language. This role however fell on English. Prior to this time, 
    people learnt a language without asking why they were learning it, 
    they just learnt the language for the justification of learning it. 
    People however saw the need for English as it was the language of 
    the international <editor-comment>currency</editor-comment>. A new 
    generation of people then came about as they saw the importance to 
    learn English. Business men and women learnt in English so as to 
    carry out their business successfully, doctors learnt English so as 
    to write prescriptions accordingly, secretaries learnt English so 
    as to write memos and letters well. The oil crisis of the 1970s 
    also contributed to this development as their was a mass flow of 
    funds into the Western and oil rich countries, English then became 
    a big time business as people saw it as meeting their required 
    goals.</p>
    <p>2. A revolution in linguistics: Linguistics has traditionally 
    been accustomed to describing the features of a language but the 
    attention however shifted to communication uses, that is how 
    language is used for communication. The guiding principle of ESP 
    however became ‚Äòtell me what you need English for and I‚Äôll tell you 
    the English you need.‚Ä?</p>
    <p>3. A focus on the learner: The educational psychology 
    <deleted>at the</deleted> until the 20th century shifted to the 
    learner. The interests of the learner was taken into cognisance. 
    The whole essence of the language was therefore based on the needs 
    of the learner.</p>
    <p>b) Target needs</p>
    <p>Target needs are the needs a learner needs in order to function 
    well in a target situation. The linguistic features of the target 
    situation should be taken note of and aimed at in order for the 
    learner to carry out his or her duties in the target situation. The 
    target needs are divided into three, they are <error corrected=":">
    ;</error></p>
    <p>1. Necessities</p>
    <p>2. Lacks</p>
    <p>3. Wants.</p>
    <p>Necessities are what is needed in the target situation, that is 
    what is in the target situation, that the learner doesn‚Äôt have.</p>
    <p>Lacks are what the learner needs to succeed in the target 
    situation, that is, what is missing in the learner.</p>
    <p>Wants are what the learner requires in the target situation and 
    they should not be overlooked.</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
