<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2009-02-22</date>
    <place>http://mynaijanews.com/</place>
    <author><gender>m</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>?</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>War Child: A Novel by Bruce Cerew</heading>
    <p>Upon witnessing the explosion its creators had mixed reactions. 
    However one thing was certain, they had ushered in a new dimension 
    to war and the equilibrium in our existence. &quot;<quote>I am 
    become Death, the destroyer of worlds</quote>&quot; Cried Robert 
    Oppenheimer as he watched the mushroom cloud of radioactive vapour 
    rise into the cloud, leaving only fragments of jade green 
    radioactive glass in the soil and a horrendous weapon of war for 
    mankind.</p>
    <p>The history of mankind is a tale of an endless episode of 
    violence, death, bloodshed and the misery all in the name of war. 
    In spite of these harsh realities mankind continues to be plagued 
    by this terror. Benjamin Franklin once said, ‚Äú<quote>There never 
    was a good war or a bad peace</quote>‚Ä? yet sadly we are forced to 
    hear and see the frightening images of innocent men, women and 
    children who have been murdered, maimed, raped, tortured and 
    scarred by conflicts in their localities.</p>
    <p>Driven by the will to survive, the victims are forced to flee 
    their homes and seek refuge in the indignity of life as <error>
    a</error> hopeless nomads and refugees. In the process they attempt 
    to cross paths strewn with perils, despair and hopelessness; many 
    perish, some fall prey to uncertainty and many never have another 
    shot at the better life they desperately seek. Yet the fortunate 
    few that brave the hazardous circumstances end up in the chains of 
    destitution, discrimination and under the constant shadow of fears 
    in cities of the Western nations.</p>
    <p>The ‚Äò‚ÄôWar Child‚Äô‚Äô by Bruce Cerew is a book that chronicles the 
    tales of war; as seen through the eye of a boy, Ray, its 
    protagonist and victim of horrors of the conflicts in Sierra Leone 
    and Liberia. The book paints a true picture of the plight of 
    refugees and the horrors they are so atrociously forced upon by 
    lending credence to the voices of the maimed men, women, and 
    children scarred and ravaged by war.</p>
    <p>The 318 page ‚ÄúWar Child‚Ä? is written as a narrative and employs a 
    simple diction to tell its story. It is a tale of humor and 
    tragedy, courage and fear, hopelessness and anticipation, love and 
    betrayal, hope and triumph. ‚ÄúWar Child‚Ä? in set in Nigeria, Sierra 
    Leone, Liberia and the Netherlands.</p>
    <p>The book begins with Ray‚Äôs struggles in life beginning from an 
    early age in Eastern Nigeria. The young Ray was constantly abused 
    by his father (a compulsive gambler and an alcoholic) who could not 
    come to terms with the boy‚Äôs inadequacies. Ray was thus sent away 
    to the village of Amata to live with his grandmother. There Ray 
    finds love, fear and mysterious character in whom he suddenly finds 
    a friend and comforter.</p>
    <p>Now grown the boy Ray puts aside childhood traumas and 
    insecurities returns to the city in search of a livelihood. But his 
    hallucinations reappeared handing him the feeling of emptiness and 
    his fears and delusions.</p>
    <p>In search of greener pastures away from hassles of life in 
    Nigeria, Ray emigrates to Monrovia. But before he could settle in 
    the country was thrown into conflict. The war ushered in a time of 
    bloodshed, death, sorrow and anguish. Ray forced to flee to 
    Freetown, Sierra Leone in the hope for a life away from the misery 
    of carnage in Liberia. But yet again the gates of Hell were cast 
    open.</p>
    <p>The second part of ‚ÄúWar Child‚Ä? begins Ray‚Äôs eventual flight to 
    the Netherlands where Ray meets Jamo and Bar. The plot in the tale 
    of their freedom from war, poverty and uncertainty in Africa 
    climaxes with the rejection, misgivings and hardships of life in 
    the observation camp. Living with other refugees the trio are 
    challenged by myriad elements and the harsh realities of life in 
    the west.</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
