<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2009-10-19</date>
    <place>http://thenationonlineng.net/web2/</place>
    <author><gender>m</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>Yoruba</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>Toyota Camry reshapes for 2010</heading>
    <p><boldface>With a mid-size four-door sedan offered in four trim 
    levels, award-winning Toyota Camry has received a number of updates 
    to become a force to reckon with in 2010. Top among them is a 
    2<punctuation>.</punctuation>5-litre four-cylinder base engine that replaces the 
    previous 2<punctuation>.</punctuation>4-litre unit and comes in two versions, writes 
    TAJUDEEN ADEBANJO</boldface> <error corrected="."/></p>
    <p>The 2010 Toyota Camry has all the character of a reliable 
    machine behind the wheel. Roomy cabin, extraordinarily refined and 
    fuel-efficient V6, quiet and cushy ride, excellent crash test 
    records among others.</p>
    <p>The changes include a restyled grille and taillights, a new 
    optional audio system with satellite radio and Bluetooth for base 
    and LE models, and auto up/down windows on all four doors.</p>
    <p>Stability control is now standard across the model range.</p>
    <p>Award winning Camry receives a number of updates for 2010, chief 
    among them a new 2<punctuation>.</punctuation>5-liter four-cylinder base engine that 
    replaces the previous 2<punctuation>.</punctuation>4-liter unit and comes in two 
    versions (the SE gets the more powerful version).</p>
    <p>Also, both the manual and automatic transmissions now have six 
    speeds instead of five.</p>
    <p>The 2010 Toyota Camry is a midsize four-door sedan offered in 
    four trim levels - base, LE, SE and XLE.</p>
    <p>The base Camry comes only with a four-cylinder engine, while the 
    other trims offer a choice between the four-cylinder and a V6.</p>
    <p>The base Camry features 16-inch steel wheels, air-conditioning, 
    auto up/down windows for all four doors, a six-speaker CD audio 
    system with an auxiliary input jack, a tilt-and-telescoping 
    steering wheel, cruise control, full power accessories and a 60/40 
    split-folding rear seat. The Camry LE adds keyless entry and an 
    eight-way power driver seat.</p>
    <p>The SE includes a sport-tuned suspension, 17-inch alloy wheels, 
    and special interior and exterior styling details.</p>
    <p>The luxurious XLE reverts to the LE’s softer suspension settings 
    and 16-inch wheels while providing an upgraded JBL-branded sound 
    system with an in-dash CD changer and satellite radio, Bluetooth 
    phone and music connectivity.</p>
    <p>It also proud of automatic dual-zone climate control, a power 
    passenger seat, an auto-dimming rearview mirror, reclining rear 
    seats, a moon roof, wood-tone accents and, on the V6 model, leather 
    seating.</p>
    <p>Note that neither the SE nor the XLE offers the folding rear 
    seat, though each has a center pass-through.</p>
    <p>Most of the XLE’s upgrades are offered on the lower trim levels 
    as options.</p>
    <p>Other major options, depending on trim level, include a sunroof, 
    a navigation system, keyless ignition and entry and heated front 
    seats.</p>
    <p>All Camrys are front-wheel drive, and the standard engine on 
    base, LE and XLE trim levels is a 2<punctuation>.</punctuation>5-liter four-cylinder 
    that generates 169 hp, 11 more than the previous 2<punctuation>.</punctuation>4-liter 
    four.</p>
    <p>Optional on all models except for the base Camry is a 3<punctuation>.</punctuation>5-liter V6 that cranks out 268 horse power and 248 lb-ft of 
    torque. A six-speed automatic is the sole transmission choice.</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
