<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2009-06-03</date>
    <place>http://www.mynaijanews.com/</place>
    <author><gender>m</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>Igbo</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>How far has Samsung gone with the PIXON-12?</heading>
    <p>Since the beginning of the year, we have been witnessing an 
    influx of mind blowing phones into the industry. Especially in 
    terms of camera pixel strenght, document viewing compatibility, 
    Wi-Fi connectivity, GPS, etc.</p>
    <p>This time Samsung has raised the bar higher as they have gone 
    ahead to announce a 12<punctuation>.</punctuation>0 mega pixel camera; now not a 
    digital camera O, but a mobile phone! Can you imagine what you can 
    capture with that? Anyway it is called the PIXON-12, otherwise 
    known as the M8910. Looking like the omnia and the 5800, but more 
    of the 5800, the pixon spots a display type of AMOLED capacitive 
    touch screen, 16M colors of size 480 x 800 pixels, 3<punctuation>.</punctuation>1 
    inches.</p>
    <p>However it was announced if the pixon comes with an 
    accelerometer sensor [what use would the 12MP be without the sensor 
    for viewing, I really hope otherwise <indigenous>sha</indigenous>]. 
    According to it’s announcement on the 1st of June, the pixon is to 
    be released before the month runs out.</p>
    <p>Its memory is relatively low for a phone of its kind, imagine 
    150MB internal storage only! <coll>Arrgh</coll>! Well at least you 
    have your card slot supporting up to 16GB tran flash cards. The 
    PIXON sits awkwardly on Class 10 on both GPRS AND EDGE. Not 
    compatible on the HSCSD, and connects via WLAN only what happened 
    to Wi-Fi technology and why does it not come with an in-built 
    processor? [Unanswered questions].</p>
    <p>The camera that seems to be the sole purpose of the phone’s 
    existence; capable of auto-focus and comes with xenon flash and 
    power LED flash. The camera also comes with the following features; 
    touch auto focus tracking, geo-tagging, face, smile and blink 
    detection, wide dynamic range, and smart auto mode.</p>
    <p>Samsung, I know nokia has been holding the market down and you 
    guys are trying to meet up or even step up, but with this kind of a 
    gadget....</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
