<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2009-08-24</date>
    <place>www.thenationonline.net/web2/</place>
    <author><gender>f</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>Igbo</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>LG launches dual SIM/ touch screen phone</heading>
    <p>LG electronics has introduced a new dual SIM card and touch 
    screen handset as <punctuation>‘</punctuation>LG-KS660<punctuation>’</punctuation> model in 
    into the telecom market.</p>
    <p>A statement made by the company, said the product’s slim design 
    and <error corrected="operator–friendly">operator – 
    friendly</error> tools will help users manage their time better and 
    work more efficiently.</p>
    <p>The General Manager, mobile communicators, LG Electronics, West 
    Africa Operation, Mr<punctuation>.</punctuation> Steve Koh, said: &quot;<quote>Mobile 
    handsets have become an essential part of everyday life, for 
    private consumers and business. This has led to easier 
    communications when away from the office, and it is with this in 
    mind that LG developed the LG-KS660 with dual SIM to provide a more 
    useful and smart touch screen for business people</quote>’’.</p>
    <p>The application of a device, referred to as <punctuation>‘</punctuation>LG-Bi-SIM<punctuation>’</punctuation> in the new LG handset enables users to 
    operate two SIM cards and call- waiting multiple functions 
    simultaneously, with both cards in place and call – waiting 
    functions, also it is possible to have as many as four active calls 
    at a time.</p>
    <p>The simple touch of the screen allows an easy transition between 
    callers on hold and the person they are speaking to, without 
    switching cards or powering off.</p>
    <p>Using the phone stylus, messages can be handwritten while making 
    calls and sent immediately as an image. The automatic handwriting 
    recognition feature ensures that the LG-KS660 responds quickly to 
    users input.</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
