<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2009-04-14</date>
    <place>http://www.mynaijanews.com/</place>
    <author><gender>m</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>Yoruba</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>How functional will the PUMA be?</heading>
    <p>A quick quiz. Q: What do get when your cross General Motors with 
    Segway? A: The PUMA. (Personal Urban Mobility and 
    <error corrected="Accessibility">Accessiblity</error>). No, not the 
    cat. General Motors and Segway jointly announced project PUMA and 
    released a prototype last week.</p>
    <p>Remember the Segway Personal Transporter (PT)? I&apos;m sure you 
    must have seen one on TV. It&apos;s that weird looking contraption 
    with two wheels with space for one. Very useful for short 
    distances. <error corrected="Its">It&apos;s</error> selling point, 
    as far as I was concerned, was <error corrected="its">
    it&apos;s</error> <error corrected="manoeuvrability">
    maneuverability</error>, even in off-road conditions. By off-road, 
    I mean the kind of road conditions we have on Lagos streets. I 
    don&apos;t think one of those ever made <error corrected="its">
    it&apos;s</error> way to Nigeria, though.</p>
    <p>Asked about the off-road readiness of the PUMA, a Segway 
    representative responds, &quot;<quote>At this time it is important 
    to remember that this is a prototype, which ultimately is intended 
    to use on the roads of congested urban 
    environments</quote>&quot;.</p>
    <p>Project PUMA has got General Motors and Segway really excited. I 
    kind of share their excitement. The PUMA is actually based on the 
    PT. But it increases capacity to two passengers in a seated 
    position; capable of carrying them up to anywhere between 25 and 35 
    mph (40 - 56 kph) for anywhere between 25 and 35 miles (40 - 56 km) 
    on a single charge, with zero carbon emission. That makes it 
    green.</p>
    <p>From what I read on Segway&apos;s website and videos I&apos;ve 
    seen, the PUMA is really something. From zero emission operation, 
    dynamic stability to drive by wire technology. It&apos;s a dream 
    gadget. it&apos;s really cool. But what if all this really useful 
    technology is incorporated in the design of real cars, or at least 
    something close? Of course, I think I&apos;d prefer four wheels at 
    100Km/hr.</p>
    <p>How about a true transport module that has space for a driver 
    and two passengers and is still <punctuation>'</punctuation>green<punctuation>'</punctuation>. The P<punctuation>.</punctuation>U<punctuation>.</punctuation>M<punctuation>.</punctuation>A<punctuation>.</punctuation> might just remain a rich man&apos;s toy. Will the PUMA be 
    affordable enough to actually replace urban preferences for 
    transportation, e<punctuation>.</punctuation>g<punctuation>.</punctuation>, <error corrected="motocycles">
    motocyles</error> (a<punctuation>.</punctuation>k<punctuation>.</punctuation>a<punctuation>.</punctuation>, 
    <indigenous>okada</indigenous> in Nigeria).</p>
    <p>Ok<error corrected=",">.</error><punctuation>.</punctuation> it&apos;s still a 
    prototype. There&apos;s still a chance of the current design being 
    discarded for a more functional one. And here&apos;s what a friend 
    thinks, &quot;you want green? Get a bicycle!&quot;</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
