<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2009-08-31</date>
    <place>http://www.vanguardngr.com/</place>
    <author><gender>m</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>Igbo</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>Nokia out with 3G Laptop</heading>
    <p>After more than 25 years in the mobile industry, Nokia will 
    bring its rich mobility heritage and knowledge to the PC world with 
    the new, Windows based, Nokia Booklet 3G.</p>
    <p>Powered by the efficient Intel Atom processor, the Nokia Booklet 
    3G delivers impressive performance with up to 12 hours of battery 
    life, enabling people to leave their power cable behind and still 
    be connected and productive.</p>
    <p>Delivering the rich experience of a full-function PC inside an 
    ultra-portable aluminum chassis, the new mini-laptop weighs 1<punctuation>.</punctuation>25 kilograms, measures slightly more than two centimeters thin, 
    and has the features one would expect from the world‚Äôs leading 
    mobile device manufacturer.</p>
    <p>A broad range of connectivity options ‚Äì including 3G/ HSPA and 
    Wi-Fi ‚Äì gives consumers high speed access to the Internet, 
    including Nokia‚Äôs broad suite of Ovi services, and allows them to 
    make the most of every moment and every opportunity.</p>
    <p>Nokia‚Äôs Executive Vice President for Devices, Kai Oistamo, said 
    that ‚Äú<quote>a growing number of people want the computing power of 
    a PC with the full benefits of mobility</quote>‚Ä?, adding that 
    ‚Äú<quote>we are in the business of connecting people and the Nokia 
    Booklet 3G is a natural evolution for us. Nokia has a long and rich 
    heritage in mobility and with the outstanding battery life, premium 
    design and all day, always on connectivity, we will create 
    something quite compelling. In doing so we will make the personal 
    computer more social, more helpful and more personal</quote>.‚Ä?</p>
    <p>The mini-laptop also comes with an HDMI port for HD video out, a 
    front facing camera for video calling, integrated Bluetooth and an 
    easily accessible SD card reader. Other premium features include 
    the 10-inch glass HD ready display and integrated A-GPS which, 
    working with the Ovi Maps gadget, can pinpoint your position in 
    seconds and open up access for a truly personal maps experience.</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
