<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2009-10-18</date>
    <place>www.vanguardngr.com</place>
    <author><gender>?</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>?</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>Starcomms introduces alternative data subscription 
    payment</heading>
    <p>CDMA operators, Starcomms at the weekend, announced that it has 
    provided its data subscriber with the latest initiative designed to 
    make renewal of data subscriptions more convenient. It said that 
    subscribers now have three easy options to renew and pay for their 
    data connections. They are, online renewal by using recharge cards, 
    by SMS through direct airtime debit or through subscribers‚Äô 
    Interswitch debit/ATM cards. The new payment initiative is 
    available to the company‚Äôs subscribers using either Izap or 1x 
    internet services.</p>
    <p>To enjoy the online payment facility, a subscriber will first 
    have to register on the Starcomms website and enter their preferred 
    user name and the data device number. Once the customer 
    registration is confirmed, the subscriber‚Äôs user name and a 
    password will be sent directly to the subscriber‚Äôs email 
    address.</p>
    <p>The company announced that all subscriber‚Äôs who registered, will 
    have the option to pay either through recharge cards or by 
    Interswitch debit/ATM card. Subscribers can also change their data 
    package plan without the need to go to an outlet or calling the 
    call center. The customers get a transaction reference number and 
    will get their services renewed or reactivated within minutes.</p>
    <p>Besides, Starcomms Data subscribers can also renew their 
    subscription through a code sent as a SMS from any Starcomms phone. 
    Speaking on this initiative, the CCO of Starcomms Mr<punctuation>.</punctuation> Tushar 
    Maheshwari said: ‚ÄúCustomer first is a philosophy which we firmly 
    believe in and our endeavor has been to put the customer 
    perspective in the forefront of what we do and our latest 
    initiative reflects this philosophy‚Ä?<error corrected="."/></p>
  </text>
</annotated>
