<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ew</transcriber>
    <date>2008-?-?</date>
    <place>Nigeria</place>
    <author><gender>m</gender><age>22</age><ethnic-group>Hausa</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>A short story by Muhd Ibrahim Muhsin</heading>
    <p>Gwaggo cleared her throat<error corrected=",">-</error>emulating 
    her master&apos;s action. &quot;The story begins when we were 
    youngsters, now about five decades ago. Surely I won&apos;t use her 
    right name because she&apos;s still alive, thus 
    <error superfluous="yes">,</error> let me call her Ummi, as the 
    <error corrected="household">house-hold</error> name in Hausa 
    communities, was betrothed to a young man by the name of Audu.</p>
    <p>&quot;Audu?&quot; she tried to recall the exact name. &quot;Yes 
    <error corrected=","/> Audu.&quot;</p>
    <p>Audu, whose occupation was farming, inherited from his father 
    <error corrected=",">;</error> a farmer and also great scholar in 
    our village then.</p>
    <p>Someday, a fortnight left for their wedding to take place 
    <error corrected=",">.</error> One of the eminent wealthy men 
    living in the village heard about it <error superfluous="yes">
    ,</error> through one of his informers. He said he was the one who 
    this girl would be married to.</p>
    <p>Ummi was a pretty, very elegant girl<error corrected=","/> but 
    her parents were incredibly poor. Thus, as soon as this opulent 
    idol came in her life, Audu&apos;s story was completely demolished 
    and built himself up to that for marrying her. Subsequently, people 
    started criticizing parents of Ummi
    <error superfluous="yes">,</error> over their ruthless decision of 
    giving their daughter&apos;s hand in marriage for worldly thing not 
    to her initial fiancé, who is poor.</p>
    <p>The damnedest thing is that<error superfluous="yes">;</error> 
    Basara, the illegitimate husband-to-be of Ummi
    <error corrected=","/> was wonderfully a generous man in the face 
    of people of Shanya, particularly elders of the village. Therefore, 
    nobody thought of making a single reproachful expression on that
    <error corrected=",">;</error> thinking it wasn&apos;t his wish but 
    her parent&apos;s to get source of earning. Eventually, if you were 
    in his house, the story has a transcendental dichotomy.</p>
    <p>To cap the story short, Ummi was at the end married to Basara. 
    She was<error superfluous="yes">,</error> in the house a third and 
    callow one, so she was mercilessly treated like a skivvy. She spent 
    few weeks in such hardship and later divorced as a result of untrue 
    criticism of saying she was pregnant already for someone before the 
    wedlock.</p>
    <p>&quot;Hear me,&quot; he said horribly, &quot;I don&apos;t like 
    any bastard child in my house. Take your dirty body and leave my 
    house immediately<error corrected="."/>&quot;</p>
    <p>&quot;Alhaji,&quot; she called, hiding his real name for honor, 
    &quot;Wallahi<error corrected=","/> it’s yours
    <error corrected=","/> not <error corrected="anybody&apos;s">any 
    body&apos;s</error><error corrected=",">.</error>&quot; she 
    miserably, tearfully said.</p>
    <p>&quot;No! Immediately pack your ratty belongings and leave my 
    house before I returned.&quot;</p>
    <p>&quot;Oh<error superfluous="yes">-</error>Alhaji
    <error corrected=",">-</error>Please.&quot; She held the edge of 
    his big gown tearfully, begging.</p>
    <p>He, without a single glance at her, went out harshly, pushing 
    her back disdainfully, &quot;Stupid!&quot; he roared.</p>
    <p>Basara was, after Ummi had returned home, called by her elders. 
    He honored the invitation and came<error corrected=","/> but 
    repeated what he said to her before.</p>
    <p>&quot;Basara,&quot; called one of her folks in a pitiful 
    sensation, &quot;she supposed to get pregnancy. Two months are not 
    two days. Even in a day, a wife could be pregnant by her husband, 
    isn&apos;t it?&quot; he asked, looking at Basara, &quot;Don&apos;t 
    you know this?&quot;</p>
    <p>&quot;I know, but I actually didn&apos;t.&quot; he grinned 
    wildly, &quot;How can I sleep with that little crazy girl! God 
    forbid.&quot;</p>
    <p>&quot;Watch your language, Alhaji!&quot; warned one old man 
    beside.</p>
    <p>&quot;Wallahi…he…did…severally<error corrected=","/>&quot; cried 
    Ummi from the back.</p>
    <p>&quot;Ah,&quot; he exploded, mouth agaped, &quot;Am I a liar? Is 
    it what you teach her<error corrected="?">;</error> disrespecting 
    people older than her and in such a company of aged faces? You 
    chit!&quot; he groaned, pointing her.</p>
    <p>&quot;<error corrected="it&apos;s">Its</error> okay…that&apos;s 
    all…&quot; said one of them.</p>
    <p>They had no sort of power to convince him to accept the 
    pregnancy. They unwillingly <error corrected="gave up">
    gave-up</error>. And fact is<error corrected=":">;</error> he was 
    the responsible. He only fulfilled his desire.</p>
    <p>At the end of the day, Ummi was left the victim; severely 
    jeopardize, suffered, dishearten and with a pregnancy that people 
    remained regarding illegitimate. She finally gave birth to a baby 
    seen in community as bastard.</p>
    <p>It was then that her parent realized their fault, regretted and 
    wished they had not done that to her. What a pity
    <error corrected="!">?</error></p>
    <p>&quot;Why didn&apos;t they sue that <error superfluous="yes">
    &apos;</error>rake<error superfluous="yes">&apos;</error> to 
    court?&quot; asked Shahada, absolutely startled by the story.</p>
    <p>&quot;This is a nice idea. The magistrate courts we had then 
    couldn&apos;t deal with that case. No one would agree that Basara 
    could have done such a wretched thing. The man was a wolf in 
    sheep&apos;s cloth.</p>
    <p>&quot;What about the district head, didn&apos;t he get the 
    story?&quot;</p>
    <p>&quot;Young girl…what was done couldn&apos;t be undone. So they, 
    though the parents alone, deserved. Materialism.&quot;</p>
    <p>&quot;May Allah avenge<punctuation>'</punctuation>em.&quot;</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
