<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2000</date>
    <place>Oxford, African Books Collective</place>
    <author><gender>m</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>Igbo</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <p>In time I became one of Sawa&apos;s best friends and 
    confidantes, and his pimp. He told me that most people who claimed 
    to be his friends only wanted to take some of his money, including 
    some who were wealthier than he was. The world was a bad place, and 
    he had found out that it was very dangerous to trust people. For 
    some reason that was not clear to me, he assumed I had nobler 
    motives than other people.</p>
    <p>Only six years before he had been a poor teacher in a rural 
    secondary school (that&apos;s where he got his educated man&apos;s 
    words from), and the limits of his ambition had been to win a 
    transfer to a city school where he would earn a better living by 
    giving extra lessons to the children of the wealthy and be promoted 
    one day to school principal. Then a cousin in the army, who had 
    been brought up by Sawa&apos;s parents and was really like a 
    brother, was given a lucrative post in government. Since Sawa was 
    the only other person in the family with a modicum of education, 
    and the cousin-brother had long known that he was a trustworthy 
    person, he suggested that Sawa should resign from his teaching job 
    and become his front (or business representative, as Sawa put 
    it).</p>
    <p>The cousin-brother gave purchase orders to companies registered 
    in Sawa&apos;s name, say, to supply in bulk a year&apos;s 
    requirement of drugs for all the hospitals in a particular state. 
    Sawa would arrange for half the quantity of drugs to be delivered 
    and get the state&apos;s health officials to certify that the 
    purchase order had been fulfilled by giving them bribes several 
    times higher than their pathetic salaries. Then he would pursue 
    payment for the order, bulldozing vouchers past all bureaucratic 
    hurdles, spraying bribes like an irrigation pump. The money would 
    be paid into one of Sawa&apos;s bank accounts, and he would pass on 
    the cousin-brother&apos;s share in cash, or purchase foreign 
    currency with it which he would pay into the cousin-brother&apos;s 
    bank account in Zurich.</p>
    <p>Sawa and his cousin-brother grew in daring over time. They 
    sometimes didn&apos;t bother to supply anything at all, just paid 
    handsomer bribes and got the papers signed to say that deliveries 
    had been made. In only a year Sawa made more money than he had ever 
    dreamt of. Gone were the burning afternoons of severe headaches and 
    back pain spent hoeing his farm beside his house in the rural 
    school to supplement his family&apos;s diet; the nights of hunger 
    and bitterness while waiting for the monthly salary that was 
    already eaten up by debts even before it was paid, and the cruel 
    contempt in the eyes of his wife and children. Sawa reminded you of 
    this suffering all the time. By suffering so much, he seemed to 
    imply, he had earned the right to his wealth even if it came from 
    cooked-up supply receipts and systematic theft from public coffers. 
    Anyway, only our country&apos;s socialists, radicals and people 
    like that still thought that robbing the government was any sort of 
    crime. Government money was juicy fruit hanging on a tree that 
    belonged to no one; only a fool would, when given an opportunity, 
    not help himself.</p>
    <p>Over the years he developed his own connections and no longer 
    relied solely on the cousin-brother. He had the private phone 
    numbers of all the people in lucrative government positions, and a 
    great part of his life was now spent going from one state capital 
    to another, keeping warm all his contacts with men of power and 
    sniffing round for good deals. He attended the numerous launchings 
    of biographies of government officials - syrupy fiction of 
    abysmally low quality by nonentities about nonentities; their 
    birthdays and their wives&apos; birthdays; the ceremonies where 
    they were conferred with traditional chieftaincy titles; the naming 
    ceremonies of their children and of their brothers&apos; children; 
    and the weddings of their sons, daughters, nephews and nieces - and 
    he donated generously everywhere. He took out full-page 
    advertisements in the newspapers every few months to congratulate 
    them on their dynamism and their miraculous achievements in office 
    and to assure them that the machinations of their enemies would 
    come to naught. He retained informants near the highest points of 
    government who alerted him when an official was about to fall so 
    that he knew when not to attend a launching ceremony and when 
    malaria would conveniently afflict him a day or two before a 
    wedding. Sawa was a generous man, but men of power, he said, were 
    almost always bastards so when they were ascendant you took all the 
    shit they gave you in order to get what you wanted, but the moment 
    they began to fall you got out of the way so they would have the 
    hard, painful fall they richly deserved. But sometimes they defied 
    all predictions and did not fall, or they fell and rose again, and 
    you had to take ten times as much shit as you had before, to get 
    close again to the tree hanging heavy with fruit. It was a life 
    riddled with more uncertainties than astrology, and Sawa developed 
    hypertension along the way.</p>
    <p>A bit of his wealth began to flow in my direction. In addition 
    to brokerage fees and bonuses on the deposits he made with BTF - a 
    total of four million naira before the bubble burst - I earned 
    commissions by acting as agent for the sale of a house in Ikoyi, 
    which one of his friends in government had bought from the 
    government at one-hundredth of the market value, and by helping to 
    find buyers for a consignment of second-hand delivery vans which he 
    and his cousin-brother had imported from Germany.</p>
    <p>Early in 1992, Philip, whose driven eyes nearly shed tears of 
    joy each time I scored another victory for BTF, made me manager of 
    Treasury and Marketing, doubled my salary and permanently assigned 
    one driver and one Nissan Sunny to me. He had a small office carved 
    out for me next to his. Yemisi and Amina took my elevation in good 
    grace and I bought them lunch almost daily in an eating place near 
    our office of dubious sanitation and dangerously peppery fare, 
    called <italics>Executive Buka</italics>, which was heavily 
    patronised by the banking-finance company tribe. We nicknamed Sawa 
    <italics>gorilla millionaire</italics>.</p>
    <p>I acquired more designer suits and blazers, more shoes, more 
    fragrances. I overhauled my father&apos;s nearly moribund Peugeot 
    504, replaced the ten-year-old rug in our living room and the 
    exhausted upholstered easy chairs. I bought a microwave oven for my 
    mother and a new radio for my father. I spoiled Nwaka with new 
    clothes and chocolates and ice cream. I spoiled Robo, too, and she 
    didn&apos;t grumble too loudly when I said I had to take Sawa out. 
    I swore to her that I never slept with any of the women we went out 
    with; they were too low class for me, I said.</p>
    <p>My father&apos;s scepticism about my job changed to 
    apprehension. In March 1992, he summoned my mother and me to a 
    meeting in his study, lined with Ovid and Homer, Shakespeare and 
    Marlowe. He called meetings in that study only on very grave 
    matters and my mother and I arrived wearing appropriate looks of 
    mourning.</p>
    <p>&apos;Obiora,&apos; he began (he called my name in full only on 
    very serious occasions), looking subdued and afraid behind his 
    glasses, looking like he had suddenly shrunk in size, &apos;we are 
    very, very happy with your success at work.&apos;</p>
    <p>He paused, my mother nodded vigorously; I waited for him to 
    continue.</p>
    <p>&apos;But, we have brought you up in a humble Christian family 
    and we have a duty to make sure that you live a fully Christian 
    life. Like I said, we are very happy with your success at work and 
    we are grateful to God for everything. All I want to say is that 
    you should be very careful in everything you do. This country is a 
    place of many temptations, and when you are young you want very 
    many things, and you want all of them immediately. Sometimes you do 
    not care how they come; you just want them. That is the road to 
    doom and that is the road we want you to avoid. Easy money is very 
    sweet but it is also very dangerous. Don&apos;t get me wrong -I am 
    not saying you have done anything wrong, we just want you to be 
    very careful about who you deal with and in everything you 
    do.&apos;</p>
    <p>&apos;Daddy, I thank you for your advice and for your 
    concern,&apos; I said like an obedient son, feeling sorry for the 
    old man. &apos;I&apos;m not doing anything wrong; I&apos;ve just 
    been a bit lucky.&apos;</p>
    <p>He nodded sagely, then he went round and round in slow and 
    aimless circles of advice like a man who had completely lost his 
    way in a strange town. For people like my father, sudden wealth was 
    inherently evil; it upset the order of the world 
    -twenty-six-year-old sons became breadwinners, made more money in a 
    week than their parents who had worked for thirty years made in a 
    year and wore colognes that cost more money than the family&apos;s 
    annual food bill. It was as though, in less than a year, I had 
    supplanted him as the head of his house, as though I had married 
    his wife and become the father of his children.</p>
    <p>After what seemed like an eternity of directionless counselling, 
    my father said, &apos;Let us pray.&apos;</p>
    <p>He fetched his huge old Bible from a drawer and read from the 
    Book of Psalms. Then he knelt down and entrusted my future in that 
    land of temptation and wickedness to the Heavenly Father. When he 
    was through my mother led us in singing a song of praise to the 
    Lord:</p>
    <p>His promises never fail</p>
    <p>His promises never fail</p>
    <p>Oh yes, the promises of my Father</p>
    <p>Will never ever fail.</p>
    <p>Three months later I took a well-deserved three-week vacation 
    and went with Robo to London. Bronzo, my friend from university, 
    who came to pick us up from Victoria Station, looked at my grey 
    single-breasted Louis Raphael suit, my tie by Profilo and my black 
    shoes by Gucci, and at Robo&apos;s lovely peach dress and he let 
    out a yell.</p>
    <p>&apos;I thought I heard there was recession in Nigeria,&apos; he 
    said. &apos;Do you work in the fucking finance house, or do you own 
    the bloody thing?&apos;</p>
    <heading>Glass, Not Diamond</heading>
    <p>My rise to designer-suit-wearing manager at BTF took about a 
    year and a half; my fall to joblessness and pennilessness took only 
    nine months, but those nine months, of stomach-churning anxiety and 
    fear, felt like a hundred years. And even now I sometimes still 
    have nightmares about that horrible sinking, and wake up with the 
    psychosomatic ailments of that period: dull, lingering headaches, 
    sudden diarrhoea, vicious tightness in the chest, constriction of 
    the throat, acute insomnia.</p>
    <p>It started, as most things start in Nigeria, in the form of 
    rumours that gather strength and mutate as they swirl around: this 
    or that finance company was having problems paying interest on 
    deposits, this or that bank was quietly laying off workers. Stories 
    appeared in the papers early in 1993 about finance companies which 
    had defaulted on paying the insane interest rates they had offered 
    to their depositors in the desperate scramble for money. Some of 
    these depositors were themselves banks and finance companies and 
    default in one financial institution badly wounded a number of 
    others.</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
