<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2002</date>
    <place>African Books Collective</place>
    <author><gender>m</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>Igbo</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <p>Both Chike and Bisi come from Wazobia. Chike is from the 
    <italics>Igbo</italics> ethnic group of the eastern part of 
    Wazobia, while Bisi is from the <italics>Yoruba</italics> ethnic 
    group of the western part. Chike&apos;s parents moved to Lagos in 
    Western Wazobia in the early 1960s. Then, life in Wazobia was good. 
    The economy was stable, food plentiful and affordable. People 
    harbored no fears for their personal safety when traveling from one 
    end of the country to the other. Then, the country had an air of 
    optimism about it. People got about their daily labors with the 
    sustaining hope and assurance that tomorrow will be better than 
    today.</p>
    <p>It was not long, however, before ethnic or 
    <italics>tribal</italics> politics, although lurking beneath the 
    surface of the national life of Wazobia, broke out like hives all 
    over the body politic of the country. Yet, before the rash of 
    hives, in the brilliant sunlight of normalcy that was immediate 
    post colonial Wazobia, hope tarried fleetingly, almost mockingly, 
    wedged between the end of Anglian tyranny and the beginning of 
    Wazobian folly.</p>
    <p>Then, in that short-lived bedazzling sunlight of normalcy, 
    Wazobia&apos;s port-city capital, Lagos, was a cosmopolitan hot bed 
    of <italics>highlife</italics>. Even the popular music of the time 
    came to be known for the spirit of the times, as 
    <italics>highlife</italics>. People streamed in from all corners of 
    the new nation. Awaiting them were the city lights of fantasy and 
    faith, the neon promise of a slice of <italics>modernity</italics> 
    and prosperity—a piece of what came to be much ballyhooed in 
    Wazobia as <italics>the national cake</italics>. The City is the 
    magnet. An electric stage prop of luminescent nights, humming 
    factories, sleek automobiles, mind-numbing liquors, sex-on-tap, and 
    the mother of them all, the <italics>pursuit of money</italics>.</p>
    <p>The gold prospectors from the rural backwaters of Wazobia pour 
    incessantly into The City—into Lagos, seduced by her bright lights 
    and long nights. They pay no heed to the squalid shanty town tied 
    around The City&apos;s cosmopolitan neck like a hangman&apos;s 
    noose, threatening to choke the life out of her. Though it is The 
    City&apos;s neck at risk of being choked to death, it is the lot of 
    the gold prospectors from the rural backwaters of Wazobia to serve 
    as the noose; and for all its grizzly task, the hangman&apos;s rope 
    has no more life itself than the neck it breaks at the yank of the 
    lever. Any wonder the now marooned gold prospectors in the great 
    city of Lagos, whose hopeful fantasies had long been dashed into a 
    huge pile of rubble by the <error corrected="gargantum">
    gangantum</error> demolition ironball of reality, coined the famous 
    local <error corrected="colloquialism">colloqialism</error>: &apos; 
    <other-language language="nigerian-pidgin">to go Lagos no hard, to 
    return na &apos;im be the wahala</other-language>.&apos;</p>
    <p>It was upon the shifting ground from live-and-let-live 
    prosperity and national confidence, to unapologetic ethnic or 
    <italics>tribal</italics> chauvinism and national cynicism in 
    Wazobia, that Chike and Bisi grew up. Unlike their parents and 
    their parents before them, whose childhood memories were made up of 
    fighting, serving, and again, fighting Anglians, theirs are made up 
    of Wazobians serving and then, fighting each other.</p>
    <p>Wazobia is an enormous African country. A number of estimates 
    put her population at anywhere from eighty to one hundred and 
    twenty million people. The country sprawls across three distinctive 
    geographic zones: sahel, savannah grassland, and rain forest 
    respectively, if one traverses it in a north-southerly direction. 
    Vast areas of its territory are generously watered by the River 
    Niger, its numerous tributaries branching out on a map like 
    varicose veins showing through the unpigmented skin of the legs of 
    an albino woman.</p>
    <p>The Anglians, the colonial architects of the modern state of 
    Wazobia, were responsible for putting that jig-saw puzzle together. 
    One Anglian ex-colonial officer reflecting on this subject in his 
    memoirs, which he gave the self-congratulatory title: 
    <italics>Footprints On The Sands of Time: A Personal Account of 
    Anglian Exploits in The Dark Continent</italics>, observed, that 
    the reasons for that action were threefold: it made commerce for 
    the Anglians easier by standardizing business and municipal laws; 
    it unified administrative procedures-such as application of law and 
    order and the civil-service bureaucracy; and, of course, it 
    integrated the command structure of their colonial army and 
    constabulary.</p>
    <p>Had Wazobia simply been a zoo in which the zoo-keeper had of 
    necessity to unilaterally decide how to organize the animals under 
    his charge, it might have been understandable why consultation with 
    the captive beasts would have been uncalled for and, at any rate, 
    impossible. But, Wazobia was not a zoo. It was, rather, a territory 
    filled with great African nations.</p>
    <p>Nations with distinct political systems, cultures, religions, 
    languages, and traditions. Nations that had dwelt in the same 
    geographic vicinity for several millennia. Yet, Anglia behaved like 
    a zookeeper. With little or no consultation, she mixed up those 
    African nations like tossed salad contained in her colonial bowl, 
    or more properly, like a large patchwork quilt that she made a poor 
    seamstress of stitching together.</p>
    <p>When at last, the Anglians made their rather ceremonious exit, 
    the quilt they badly stitched together, began to come apart at the 
    seams. The cracks on the shell of the tortoise, caused by its 
    proverbial great fall from the heavenly abode of the gods, began to 
    disintegrate on the impact of Anglian colonial departure, for no 
    effective adhesive had been applied along the fracture lines to 
    hold the shell together.</p>
    <p>The over two hundred and fifty ethnic groups, large and small, 
    in post-colonial Wazobia, boiled as though in a cauldron. The large 
    ones sought to wield national power, the small ones wanted 
    protection from the large ones as well as a piece of the action at 
    the national level. Each was for self none for all. Less than a 
    decade after the Anglians granted Wazobia her political 
    independence, the family quarrel exploded into a full fledged blood 
    feud.</p>
    <p>For thirty grueling months the House of Wazobia tottered, 
    divided against itself. The Anglians sat back in the warmth of 
    their homes in their island stronghold, their fireplaces heated 
    with timber from Wazobia; felled, cut into logs, loaded unto trucks 
    and still later, unto steamers at port cities by the underpaid 
    labor of the warring Wazobians, wringing their hands in sheer 
    delight at the seeming folly of the so-called 
    <italics>Negro</italics>.</p>
    <p>The civil war that was fought in Wazobia was so fierce, so 
    costly in human and material terms that scholars of African 
    politics characterized it as the bloodiest in all of Africa south 
    of the great Sahara. Millions died of hunger, malnutrition, 
    disease, and actual combat. Some others died in prison cells on 
    both sides, for real and imagined crimes against &quot;the 
    people&quot; --- that amorphous, ambiguous, abstraction, under 
    whose banner every conceivable inhumanity has been visited on 
    people, and under whose edifying standard tyrants, democrats, and 
    political bootleggers of all shades and stripes, have justified 
    their keep!</p>
    <p>Chike was quite young during that civil war, about ten years of 
    age when it began, and about thirteen, when it came to as abrupt an 
    end as it started. This is, of course, not quite true, for 
    everybody knew that the departing Anglians set up the structure of 
    Wazobia in such a manner as to self-destruct upon their departure. 
    If they can not rule Wazobia and other parts of Africa directly, 
    then they had to exercise remote control. Failing that, the whole 
    <italics>damn</italics> thing could go to pot for all they 
    cared.</p>
    <p>Nothing quite provides the opportunity for such external control 
    like internal disunity and disorganization. In the darkest hour of 
    Wazobia&apos;s post-Colonial history, the exploits of the Anglians 
    appeared to be working like a charm.</p>
    <p>Of all the things involved in Wazobia&apos;s fratricidal war, 
    none left as lasting an impression on Chike&apos;s young mind as 
    the sheer horror of that violent clash of wills. The horror was 
    most eloquently expressed in the scale and tragedy of human 
    suffering. The endless lines of famished refugees, migrating from 
    one war-torn area of the breakaway republic&apos;s steadily 
    shrinking realm to another. The horror and pain of gnawing hunger, 
    starvation and grotesque malnutrition. The unimaginable agony 
    visible in the vacant stares of helpless parents, as their young 
    ones lie next to them, emaciated black rag-dolls of certain 
    death.</p>
    <p>Chike also recalls quite vividly the horror of mangled human 
    body parts from the air raids. No. The bombing of civilian 
    population centers--market places, schools, churches, hospitals, 
    orphanages --- by the Federal Air Force of Wazobia, was not mere 
    propaganda by the <italics>secessionists</italics>. It was true. It 
    was real. It happened.</p>
    <p>After those terrifying air raids with the haunting supersonic 
    sounds of jet fighters and bombers fade into the distant clouds, 
    suggesting that the pilots may be taking a lunch break from their 
    grizzly work as bringers of death; men and women of the Civil 
    Defense and Red Cross, run helter-skelter, picking up dismembered 
    body parts in wheelbarrows, to be sent unceremoniously to mass 
    graves. The lucky ones die with their remains recognizably intact 
    for a decent burial.</p>
    <p>Hospital wards and their outpatient rooms overflow with the 
    injured and the deceased. Doctors and nurses work round the clock 
    in a zombie-like daze of fatigue trying to save a life here, a limb 
    there.</p>
    <p>At the end of all the horror of haunting supersonic jet sounds, 
    acrid smells in the after-air of explosives and burning flesh, the 
    macabre ritual of gathering body parts, overflowing hospital wards, 
    wailing mothers and despondent fathers, the day after holds out 
    only one sure promise: to bring yet another dreaded experience of 
    violent death from the hell&apos;s angels of the sky.</p>
    <p>How does a country exorcise this kind of horror from the minds 
    of the victimized? Do you simply not talk about it and hope that it 
    fades from conscious memory? Do you fabricate an alternative fable? 
    Do you tell the children it never happened? That it was a lie—the 
    figment of someone&apos;s imagination? Do you say to them that 
    while it may have happened, it was not nearly as bad as some make 
    it seem? Does quibbling over the magnitude of the horror outweigh 
    the principle of inflicting the horror in the first place?</p>
    <p>How does a country bury its dark past? How does a country purge 
    its collective memory of the horror of its own 
    <error corrected="wilful">willful</error> savagery? Do you punish 
    those who remember—who refuse to forget, as traitors of the hard 
    won peace? Do you hire court historians to sing the obsequious 
    praises of the victorious king, damning truth to kingdom come? Or 
    do you assemble the nation&apos;s sages and let the truth they 
    speak free the nation?</p>
    <p>Chike had no ready answers to any of these daunting questions; 
    however, there were two things he knew for sure would not go away: 
    his long memory of the horror of that war and the fact that his 
    people were back in Wazobia to stay, for better or for worse.</p>
    <p>Although Chike is studying medicine, politics fascinates him. 
    Everything for him revolves in one way or another on the pivot of 
    politics. He finds every aspect of life inextricably interwoven 
    with politics. Nothing, he, however, feels quite has the kind of 
    intimate and peculiar connection with politics as religion. Its 
    potential as a rallying force, its history, and certainly its 
    inter-faith and inter-sectarian rivalries and conflicts. Each 
    aspect of religion, breeds by its very nature, political 
    consequences. He often finds it amusing whenever he hears people in 
    Wazobia say that they are &apos;entering politics,&apos; when, in 
    fact, they are always in politics— living life. Perhaps what they 
    really mean is that they intend to run for public office.</p>
    <p>One of Chike&apos;s favorite pastimes is brain-storming the many 
    contradictions that riddle the institutions and practice of 
    religion and politics, especially regarding their interaction. 
    Seemingly strange bedfellows, the former claiming to be of the 
    divine and transcendent realm, and the latter, the earthly and 
    temporal domain, they have a constant love affair with each other 
    that would leave a merry-go-round dizzy.</p>
    <p>Bisi has grown so used to listening to Chike&apos;s insufferable 
    monologues about one aspect or the other of religion and the social 
    and political life of Wazobia, that she feels she can recite them 
    by heart. He almost always begins by saying in his acquired 
    Americanism, something like, &quot;My dear Bisi, they have this new 
    thing up for sale and they want us to buy it.&quot;</p>
    <p>Any one unaccustomed to Chike&apos;s manner of speaking, would 
    honestly think that he is referring to a new commodity available at 
    the downtown department stores. Invariably, his discourse would 
    have something to do with the black man, the current political 
    situation in the country, or his disagreement with some moral point 
    or the other propounded by the Church. Both Chike and Bisi&apos;s 
    parents are staunch Catholics and that may account for Chike&apos;s 
    antipathy towards religion.</p>
    <p>There is often this irrepressible rebel in him that seems 
    hell-bent on bucking the religious establishment.</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
