<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>?</date>
    <place>?</place>
    <author><gender>m</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>?</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>The Fisherman of Iboko</heading>
    <p>Ten yards of the finest white sand separated the fishing village 
    of thatched bamboo and mud huts from the angry Iboko sea. A lonely 
    white gull flew low, parallel across, then dipped itself here and 
    there, desperate for a catch to quell the gnawing hunger wringing 
    deep inside the pit of its stomach. The small bald-headed old man 
    with eyes like burning coal, looked me over from head to toe, spat 
    and sighed.</p>
    <p>&apos;I am sorry for your parents, the papa and mama, who gave 
    birth to you&apos;. By the way&apos;, he continued, &apos;let me 
    ask you. Has it ever occurred to you, why a young and inexperienced 
    hawk never ventures into an enemy territory? Answer me. Mr Ade 
    Answer me&apos;.</p>
    <p>I kept mute. I uttered not a single word. All my attention was 
    focused on the small old man. Akpan himself left me for a moment. 
    He concentrated his attention on the ground before him. Grinding 
    and gnashing his teeth, he began to draw silly maps of nowhere in 
    particular in the sand with the big toe of his right leg. From his 
    countenance, it was obvious that the old bugger was reeling with 
    anger; and that truly he hated me.</p>
    <p>&apos;Go on Akpan&apos;, I cajoled. &apos; I&apos;m sure you 
    have not exhausted your tale?&apos;</p>
    <p>Suddenly Akpan stopped drawing his little maps in the sand, as 
    angry waves also began to lap unto the shores, bathing every body 
    present with salty foams. &apos;Mr Ade&apos;, Akpan hissed, 
    reverting back his blood-shot eyes from the sand unto me.</p>
    <p>&apos;You small rat. How dare you challenge me?. If you are a 
    stranger in Iboko, why do you not first and foremost find out who 
    is who in this village, before daring me, Akpari Etete Jackson Udoh 
    a<punctuation>.</punctuation>k<punctuation>.</punctuation>a 
    &quot;Tomorrow too far&quot;?</p>
    <p>&apos;Akpan&apos;, I replied, trying my utmost to re-engage the 
    old man&apos;s gaze.</p>
    <p>&apos;Since I came into Iboko, I have held a few young ladies by 
    their hands, some by the waist, but I have never touched a married 
    woman. Does that not in a way show that I know who is who?&apos;</p>
    <p>&apos;Hmmm —?<error superfluous="yes">.</error> I see 
    <error superfluous="yes"/>!&apos;, Akpan taunted.</p>
    <p>&apos;So you know me?<error superfluous="yes">.</error> You know 
    who I am and you have the effrontery to challenge me? 
    <error superfluous="yes">.</error> Mr Ade, I swear, I will not 
    forgive you. Nobody in Iboko has ever stood before me to shake a 
    finger, and lived to tell the story, after. Send words home to your 
    father and mother to start making your coffin&apos;, the old man 
    yelled.</p>
    <p>As the argument between me and Akpan was heating up, those 
    fishermen present, citizens of Iboko, urged me to apologise to 
    Akpan. They persuaded me to apologise and appease him, whether I 
    was right or wrong. <error corrected="Earnestly">Ernestly</error>, 
    they urged that I apologise and beg, to be spared my life. They 
    thought I had been reckless, not to have stayed out of the way of 
    Akpan&apos;s wrath. Indeed, the fishermen regarded me with pity, or 
    that sort of feeling one has when one witnesses a helpless child 
    drowning, for example, without one being able to save or help it. 
    They were all on my side though, silently, secretly. But they dared 
    not risk Akpan&apos;s wrath, by letting him know that they sided 
    with me in this argument, or even that they sympathised with me.</p>
    <p>Etekamba the oldest of the fishermen tried to clear his throat. 
    His first and second attempts were barely audible. It was obvious 
    he was scared and terrified of the venture he had decided to embark 
    upon. His right hand was trembling visibly from where he stood, as 
    he tried to gather his loin-cloth about him. With the fingers of 
    his left hand folded beneath his deeply furrowed chin, his eyes 
    cast on the ground in front of him, Etekamba was a man groaning 
    under an unimaginable yoke. Indeed, his venture seemed most 
    tortuous and beyond the ordinary call of duty. &apos;Mr Ade&apos;, 
    Etekamba began in a very grave high pitched and shaky voice, 
    &apos;a child carried on the back can never tell how tedious the 
    journey to a distant farm is. The canoe is also said to have opined 
    that; &apos;nobody would ever enter it, who knows what dangers it 
    sees in the deep&apos;. &apos;Beg the man to forgive you. Beg him 
    whether you are right or wrong. It is that rat that brags, knows no 
    fear, that is normally found dead in a trap. Look around you at our 
    village Iboko&apos;, Etekamba croaked.</p>
    <p>Against my will, but at Etekamba&apos;s behest, my eyes wandered 
    about, trailing after his gaze, as the old man took a painful swoop 
    over Iboko, or what remained of it, with his experienced, sad and 
    thoughtful gaze. An uncompleted building here. An uncompleted 
    building there. Some of the houses had only reached foundation 
    level. Some without roofs. Some were so weather-beaten that their 
    block walls, door and window frames had even begun to disintegrate 
    and to grow mushroom and fungi. Their owners, one after another, 
    had suddenly died under mysterious circumstances without completing 
    them. Their owners, one and all, had been killed by the powerful 
    witchcraft owned by none other than Akpan Etete Jackson Udoh - 
    (a<punctuation>.</punctuation>k<punctuation>.</punctuation>a 
    -Tomorrow too far). All of them were killed by this wizard of 
    wizards, because, he envied their progress. That was the kind of 
    person Akpan was to his own people, a real terror. So one can 
    imagine why Etekamba and all the other fishermen were asking me to 
    apologise to Akpan, whether I had actually offended him or not. 
    Etekamba was urging me to try to salvage and retrieve my life, from 
    the talons of Akpan&apos;s sorcery, and sure death..</p>
    <p>Akpan bent down almost double, and picked up a broomstick that 
    lay on the ground in front of him. Slowly, he broke the broom, 
    closed his eyes, and used one end of the broom to remove wax from 
    inside his ears. The silence that engulfed the entire vicinity was 
    horrendous, a silence of fear. No one dared to cough. Indeed, one 
    might even have been able to hear the footsteps of an ant. The 
    suspense in the air was beyond comprehension! After Etekamba had 
    spoken, all the other fishermen sat with their legs folded under 
    their buttocks, eyes glued on the sandy floor before them. No one 
    dared look Akpan in the face. Not a single word had further crossed 
    a lip. Akpan thoroughly enjoyed the state of siege in which he held 
    his people. It was as if even the waves were at Akpan&apos;s 
    command, and would break-loose and sweep everybody out to sea, if 
    Akpan so desired.</p>
    <p>I said nothing in spite of Etekamba&apos;s passionate plea. 
    After a while, Akpan shifted his gaze and rested his burning 
    coal-red eyes on me again.</p>
    <p>&apos;Mr em- em -em —. What again do you say is your name? 
    Anyway whatever your name is, I give you four hours to pack your 
    bag and baggage and leave Iboko. Go away in four hours, or send 
    words home to your parents to prepare your coffin&apos;.</p>
    <p>&apos;You can&apos;t do <coll>f---up</coll>&apos;, I said. It 
    was high time, I thought, to call Akpan&apos;s bluff.</p>
    <p>&apos;<indigenous>Chei</indigenous>&apos;, the crowd shrieked in 
    shock and bewilderment. Those were the very words, I later learnt, 
    Akpan&apos;s wife Nkoyo, had uttered to her husband, a few years 
    back, before he used witchcraft to kill her.</p>
    <p>Rumour had it, that Nkoyo had quarrelled with her husband one 
    night, five years back. It was said, that Akpan&apos;s wife, had 
    pleaded with her husband to desist from his evil ways. The woman 
    was said to have been heard by neighbours pleading with her 
    husband, to change his evil ways, as she was fed up with people 
    referring to her as the wife of a wizard. It was said that Akpan 
    that night had shouted and threatened his wife to stop bothering 
    him, or he would teach her an unforgettable lesson. The woman had 
    lost her head in the heat of such argument, and in desperation had 
    told her husband, &apos;You can&apos;t do 
    <coll>f---up</coll>&apos;. Those very words that had escaped from 
    my lips moments ago.</p>
    <p>Three days after the quarrel, the story continued, Akpan&apos;s 
    wife and two other women, her friends, had crossed the Iboko narrow 
    strait, opposite the isthmus that links Iboko with Cross River in a 
    canoe to go and pick periwinkles. The sea was calm that day, very 
    calm indeed, but the canoe had somehow capsized. Without 
    difficulty, the two other women had swum to shore, since the 
    accident had taken place in shallow calm waters. But Akpan&apos;s 
    wife had simply disappeared. Two days later, some fishermen had 
    caught a medium sized shark. When they dragged the mammal to shore 
    and opened its belly, they had discovered a human leg inside the 
    animal. That same day a powerful oracle from a neighbouring village 
    had divined, that it was Akpan, who through witchcraft, had 
    overturned the canoe, and caused the shark to swallow Nkoyo, his 
    own wife.</p>
    <p>Such was the need to call Akpan&apos;s bluff, as you can see. 
    So, in spite of the sweat that had begun to run down my ribs inside 
    my shirt, and the fact that my heart was pounding in my chest like 
    hollow gongs, I tried my best, to look cool and unfazed.</p>
    <p>&apos;Akpan&apos;, I began, &apos;it is only a bird that once it 
    learns to fly, flies away and never again remembers mother and 
    father, or a place called home. But a man is never like that. Man 
    always has a home. His own ancestral home. And every ancestral home 
    in Black Africa, as you may know, has an ancestral spirit. Their 
    own family god that guards and guides them. Furthermore&apos;, I 
    invited Akpan. &apos;look around you. Do you see the earth and the 
    sky, the sand, the trees, the sun and the waters of the ocean? 
    <error superfluous="yes">.</error></p>
    <p>Every home has the earth and the sky; and in between them are 
    housed whatever ingredient one needs for witchcraft. All these that 
    you have in Iboko, I also have in my own ancestral village called 
    <italics>kira</italics>. So, if you can kill, I also have all the 
    ingredients in my native village to make witchcraft to kill you 
    too, if I so desire&apos;.</p>
    <p>Akpan gnashed his teeth for the last time, then slowly stretched 
    his wrinkled right had to shake me. &apos;You speak like a real 
    man&apos;, he croaked, nodding his small bald head.</p>
    <p>&apos;When we started, I thought you were a mere kid, a spoilt 
    child trying to rub shoulders with elders. But I was wrong. Yes! 
    You-speak-like a man&apos;, he said, counting the words. &apos;But 
    Mr Ade, that does not change anything I have told you. In fact, 
    your boldness makes my warning even more urgent, more imperative! 
    Send words home for your coffin. And do so quickly too&apos;.</p>
    <p>Those were the very last words Akpan spoke to me, over his 
    shoulders, as he stalked away from the shore, leaving me and the 
    other fishermen behind.</p>
    <p>One might wonder what might have brought about my palaver with 
    Akpan. The story is simple and straight forward. I am a civil 
    servant, an extension officer with the local Ministry of 
    Agriculture. I was sent to Iboko some three months or so ago, to 
    assist and organise the peasant fishermen of Iboko into a 
    co-operative society. When I opened the small liaison office here, 
    I employed two staff, a clerk and a messenger. The clerk was Ufot 
    Jackson Udoh, the son of Akpan. A fortnight ago, I was on tour to 
    other stations under my jurisdiction. When I returned, I discovered 
    that Ufot had sacked the messenger, and had employed his old man in 
    his place.</p>
    <p>&apos;You can&apos;t do that&apos;, I had chided Ufot. 
    &apos;Please ask your father to leave immediately, or I will sack 
    you&apos;. That was all I said.</p>
    <p>And that was the reason why I had earned Akpan&apos;s venom.</p>
    <p>Anyway, the palaver sorted itself out last night. I&apos;m sorry 
    to say that we woke up this morning to hear that Akpan, the old 
    fishermen of Iboko died in his sleep late last night. lt is 
    surprising how these rural people have reacted to the event. I am 
    about to offend so many more people in Iboko, since I do not have 
    the time or stomach to listen to, or receive all the delegations 
    that are billed to call on me today.</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
