<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2009</date>
    <place>Malthouse Press, Nigeria, African Books Collective</place>
    <author><gender>m</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>Igbo</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <p>Battles are generally won with morale. How morale is got varies. 
    To most of the civil populace, the justification of going to war is 
    morale-boosting. Everyday, the government used every means to 
    propagate lucid pictures depicting the opponent as a vampire, 
    devil, vandal, cannibal and what-have-you. To the fighting men in 
    the fronts, propaganda was useless as a morale-boosting factor. It 
    was not the justness of the national cause that spurred the 
    fighting men to gallant deeds. Though the Federal cause was 
    succinctly put during the civil war, almost every young man that 
    enlisted at that period had his personal reasons. The national 
    cause had little to do as far as most of us were concerned.</p>
    <p>Many young men, for instance, enlisted so as to avenge 
    humiliations meted out on them or members of their families by 
    soldiers. In most cases, the avengers knew that they were not going 
    to redeem the humiliations on the soldier that had caused it, but 
    on other innocent civilians. It was a vicious cycle in which the 
    stay-at-homes were always at the receiving end. Sometimes, it was 
    not always for vendetta, but for self-assertion. Most young men 
    felt that they would become supermen once they enlisted in the 
    army. They believed that once a soldier, nobody could dictate to 
    them again. How true this belief is, is a matter of individual 
    experience. For, the humiliating acts passing from one soldier to 
    another is, in most cases, much deeper than from soldier to 
    civilians.</p>
    <p>To many other young men, the glamour of the soldiers&apos; 
    uniform was an irresistible factor that lured many lads into the 
    army. The privileges, real and imagined, and the respect or awe 
    associated with the soldier were some of the other factors that 
    lured many lads into the army. Finally, there were those who 
    enlisted as a result of unemployment or dissatisfaction with jobs 
    held. For instance, those of us who enlisted from the Mid-west 
    after the Biafran invasions were not necessarily the most outraged. 
    Our signing up was no doubt fuelled by some of the aforementioned 
    factors.</p>
    <p>After enlistment, the pride, to live up to personal or external 
    expectations of the profession was usually a driving force behind 
    many heroic exploits. The pride of where one was trained and the 
    unit one belonged to was usually encouraged by military traditions. 
    So as not to let down their alma mater or the renowned unit to 
    which they belonged, many soldiers performed the near impossible. 
    If battles were to be football matches and the spectators 
    civilians, every soldier will probably end up a martyr. To have run 
    battles watched by the sub-humans known as civilians would have 
    been unthinkable. All battles would have been fought to the last 
    man. Many Senior Officers parading about with their exploits as 
    commanders during the war will surely commit suicide if a video 
    recording of their roles in battles were made available.</p>
    <p>Since there are no civilian spectators during battles, when 
    professional pride is confronted by the stark realities of wars, it 
    is only morale that can propel the fighting men to greater 
    sacrifices. And nothing gives morale to the men in battle more than 
    previous victories. Until they have been used in scoring victories, 
    superior training, numbers and equipment are nothing. A bow and 
    arrow carrying unit that was able to defeat a conventionally 
    well-equipped modern opponent is bound to have high morale. With 
    that initial victory-induced high morale, the bow and arrow unit is 
    likely to continue defeating its rifle-carrying opponent. Greater 
    number of men, better weapons and first class training cannot win 
    any battle if the morale is zero.</p>
    <p>By the time some of us were drafted back to retake our lost 
    rear, the series of defeats suffered by our men at Umuagbai had 
    reduced our pride and morale. This was aggravated by the absence of 
    Lt<punctuation>.</punctuation> Akumoko who did not accompany us. With such a low 
    morale, and in the absence of our trusted Officer, things seemed 
    bound to go haywire. The sophisticated weapons which we had not 
    seen before, but which were thrown in to assist us to retake 
    Umuagbai were of little help. The only thing that was waxing 
    stronger every passing minute was rumour. There were rumours that 
    our GOC was not only leaking our plans, but also giving our arms 
    and ammunitions to the enemy. Having been almost dispossessed of 
    Port-Harcourt, the enemy resistance was thought to have been 
    completely broken. According to the rumours the enemy&apos;s 
    continuous resistance was due to a sellout. The GOC was said to 
    have some sympathies for the enemy, because either his mother or 
    wife was said to be an Ibo, the ethnic group that was at the core 
    of the secession.</p>
    <p>We were ruminating over these rumours when the trucks came. They 
    appeared from our fronts which in the real sense was no longer a 
    front. Obigbo, as said earlier, had been occupied by a sister unit. 
    It was supposed to be our next objective if things had turned out 
    as we expected. Our rear was now not safe so it became the new 
    front. Immediately the trucks came to a stop at the headquarters, 
    our company, which was less by a platoon or so was ordered to get 
    into them.</p>
    <p>&apos;<italics>Dem no go write names</italics>?&apos; someone 
    sighed.</p>
    <p>I realized that since we came to the battlefronts there had been 
    no writing or calling of names. In the rear, the names of soldiers 
    going to fatigue in any place outside the immediate surroundings 
    were written more than once. The orderly Corporal had to have a 
    copy of such names. The Section Commander, another copy. The 
    Platoon Sergeant and even the Company Sergeant-Major had to have 
    their copies too. In the fronts, names of men for special and 
    sometimes suicidal missions were often not recorded anywhere. Some 
    men who were reported to have been drafted to Escravos during the 
    Biafran occupation of the Mid-west were without army numbers. They 
    were a few weeks old in their recruit training when this was said 
    to have happened. If it is true; all those who lost their lives 
    without numbers will have no records in the Army Headquarters.</p>
    <p>&apos;Why is the enemy bent on retaking Umuagbai instead of Afam 
    since Afam is more important than Umuagbai?&apos; I asked my trench 
    mate once.</p>
    <p>&apos;Don&apos;t you know that the enemy would rather have the 
    Afam Power Station remain intact in our hands than having it 
    destroyed if protracted battles were fought there?&apos;</p>
    <p>&apos;Ah, no wonder the place was abandoned to us without a 
    serious fight,&apos; I said.</p>
    <p>&apos;But, why do we want to retake Umuagbai? We could just 
    leave it for them.&apos; I asked again after a long pause.</p>
    <p>&apos;Afam itself will not be safe if Umuagbai is in the 
    enemy&apos;s hands. Also, the Ogonis will not feel safe if 
    Umuagbai, a neighbouring village, is in the hands of the Biafrans. 
    In fact, our concentration point for the battles to retake Umuagbai 
    was Bori, the headquarters of the Ogoni District.</p>
    <p>To get to Bori from our position at Afam, we headed towards 
    Obigbo along the tarred road. This was after we had been squeezed 
    tightly into the trucks that had come to take us there. After 
    covering some distance along the tarred road, the trucks swerved 
    into a barely visible bush track by the left. We rumbled on through 
    farms, groves and fallow land overgrown with bush. We swayed, 
    docked and cried not only as a result of the speed of the vehicles 
    by also because of the overhanging branches and bushes that lashed 
    at us if we were a second too slow. After zigzagging for what 
    seemed a long time, we burst out in another tarred road. We headed 
    left on entering this road at the same breakneck speed. Traffic was 
    heavy on this road compared to the ones we had been used to for 
    sometime now. We passed three or four other military trucks that 
    were grotesquely adorned with masks and motifs. Not long after, we 
    arrived at Bori town. The emphasis placed on &apos;town&apos; made 
    it seem as if its &apos;township&apos; was in dispute.</p>
    <p>Before we sped into the town proper, we passed a sprawling green 
    lawn crescented by blocks of houses. A few military hardware could 
    be seen under the shades of the trees that were between these 
    houses. Soldiers could also be seen moving in and out of the 
    houses. As we learnt, the place was the most famous secondary 
    school in the District. Now, it was serving as Headquarters to one 
    of our sister Brigades with whom we started the march to Port 
    Harcourt. The forward-men of this Brigade were now closing in on 
    Port Harcourt. We forked into a side street by our left and in a 
    few minutes, the trucks came to a stop in front of some dilapidated 
    buildings. Here, we learnt, was the temporary headquarters of our 
    Brigade since Umuagbai was wrenched from us by the enemy.</p>
    <p>We were not allowed a minute&apos;s rest on getting down from 
    the trucks. The journey was continued, this time on foot. We 
    marched on along an untarred but motorable road. We crossed one 
    rickety bridge which groaned and creaked under our weight.</p>
    <p>Like amphibians, we had been sleeping in waterlogged trenches in 
    the past few days at Afam. Rain or sunshine, we were always in the 
    open since our second crossing. We started noticing the bad 
    condition of our feet a few days after arriving in Calabar. 
    Everywhere we stayed, if an attack was not imminent our other 
    preoccupation if we were not foraging for what to eat, was the 
    airing of our feet and footwears. After removing the canvas shoes 
    or boots, we would squeeze water out of the socks before spreading 
    them out to dry outside if it was not raining. After that, we would 
    start peeling off whitish fluffy old skins that had formed 
    in-between our toes. Few odours are as nauseating as that of dirty 
    socks mixed with dirtier feet. We had been bearing our foot-rot 
    because so far we have not embarked on any long march at a stretch. 
    But on that day, as we were marching from Bori Town to the next 
    point, the disease was aggravated. Worst affected were those 
    wearing the canvas boots that were commonly called patrol or jungle 
    boots. When the pains became too unbearable to allow for even a 
    limp, some of us started removing the damned footwears and hung 
    them, tied together by the laces on our shoulders or across the 
    neck. Others whose footwears were already torn beyond use as a 
    result of the trek, had them removed and thrown away. We limped 
    like this until we arrived at a junction late in the night. Here we 
    were told to pass the night.</p>
    <p>We had not lain down for an hour when some of us were wakened by 
    a deep eerie monotonous rumbling sound. We sat up in the darkness 
    and pricked up our ears so as to place the frightening sound that 
    seemed to be coming out of the bowels of the earth. Our efforts in 
    this direction was in vain, for as soon as we sat up, the sound was 
    not heard again. We were beginning to doubt our sanity for as soon 
    as we lay down again, the sound became audible and even louder. 
    This time before we could start a panicky shoot out with this 
    mysterious enemy, we started to hear the noise faintly as we sat 
    up. In our prone positions, the direction from which the sound was 
    coming was not the same to all of us. Some claimed it was coming 
    from our front. Others said it was from our sides or the rear. 
    Nobody was however very certain of the direction claimed. All were 
    based on guesswork. As soon as we started hearing the sound in our 
    crouching positions, it became clear that it was coming from our 
    rear.</p>
    <p>To our utter relief, we realized that it was the sound of 
    hundreds of boots of our colleagues as they were marching to join 
    us. Before long, the dark awe-inspiring silhouette of the men at 
    the vanguard of this march became visible. In a few minutes they 
    arrived in our position.</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
