<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2009-06-13</date>
    <place>www.thenationonlineng.com</place>
    <author><gender>m</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>Yoruba</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>What causes high blood pressure?</heading>
    <p>High blood pressure can eventually cause blood vessels in the 
    eye to burst or bleed. Vision may become blurred or otherwise 
    impaired and can result in blindness.</p>
    <heading>Arteries</heading>
    <p>As people get older, arteries throughout the body 
    &quot;harden,&quot; especially those in the heart, brain, and 
    kidneys. High blood pressure is associated with these 
    &quot;stiffer&quot; arteries. This, in turn, causes the heart and 
    kidneys to work harder.</p>
    <heading>Kidney Damage</heading>
    <p>The kidneys act as filters to rid the body of wastes. Over time, 
    high blood pressure can narrow and thicken the blood vessels of the 
    kidneys. The kidneys filter less fluid, and waste builds up in the 
    blood. The kidneys may fail altogether. When this happens, medical 
    treatment (dialysis) or a kidney transplant may be needed.</p>
    <heading>Heart Attack</heading>
    <p>High blood pressure is a major risk factor for heart attack. The 
    arteries bring oxygen-carrying blood to the heart muscle. If the 
    heart cannot get enough oxygen, chest pain, also known as 
    &quot;angina,&quot; can occur. If the flow of blood is blocked, a 
    heart attack results.</p>
    <heading>Congestive Heart Failure (CHF)</heading>
    <p>High blood pressure is the number one risk factor for congestive 
    heart failure (CHF). CHF is a serious condition in which the heart 
    is unable to pump enough blood to supply the body’s needs.</p>
    <p>The causes of high blood pressure vary. Causes may include 
    narrowing of the arteries, a greater than normal volume of blood, 
    or the heart beating faster or more forcefully than it should. Any 
    of these conditions will cause increased pressure against the 
    artery walls. High blood pressure might also be caused by another 
    medical problem. Most of the time, the cause is not known. Although 
    high blood pressure usually cannot be cured, in most cases it can 
    be prevented and controlled.</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
