<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ew</transcriber>
    <date>2007-12-18</date>
    <place>www.thenationonlineng.com</place>
    <author><gender>m</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>Yoruba</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>Five-month old among 275 beneficiaries of free eye 
    surgery</heading>
    <p>From Femi Shodunke, Abeokuta</p>
    <p>No fewer than 275 eye patients have been treated by the Indian 
    doctors who visited Ogun State on a Rotary International Exchange 
    programme.</p>
    <p>A five-month-old child was among the patients that benefited 
    from the medical programme which was at the instance of Rotary 
    International District 9110 in partnership with the Indian 
    community in Lagos and Ogun States.</p>
    <p>Speaking at the &quot;Save Our sight project 2007&quot;, Ogun 
    State Health Commissioner, Dr<punctuation>.</punctuation> Abiodun Oduwole, pleaded with 
    individuals and corporate bodies to help in providing health 
    facilities to support Daniel administration in its effort to 
    improve healthcare.</p>
    <p>Oduwole said at the General Hospital, Ijaiye, Abeokuta, that 
    doing so would help take the healthcare delivery beyond the present 
    level, thus impacting positively in the lives of the citizens.</p>
    <p>The leader of the 12-man team from India, Viral Purohit of 
    Rotary Eye Institute, expressed the delight of the delegation in 
    coming to Ogun State.</p>
    <p>He said that the State had good medical programme, the 
    development which informed the decision of the Indian doctors to 
    visit it.</p>
    <p>According to Purohit, who was accompanied by Rotarian D<punctuation>.</punctuation>S<punctuation>.</punctuation> Mirani, the team began the eye operation from Kaduna, 
    before moving to Lagos and finally ended the trip in Ogun State.</p>
    <p>&quot;We cannot afford not to come to Ogun State because of the 
    healthcare programme of the government here, coupled with the 
    friendly disposition of the doctors and medical staff in this 
    hospital and the people themselves,&quot; the doctor said.</p>
    <p>He explained that among the eye diseases treated were cataract, 
    sight partially lost by acid or fire burns, glaucoma and 
    pterygium.</p>
    <p>Purohit assured that the team would continue to offer necessary 
    assistance to eye patients on yearly basis.</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
