<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ew</transcriber>
    <date>2007-12-18</date>
    <place>www.thenationonlineng.com</place>
    <author><gender>?</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>?</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>US Embassy boosts health reporting in Nigeria</heading>
    <p>About 200 health journalists nation-wide have benefited from a 
    media empowerment workshop held in Lagos and Abuja to equip them 
    with modern skills in community health reporting as well as broaden 
    their professional horizon.</p>
    <p>The workshop<error corrected=","/> which took place at Planet 
    One, Lagos and Transcorp Hilton Hotel, Abuja<error corrected=","/> 
    was facilitated by Ruyi Communications Limited in partnership with 
    the Public Affairs Section of the American Embassy.</p>
    <p>It attracted three American media trainers - Duncan Moore, Bob 
    Hirshon and Andrew Holts- besides four Nigerian media practitioners 
    - Moji Makanjuola, Akin Jimoh, Funke Treasure Durodola and Godwin 
    Odemwingie- as resource persons.</p>
    <p>The worskhop focused on topics ranging from personal hygiene to 
    sourcing health stories from non-health developments, among 
    others.</p>
    <p>In her remarks at the Lagos workshop, the American 
    Consul-General, Vicki Hutchinson, while noting that healthy 
    communities are the backbone of every great nation, said the 
    workshop would empower participants with the right skills and 
    knowledge base to improve the quality, accuracy and visibility of 
    healthcare reporting, writing and editing as a pivotal step to 
    assist Nigeria realise her Vision 2020 goal.</p>
    <p>&quot;Health is now the most important foreign policy issue of 
    our time. Health programs are the fastest-growing component of the 
    U<punctuation>.</punctuation>S<punctuation>.</punctuation> Mission’s development agenda in Nigeria. Our 
    programs save millions of lives by supporting immunisations, 
    disease prevention and control through nutrition, sanitation, 
    hygiene and other health interventions.</p>
    <p>&quot;This workshop seeks to seize on a critical health 
    diplomacy opportunity and build upon the momentum of our aid 
    programs by improving Nigeria’s healthcare journalism and 
    reporting.</p>
    <p>&quot;The media’s potential as a positive influence towards a 
    healthier Nigeria is the reason we are here to train and re-tool 
    Nigerian journalists. We believe those of you selected for this 
    training are the right people to affect a positive change.</p>
    <p>&quot;We believe this workshop will equip you with the right 
    skills, knowledge and attitude to overcome the challenges you may 
    face in your important role of informing the public&quot;.</p>
    <p>Ms<punctuation>.</punctuation> Hutchinson also used the opportunity to restate her 
    home country’s commitment to the global efforts against HIV/AIDS, 
    especially as it concerns Nigeria.</p>
    <p>&quot;In 2003, President George Bush announced the President’s 
    Emergency Plan for AIDS Relief – PEPFAR- a five-year, $15 billion, 
    multifaceted approach to combating HIV/AIDS globally. In May, this 
    year, President Bush announced a doubling of the initial commitment 
    to a total of $30 billion. PEPFAR supports diverse prevention, 
    treatment and care programs, with an emphasis on transparency and 
    accountability for results.</p>
    <p>&quot;The heart of this initiative is a partnership with the 
    government and people of Nigeria to build a locally-driven response 
    to the pandemic. Nigeria is one of the PEPFAR’s 15 focus countries; 
    From 2004 to 2007, Nigeria received more than $648 million dollars 
    in assistance; and PEPFAR has achieved encouraging results, such as 
    free diagnosis and antiretroviral treatment for those infected with 
    HIV, community outreach for HIV awareness and prevention, and 
    providing care and support to children orphaned by AIDS, as well as 
    other vulnerable children&quot;, she said.</p>
    <p>&quot;Over 900,000 people have been reached with HIV counselling 
    and testing; 250,000 pregnant women have been provided with health 
    services for the prevention of mother-to-child transmission of HIV 
    and over 80,000 men, women and children are on anti-retroviral 
    therapy,&quot; said Hutchinson.</p>
    <p>In his address, the Director General of National Agency for the 
    Control of AIDS(NACA), Prof<punctuation>.</punctuation> Babatunde Osotimehin, took 
    participants through the experiences, challenges and discoveries 
    with regards to AIDS awareness and control in Nigeria.</p>
    <p>During the training, Dr<punctuation>.</punctuation> Morhanson-Bello of the 
    University College Hospital, Ibadan (representing Dr<punctuation>.</punctuation>Oladosu 
    Ojengbede) led a demonstration session on the use of anti-shock 
    garment (also known as Life wrap) to save lives and protect women 
    from the effects of post-partum haemorrhage, thereby controlling 
    the worrisome growth of maternal mortality in the country.</p>
    <p>Meanwhile, the CEO of Ruyi Communications, Mr Soni Irabor 
    <error corrected=","/> said the media training programme was aimed 
    at paying more attention to quality and accuracy of reporting while 
    imbibing in the reporter the need to develop the habit of 
    investigating and researching the facts of the stories they 
    cover.</p>
    <p>He emphasized that the training programmes are designed to 
    complement the efforts of media organizations who pay attention to 
    training and retraining of their professionals or those 
    practitioners who believe in developing themselves and their 
    practice.</p>
    <p>According to one of the American trainers, Duncan Moore, the 
    workshop was in response to the realization that reporters, 
    especially health reporters, wield great power and shoulder a great 
    burden of responsibility, as they inform the public on issues that 
    are literally matters of life and death, thereby making adequate 
    knowledge base and ethics paramount in the discharge of their noble 
    responsibility to the society.</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
