<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ew</transcriber>
    <date>2008-01-29</date>
    <place>www.thenationonlineng.com</place>
    <author><gender>m</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>?</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>Buhari extols Onaiyekan’s virtues</heading>
    <p>From Sanni Ologun, Abuja</p>
    <p>A former Head of State, Major General Muhammadu Buhari (rtd), 
    has congratulated the President of Christian Association of Nigeria 
    (CAN) and Catholic Archbishop of Abuja, John Onaiyekan, on his 25th 
    anniversary as a bishop.</p>
    <p>Buhari, who noted Onaiyekan’s faultless dedication over the 
    years, also acknowledged his &quot;steadfastness and devotion&quot; 
    to the service of God and humanity.</p>
    <p>In a statement, Buhari, who, praised the qualities of Onaiyekan 
    as the chairman of the Catholic Bishops Conference of Nigeria, 
    pointed out that his <error superfluous="yes">:</error> 
    &quot;Liberation theology is anchored on his promotion and defense 
    of the core values and basic tenets of democracy of one man, one 
    vote that counts.&quot;</p>
    <p>The statement reads in part: &quot;Permit me on behalf of my 
    family and men of goodwill nationwide, to extend profound 
    congratulations to His Grace, Archbishop of Abuja and President of 
    Christian Association of Nigeria (CAN), on this auspicious silver 
    jubilee anniversary celebration as Bishop of our Lord.</p>
    <p>&quot;It is noteworthy to recall with admiration, the impeccable 
    devotion of His Grace as servant of God Almighty over the years, 
    for this I salute his steadfastness and devotion.</p>
    <p>&quot;May I also extol the liberation virtues of His Grace as 
    the chairman of Catholic Bishops Conference of Nigeria and 
    presently President of Christian Association of Nigeria (CAN), 
    which in no small measure, has added another golden feather to his 
    cap.</p>
    <p>&quot;His Grace’s liberation theology, is anchored on his 
    promotion and defense of the core values and basic tenets of 
    democracy; one man, one vote that counts.</p>
    <p>&quot;For his strident call for free, fair and transparent 
    elections in Nigeria; I salute him, for his courage, I salute him 
    and for his agitation for genuine democracy, I salute him 
    immensely.&quot;</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
