<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ew</transcriber>
    <date>2007-12-18</date>
    <place>www.thenationonlineng.com</place>
    <author><gender>f</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>?</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>Dry port operators worried over land title</heading>
    <p>Concessionaires of Inland Container Depots are at a cross road. 
    They have not been given title documents of the land acquired for 
    the dry port project despite the agreement signed by the government 
    with them.</p>
    <p>The Chairman of the Association of Inland Container Depot 
    Operators, Dr Godfrey Shitgurum, has led a delegation to the 
    Minister of State for Water Transportation, Prince John Emeka, to 
    seek government intervention.</p>
    <p>He lamented the lack of title documents and licence for the land 
    earmarked for the dry ports as they could not secure 
    <error corrected="finance">financé</error> from banks.</p>
    <p>Shitgurum explained that land and title documents were important 
    for seeking <error corrected="finance">financé</error> and 
    investors for the inland container depot.</p>
    <p>He itemised problems militating against the successful 
    implementation of the dry port as including lack of infrastructure 
    which entails a functional railway system and tax reliefs.</p>
    <p>Shitgurum noted that a functional railway system was central to 
    the success of the government reforms in the maritime service.</p>
    <p>He said:&quot;This will bring in more funds into the 
    industry.&quot;</p>
    <p>Shitgurum urged the government to grant the operators tax 
    reliefs and strengthen the supervising agency of the ICD project — 
    Nigerian Shippers Council.</p>
    <p>He also urged the government to empower the agency to organise 
    seminars and workshops on various aspect of the projects for the 
    dry put operators.</p>
    <p>In a statement by the Minister’s Press Secretary Mr<punctuation>.</punctuation> 
    Abiodun Oladunjoye, Prince Emeka assured the operators that 
    government would look into their problem.</p>
    <p>He said that it was important for the beneficiaries of various 
    aspects of government reforms to give adequate 
    <error corrected="feedback">feed back</error> on the impact of such 
    policies in order to render assistance where necessary to the 
    private sector operators.</p>
    <p>Emeka added: &quot;Once a policy has been taken, we need the 
    feedback to be able to beat our chest as to its effectiveness. 
    Government is not to frustrate any operator.</p>
    <p>&quot;It is vital that we open up our hinterland so that we can 
    have other businesses in those areas, not only importers will 
    benefit but exporters because, with more awareness, the farmer will 
    get their produce for export.&quot;</p>
    <p>The Federal Executive Council in March <error superfluous="yes">
    ,</error> 1996 approved the establishment of ICDs to be carried out 
    by six preferred bidders at six locations — Abia, Borno, Plateau, 
    Oyo, Katsina and Kano States. The idea of building Inland Container 
    <error corrected="depot">De</error> on a Build-Own-Operate and 
    Transfer (BOOT) basis was muted in selected stations in Nigeria.</p>
    <p>The purpose was to reduce congestion at the sea ports and 
    enhance easy clearance of goods. Under the arrangement, exporters 
    and importers will not need to travel long distances to take 
    delivery and dispatch cargoes. However, while the official 
    commencement of movement of concessionaries to sites have been 
    carried out in Kano, Jos and Isiala Ngwa, the turning of sod is 
    expected to be carried out in Ibadan, Funtua and Maiduguri 
    <error superfluous="yes">,</error> in the first quarter of 2008.</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
