<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ew</transcriber>
    <date>2008-06-25</date>
    <place>www.mynaijanews.com</place>
    <author><gender>m</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>?</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>ECOWAS Heads of State and Government Converge in 
    Abuja</heading>
    <p>Written by Adeleke Afolayan    </p>
    <p>Nigerian President Umaru Musa Yar&apos;Adua has said the 
    transformation of the Executive Secretariat of the Economic 
    Community of West African States (ECOWAS) into a Commission has 
    engendered great challenges and greater opportunities towards the 
    achievement of total integration in Africa.</p>
    <p>Yar&apos;Adua made this statement in his welcome address at the 
    34th Ordinary Session of the Authority of ECOWAS Heads of State and 
    Government currently holding in Abuja, adding he was highly 
    delighted to host the ECOWAS leaders in the Nigerian capital 
    city.</p>
    <p>According to him, the last 18 months have witnessed a relative 
    socio-political and economic stability within the West African 
    region as well as a general improvement in the security situation 
    as there at present is no &quot;active conflict&quot; in the 
    region.</p>
    <p>He expressed his optimism that there will be greater commitment 
    to the ideals of democracy and good governance, resulting not only 
    in the consolidation of stability across the region but also the 
    facilitation of requisite harmony of diverse domestic policies to 
    accelerate the region&apos;s integration process.</p>
    <p>He therefore called for a self appraisal on the progress of 
    ECOWAS so far and consider the areas which require more attention 
    in the efforts towards integration.</p>
    <p>While various integration Protocols <error corrected=",">
    ;</error> particularly the ones on Common External Tariff (CET), 
    Free Movement of Goods and Persons, Rights of Residence and of 
    Establishment as well as the ECOWAS Trade Liberalisation Scheme 
    (ETLS), have had marked impact on efforts to promoting each West 
    African country&apos;s economy, President Yar&apos;Adua stated that 
    non-tariff barriers to trade in the region still exists.</p>
    <p>This according to him has arisen from conflicting 
    interpretations of the Protocols in different countries in 
    dissonance with the spirit and the letter of the protocols.</p>
    <p>Therefore, leaders of West African nations should make it a duty 
    to make the operation of the protocols more robust and efficient as 
    only then can the peoples, development partners and international 
    community be won to partner with ECOWAS in the realisation of its 
    vision to transform the region into a major player in the global 
    economy.</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
