<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ew</transcriber>
    <date>2008-06-18</date>
    <place>www.thenationonlineng.com</place>
    <author><gender>f</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>?</ethnic-group></author>
    <author><gender>f</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>Yoruba</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>Committee members disagree over Adedibu’s funeral</heading>
    <p>From Oseheye Okwuofu, and Bisi Oladele,Ibadan</p>
    <p>Disagreement among members of the funeral committee for 
    prominent politician and Ashipa Olubadan of Ibadan, Chief Lamidi 
    Ariyibi Adedibu, may mar the eight-day fidau <editor-comment>= 
    Islamic ritual of prayers or ceremonies held in honour of deceased 
    members, and which can last several days (ew)</editor-comment> 
    prayer for the deceased, scheduled for tomorrow.</p>
    <p>The committee’s meeting on the funeral programme ended in a 
    deadlock yesterday as members engaged in altercations.</p>
    <p>The disagreement, it was gathered, was between the late 
    Adedibu’s Personal Assistant, Alhaji Hazeem Gbolarumi, and some 
    members of the committee.</p>
    <p>Besides Gbolarumi, other members of the committee, headed by the 
    Deputy Governor, Hon<punctuation>.</punctuation> Taofeek Arapaja, include Secretary to 
    the State Government (SSG), Chief Olayiwola Olakojo, Dr<punctuation>.</punctuation> 
    Saka Balogun, Hon<punctuation>.</punctuation> Folake Olunloyo- Oshinowo and Senator 
    Kamorudeen Adedibu.</p>
    <p>Gbolarumi however denied the allegation, saying &quot;we only 
    disagreed to agree and we are working towards a common 
    goal.&quot;</p>
    <p>It was gathered that the 15-member committee had been divided 
    into sub-committees.</p>
    <p>The committee’s recommendations are subject to the approval of 
    Governor Adebayo Alao-Akala<error corrected=","/> who is being 
    expected back home from a trip to Paris with President Umar Musa 
    Yar’Adua.</p>
    <p>Gbolarumi, in a telephone interview, confirmed that the 
    committee members disagreed on the funeral programme.</p>
    <p>He said: &quot;We did not fight. But you cannot rule out 
    disagreement on things like these. What happened is that some 
    people wanted some things to go up; others said no, let them go 
    down. We held our meeting today (yesterday) to finalise the whole 
    programme; we had to disagree because some were not okay and so, 
    there were some disagreements.</p>
    <p>&quot;It is not true at all that we fought at our meeting.</p>
    <p>How can that happen? Whatever we agree upon will still be 
    subjected to the approval of the Governor, Otunba Christopher 
    Alao-Akala.&quot;</p>
    <p>According to him, members of the committee are still waiting for 
    the governor for his final say on the funeral programme.</p>
    <p>An Ibadan High Court yesterday joined the executor of the late 
    Adedibu’s will in a suit challenging the destruction of the 
    property of Managing Director, Pelly Foam Limited 
    <error corrected=","/> Mr<punctuation>.</punctuation> Dapo Davies in 2006.</p>
    <p>Justice A<punctuation>.</punctuation>L<punctuation>.</punctuation> Akintola granted the prayer of Davies 
    to substitute the late Adedibu’s name with that of the executor of 
    his will.</p>
    <p>Davies dragged Mr<punctuation>.</punctuation> Peter Asha, Chairman of King Zion 
    Ventures, one of the principal officers in his company, Sola 
    Oyin-Adejobi, Akeem Adebayo (deceased) and King Zion Venture to 
    court over the destruction of his property, worth N1 billion ,by 
    hoodlums suspected to be loyal to the late Adedibu.</p>
    <p>But the hurdle before Davies is to find the name of the executor 
    before July 21<error superfluous="yes">,</error> to present it in 
    his application to the court at its next sitting.</p>
    <p>Conflicting reports have been emanating from the late 
    politician’s children and associates on whether he left a will or 
    died intestate.</p>
    <p>While one of his children, Dauda, claimed that he left no will, 
    others said he did.</p>
    <p>At the resumed hearing of the suit yesterday, Davies’ counsel, 
    Mr<punctuation>.</punctuation> E<punctuation>.</punctuation>A<error corrected="."/> Adesuyi, told the court 
    that in view of the death of Adedibu, he would like to amend the 
    case document to reflect the executor of the late Adedibu’s 
    will.</p>
    <p>Justice Akintola adjourned suit till July 21 for further 
    hearing.</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
