<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ew</transcriber>
    <date>2008-05-21</date>
    <place>www.mynaijanews.com</place>
    <author><gender>m</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>?</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>The Apprentice Africa: Home goes Kathleen</heading>
    <p>Written by Abraham Adegoke</p>
    <p>This season’s The Apprentice Africa edged one episode closer to 
    the end yesterday with the sack of Kathleen. She is the thirteenth 
    apprentice wannabe to be shown the door out of the contest.</p>
    <p>In this episode, the two teams, now equal in manpower with three 
    persons apiece were asked to create an interactive sales event in 
    order to <error>a</error> sell a repackaged brand of Tetmosol to 
    its prime distributors in the country. Tetmosol is one of the major 
    products of Jagal Pharma Limited, a subsidiary of Jagal Group and 
    also a co-sponsor of The Apprentice Africa. The team with the 
    higher profit margin at the end of the task wins.</p>
    <p>Isaac had earlier been chosen as Project Manager for the Matrix 
    corps while Deox was chosen as PM for Zulu corps. Interestingly, 
    the two Project Managers had something in common<error corrected=":"
    >;</error> they had both been project managers on two occasions 
    each. More interesting is the fact that on those two occasions, 
    their teams went on to win the task. Hence, one 
    <error corrected="person&apos;s">persons</error> winning streak as 
    Project Manager was to end in last night’s episode.</p>
    <p>According to the CEO{Biodun Shobanjo}, this week’s task is aimed 
    at bringing to the fore the persuasive ability of both teams - in 
    his exact words,<punctuation>'</punctuation>the art of persuasion<punctuation>'</punctuation>.</p>
    <p>The execution of the task began with a brief session with the 
    CEO of Jagal Group, Mr<punctuation>.</punctuation> Hargrav Richard, to orientate both 
    teams on the rudiments of the trade. Both teams also got a PA each 
    to assist them in the execution of the task.</p>
    <p>Both teams then went about the execution of 
    <error corrected="their">thier</error> tasks in the manner they 
    both know best. Matrix corps seemed to be at a disadvantage when 
    Kathleen could not control her anger while negotiating with one of 
    their prospective customers.</p>
    <p>There was also a little hitch when Blessing of Zulu corps 
    promised one of the distributors that the incentives being given 
    for purchases were on for six months whilst they were actually 
    meant to last two months only.</p>
    <p>The main action in this tasks for the contestants was to sell 
    more products whilst offering less incentives to the 
    distributors.</p>
    <p>At the boardroom, both team leaders of the corps were optimistic 
    of their teams&apos; success underlining the fact that they all 
    gave their best.</p>
    <p>Before delivering the verdict, Richard noted that Zulu corps was 
    much more confident in executing their task and they closed their 
    deals sooner than their Matrix counterparts. He further noted that 
    Matrix <error corrected="corps">corp</error> was weaker and less 
    organised than Zulu and that they got desperate at a point in the 
    execution of the task.</p>
    <p>The verdict. After summing up the sales of both teams and the 
    incentives they offered, Matrix corps had a profit of $160,000 
    while Zulu corps made a total profit of $192,000. Zulu 
    <error corrected="corps">corp</error> won.</p>
    <p>Asked what went wrong, Isaac of Matrix corps, without mincing 
    words, pointed accusing fingers at Kathleen. He went on to give an 
    analysis of her behaviour since the contest began saying she had 
    poor interpersonal relations which cost them a lot in the task. He 
    concluded by <error corrected="saying">sayng</error> if Kathleen 
    had given him half of what Eunice gave him, it would have been a 
    different story.</p>
    <p>Eunice supported his views and for that reason, Kathleen was 
    FIRED!!!</p>
    <p>This leaves just five contestants in the race for 
    <error corrected="Africa&apos;s">africa&apos;s</error> prime 
    apprentice.</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
