<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2009-06-17</date>
    <place>http://thenationonlineng.net/web</place>
    <author><gender>m</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>?</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>Nigeria to US: We are not at war in Niger Delta</heading>
    <p>The military is not at war with the people of Niger Delta, the 
    Federal Government said yesterday.</p>
    <p>Explaining that the ongoing operation in the region is to flush 
    out the &quot;criminal elements&quot;, the government it would not 
    be provoked to declare war on its own citizens.</p>
    <p>It identified illegal oil bunkerers and arms dealers as those 
    behind the restiveness in the region.</p>
    <p>Minister of Niger Delta Affairs, Ufot Ekaette, and his Foreign 
    Affairs counterpart, Ojo Maduekwe, made these known in Washington, 
    United States (US) at a special session organised by the Centre for 
    Strategic and International Studies (CSIS).</p>
    <p>Ekaette, who spoke on how to resolve the Niger Delta crisis and 
    bring about peace and development, said the armed forces were not 
    at war with the Niger Delta and would never be despite provocation 
    by criminals posing as Niger Delta crusaders.</p>
    <p>A statement by the Special Assistant (Media) to Ekaette quoted 
    him as saying that contrary to the propaganda by the oil bunkerers 
    and arms dealers, the government was doing its best to checkmate 
    criminal tendencies in the Niger Delta to pave the way for genuine 
    peace and development.</p>
    <p>The statement reads in part: &quot;Ekaette said that it was 
    wrong for the same people who accused the government of not 
    developing the Niger Delta to turn round and drive away development 
    agents, including contractors and foreign oil workers through 
    kidnapping for ransom, killing and destruction of 
    facilities.&quot;</p>
    <p>Ekaette, who pointed out that it was in a bid to significantly 
    improve the Niger Delta that the Federal Government created the 
    Ministry of Niger Delta, added that the government has already 
    worked out a concrete development programme for the region.</p>
    <p>The ministry said it had worked out modalities for the 
    construction of 45 new intra-and-inter-city roads in addition to 
    the multi-billion Niger Delta Coastal and East-West roads.</p>
    <p>The statement added: &quot;He also said that no fewer than 360 
    housing units had been slated for construction in the nine states 
    that make up the Niger Delta by the new ministry, while the 
    training of youths will begin next month.</p>
    <p>&quot;Ekaette also said an inventory of dumpsites and oil 
    impacted sites in the Niger Delta region was being undertaken with 
    a view to remedying the areas for productive uses by the 
    communities.</p>
    <p>&quot;He, however, appealed to the international community to 
    support Nigeria’s effort to end the Niger Delta crisis by checking 
    the sale of illegal of arms into the Niger Delta in exchange for 
    Nigeria’s stolen crude oil by criminals.</p>
    <p>&quot;The minister stated that the Federal Government was 
    determined to end the crisis by offering amnesty to those willing 
    to lay down their arms and be trained and re-integrated into the 
    society for meaningful life.</p>
    <p>&quot;Minister of Foreign Affairs, Chief Ojo Maduekwe, made it 
    clear that the recent crisis in the Niger Delta was triggered by 
    criminals who ambushed and killed Nigerian soldiers on routine 
    duties and said that the soldiers were not out to engage in wanton 
    destruction of lives and property of any community.</p>
    <p>&quot;Maduekwe drew the attention of the audience to the fact 
    that as a country that emerged from a very painful civil war, 
    Nigeria would not allow any group or individual to plunge it into 
    avoidable conflict and appealed to the international community to 
    allow Nigeria to take steps to resolve the problems posed by 
    criminals in the Niger Delta.&quot;</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
