<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ew</transcriber>
    <date>2008-06-26</date>
    <place>www.mynaijanews.com</place>
    <author><gender>m</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>?</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>Kano Power Project Doomed</heading>
    <p>Written by Adeleke Afolayan</p>
    <p>Alhaji Mohammadu Danpass has accused the ruling All Nigeria 
    Peoples Party (ANPP) government in Kano State of 
    <error corrected="impoverishing">improverishing</error> the people, 
    stating that the situation of electricity in Kano has never been as 
    bad as currently obtained.</p>
    <p>Danpass, who was campaign director to Dr<punctuation>.</punctuation> Abubakar Rimi 
    during the 2003 presidential election, added that the proposed 
    Independent Power Project (IPP) would not see the light of day till 
    the end of tenure of the present dispensation.</p>
    <p>According to him, the IPP projects is still mere paperwork and 
    would suffer the same fate as the N5<punctuation>.</punctuation>6b water project is as 
    the government has never been sincere with the people of Kano.</p>
    <p>Because of the government&apos;s insensitivity towards the 
    plight of the people, business activities have been on a downhill 
    slope and signing a Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) with two 
    companies to build IPP plants in two years is not what the people 
    want to hear according to Danpass.</p>
    <p>Danpass went further to state that Kano is no longer a 
    commercial center in the country but a corner shop State due to the 
    situation where people now open shops instead of establishing 
    indigenous industries.</p>
    <p>He made an example of the textile industry which according to 
    him <error corrected="has">as</error> seen a 50% drop in patronage 
    in the last two years after being one of the busiest market sectors 
    in the country.</p>
    <p>The <error corrected="people&apos;s">Peoples</error> Democratic 
    Party (PDP) chieftain therefore called on the leadership of the 
    ANPP in the State to put politics aside and face the reality on 
    ground, adding the situation could go out of hand if left 
    unchecked.</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
