<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ew</transcriber>
    <date>2008-06-24</date>
    <place>www.mynaijanews.com</place>
    <author><gender>m</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>?</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>Kano State Government Aid Farmers in Boosting Food 
    Production</heading>
    <p>Written by Adeleke Afolayan</p>
    <p>The Kano State Government in an effort to boost the production 
    of food in the State by its farmers has provided different species 
    of seeds, including maize, cotton and groundnut, to ensure this 
    year&apos;s farming season is more bountiful.</p>
    <p>Disclosing this was the Alhaji Dahiru Abdu Garko who said the 
    State Government is resolved to provide varieties of seedlings to 
    farmers this year to address the outcry of insufficient food in the 
    State.</p>
    <p>He explained further that the programme to provide seedlings was 
    also designed with a view to improving agricultural activities and 
    promote farmers&apos; efforts to harvesting larger quantity of food 
    crops.</p>
    <p>Alhaji Garko added that for the farmers to achieve the set 
    objectives of the government, farmers&apos; compliance with 
    instructions given on conducting projects is paramount to ensure 
    Kano State is free from the global food crisis.</p>
    <p>According to him, should the farmers fail to abide by the given 
    instruction, the State would likely experience a negative output in 
    the agricultural sector which consequently would result in poor 
    harvest and hunger.</p>
    <p>However, progress reports have started to come in according to 
    Alhaji Garko, indicating that the State agricultural ministry will 
    succeed in its mission. He added that maize production in Gabasawa 
    Local Government has been enhanced.</p>
    <p>He then urged the trained farmers to endure the difficulty of 
    the system, and in the meantime take advantage of the programme 
    with good expectation and conduct according to the project&apos;s 
    laid down procedure.</p>
    <p>The <error corrected="programme">progremme</error> officer also 
    hinted that anybody who purchases one bag of seeds and applies his 
    acquired knowledge would unfailingly qualify to purchase 
    fertilizers at the Ministry at an affordable price.</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
