<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2009-06-18</date>
    <place>http://thenationonlineng.net/web</place>
    <author><gender>?</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>?</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>Suspected kidnappers of Ondo officials’ wives 
    arrested</heading>
    <p>The efforts of the Ondo State Police Command to secure the 
    release of the wives of the Commissioner for Lands and Housing, and 
    a Permanent Secretary, Mrs Iyabo Basaru and Mrs Sola Alli, who were 
    abducted last Sunday, paid off yesterday with the arrest of the 
    suspected kidnappers.</p>
    <p>The suspects were arrested by policemen after they were tricked 
    that they would be paid a ransom to secure the release of the 
    hostages.</p>
    <p>Earlier, Mrs Alli was said to have escaped from the hands of her 
    abductors and made her way home yesterday.</p>
    <p>Speaking with reporters yesterday in Akure, Commissioner of 
    Police Charles Dawodu said the women were released after a gun duel 
    with the hoodlums.</p>
    <p>He was, however, silent on whether a ransom was paid to the 
    kidnappers before they were apprehended.</p>
    <p>But a source told <italics>The Nation</italics> that a 
    N10million ransom was paid before the breakthrough was recorded.</p>
    <p>There was jubilation at Ajipowo and Alagbaka Government 
    Reservation Area (GRA), Akure home of the freed hostages. Family 
    members, friends and well – wishers stormed the Basarus’ and Allis’ 
    homes to rejoice with them.</p>
    <p>A source said the suspected kidnappers were arrested at their 
    hideout in Edo State.</p>
    <p>One of them, whose identity was still been shielded, was killed 
    in the gun duel, it was learnt.</p>
    <p>Dawodu, who refused to give further details on the arrests, said 
    the suspects were in the custody of the police.</p>
    <p>Assistant-Inspector General of Police (AIG) in charge of Zone 
    II, Mr<punctuation>.</punctuation> Mohammad Yesufu, flew into the state following the 
    news of the kidnapping on Sunday, to join in the manhunt for the 
    kidnappers.</p>
    <p>An elated Governor Olusegun Mimiko congratulated the police, the 
    State Security Service (SSS) and all those involved in the foiling 
    of the crime.</p>
    <p>Mimiko, in a release issued by his Chief Press Secretary (CPS) 
    Kolawole Olabisi in Akure, yesterday, hailed the courage, diligence 
    and commitment of the officers.</p>
    <p>The statement reads in part: &quot;We congratulate the two 
    families and urge them to move on with life, unencumbered by the 
    psychological trauma that may have been caused by the unholy 
    kidnap. As a government, we have stated that we shall not submit to 
    blackmail of any kind and will strive at all times to protect the 
    interest of the larger majority of people who are law-abiding and 
    peace-loving.</p>
    <p>&quot;We cannot afford to surrender to a few who have taken the 
    alternative of seeking wealth and recognition to the detriment of 
    the society, hence our refusal to negotiate with the kidnappers 
    till the release of our dear citizens were secured.</p>
    <p>&quot;We salute their families for calmly bearing the burden of 
    missing their loved ones while their fate appeared uncertain. Our 
    faith in God, like theirs was unshaken that the ungodly effort will 
    be thwarted.</p>
    <p>&quot;We are full of thanks to God for answering our prayers by 
    rewarding the diligence of the security agencies. Once again, 
    government congratulates the security agencies for a job well done 
    and rejoices with the families on a sorrow-free re-union.&quot;</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
