<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2009-06-19</date>
    <place>http://thenationonlineng.net/web/</place>
    <author><gender>m</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>Yoruba</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>Aliyu vs Kure: A battle IBB could not settle</heading>
    <p><italics>Despite the intervention of two former Heads of State, 
    Ibrahim Babangida and Abdulsalami Abubakar, Niger State Governor 
    Babangida Aliyu and his predecessor, Abdulkadir Kure sink deeper 
    into the trenches, writes OLUKOREDE <error corrected="YISHAU.">
    YISHAU</error></italics></p>
    <p>Abdulkadir Kure was governor of Niger State from May 29, 1999 to 
    May 29, 2007. He was succeeded by Babangida Alyu, who is also a 
    member of the ruling People’s Democratic Party (PDP). Kure’s wife, 
    who is a Senator, and his six children may soon have to deal with a 
    situation where their father is picked up by the police over an 
    indictment for corruption. The days when he had immunity from 
    arrest and prosecution ended May 29, 2007.</p>
    <p>Unlike Kure, who was addressed as His Excellency, Aliyu dropped 
    the fanciful title for the less glamorous title of Chief Servant. 
    And as the Chief Servant, he says the people of the Power State are 
    his boss, and on their behalf he would fight anyone.</p>
    <p>Since he mounted the saddle as the governor, Aliyu has been 
    fighting his predecessor, who claims he is just being vilified for 
    nothing. But the governor counters by saying he is all out for the 
    people. A probe instituted by Aliyu into the activities of his 
    predecessor has led to a white paper banning Kure from running for 
    public office for ten years.</p>
    <p>Five other politicians have also been banned from holding public 
    office in the next ten years. They include the former Vice Chairman 
    of the PDP for the North Central Zone, Alhaji Abubakar Magaji and 
    the former Commissioner for Justice and Attorney General in the 
    state, Alhaji Umar Kawu, former Permanent Secretary of the state’s 
    Ministry of Local Government and Chieftaincy Affairs, Alhaji 
    Alhassan Jibrin Bala, and a former director in the ministry, Alhaji 
    Mohammed Katuka. They were all key members of the Kure 
    administration.</p>
    <p>Kure, who is now Chairman of the Federal Emergency Road 
    Maintenance Agency (FERMA), had tried to stop the Judicial 
    Commission of Inquiry established by Aliyu last year. The court 
    refused to grant his prayers seeking to stop the inquiry. The seven 
    man commission was set up to probe malpractices relating to the 
    awards and execution of contracts under the immediate past 
    administration between 1999 and 2007.</p>
    <p>Kure was indicted over the supply of 200metric 
    <error corrected="tonnes">tones</error> of iron rod, and ordered to 
    account for N99million the state loss to wrong computation. The 
    white paper also indicted the former governor in the supply of 
    ductile iron pipe fittings and water pumps to Lapai Agaie, Katcha, 
    Kontagora, New Bussa, Lambata, Mokwa and Gawu Babangida by BEEDASH 
    Nigeria Limited under the multi million Naira state-wide water 
    scheme. The former governor was also directed by the government to 
    account for N708million, for which he may face prosecution. The 
    White paper also found Alhassan and Katuka wanting of financial 
    malpractices in their handling of the state/local government joint 
    account, while Kawu was indicted over his handling of the state 
    tender board as the chairman of the board. It also indicted the new 
    Speaker of the Niger State House of Assembly, Alhaji Saidu Ndako 
    Idris, who was asked to refund N89 million allegedly 
    misappropriated during the last administration when he was the 
    Chairman of Mokwa Local Government Area of the state. He is also 
    asked to refund over N97 million to the government coffers being 
    the amount illegally withdrawn from the local government joint 
    account and the treasury of the Mokwa Local Government Council.</p>
    <p>As a result of this, the Niger State Police Command has declared 
    him and eight others wanted. The state Police Public Relations 
    Officer, Richard Oguche (ASP), confirmed that a warrant of arrest 
    had been issued against the speaker and eight others.</p>
    <p>Oguche said: &quot;The police had no choice than to take the 
    action after the affected persons had failed to voluntarily hand 
    themselves over to the police after summons were served on 
    them.&quot;</p>
    <p>He said the police took the action because of a report from the 
    Maj-Gen Mamman Kontagora Implementation Committee. &quot;We have 
    not seen them up till now but I can assure you that we will get 
    them to ensure they face prosecution,&quot; Oguche said. For Kure, 
    these are indeed trying times. Keen observers of events in the 
    state had predicted that the ex-governor would find it difficult to 
    come out clean after the enquiry. In March 2008, Aliyu alleged that 
    Kure awarded contracts verbally, without documentations. He said 
    his administration inherited N23 billion debt from the Kure 
    administration, and was able to verify only N13 billion of it. This 
    was about the same time the commission ordered the arrest of the 
    managing director of a Jos-based contracting firm, Rishabel 
    Interior, for failure to honour its summons. Alhaji Babangida 
    Suleiman was summoned to appear before the panel twice to give 
    evidence regarding a N10<punctuation>.</punctuation>5 million contract given to the 
    company. The contract was for the supply of 1,000 double bunk beds 
    to Niger State Ministry of Education. The contract was awarded in 
    2000 of which N8 million was paid as part payment. The contract was 
    among the failed contracts investigated by the panel. Testifying 
    before the panel, Kure’s Commissioner for Education, Alhaji 
    Abubakar Daja said the contractor did not execute the contract.</p>
    <p>Significantly, two former Heads of State from the state, 
    Generals Ibrahim Babangida and Abdulsalami Abubakar, are said to 
    have waded into the crisis between the duo, with the hope of 
    finding a solution. At that time, it was assumed that a truce was 
    recorded.</p>
    <p>Now, it is clear to all that whatever truce was reached has 
    broken down. And depending on the way the Kontagora Committee 
    chooses to go about it, Kure may be arrested. Others indicted by 
    the commission are being sought by the police already.</p>
    <p>The last has certainly not been heard of the drama in Niger. It 
    is just unfolding.</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
