<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2009-06-09</date>
    <place>http://www.vanguardngr.com/</place>
    <author><gender>?</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>?</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>Polio eradication: How Nigeria faced the world at World 
    Health Assembly</heading>
    <p>WHEN the 62nd World Health Assembly opened at the Palais de 
    Nations in Geneva Switzerland on May 18, 2009, one of the major 
    health concerns of international interest, besides the (then) 
    looming H1N1 influenza (swine flu) pandemic, was the race towards 
    global target for eradication of poliomyelitis.</p>
    <p>Still plagued by the ghosts of the October 2003 controversy 
    surrounding the immunisation programme against polio in which three 
    states in northern Nigeria (Kano, Katsina and Jigawa) boycotted the 
    polio immunisation campaign, it was not surprising that Nigeria has 
    remained squarely in the eye of the storm about polio 
    eradication.</p>
    <p>At the time of the boycott, the Global Polio Eradication 
    Initiative had launched what was hoped to be the final onslaught 
    against polio, with a plan to immunise more than 15 million 
    children in West and Central Africa.</p>
    <p>There had been particular concerns about the high prevalence of 
    polio cases in Nigeria, and the World Health Organisation (WHO) had 
    it on record that the nation accounted for about 45 per cent of 
    polio cases worldwide and 80 per cent of cases reported from the 
    African region in 2003. The high prevalence was attributed to poor 
    vaccine coverage during the previous control campaigns. No thanks 
    to the boycott, the nation is now one of the four nations 
    (alongsideÔÇŽ..) on the yet to interrupt the wild poliovirus 
    transmission.</p>
    <p>In 2008, during the 61st WHA, one of the resolutions adopted at 
    the end of the meeting was that Nigeria should strive to ÔÇťreduce 
    the risk of international spread of poliovirus.ÔÇ?</p>
    <p>Expectedly, this particular resolution was primal on the agenda 
    which the Nigerian delegation to the meeting had committed to 
    address along with issues concerning maternal and child health, 
    malaria control, pandemic influenza prevention and control, non 
    communicable disease prevention and control, and national 
    legislation on health, among others.</p>
    <p>So as the 62nd WHA got under way, the world was all ears to know 
    just how far the country had progressed. No one was better placed 
    to tell the story than NigeriaÔÇÖs own Minister of Health, Prof<punctuation>.</punctuation> Babatunde Osotimehin, who led the 28-man delegation to the 
    event.</p>
    <p>Mounting the rostrum, Osotimehin delved into the series of 
    activities and events the nation had undertaken to meet the WHA 
    mandate as far as polio was concerned.</p>
    <p>Noting that Nigeria did make appreciable progress in polio 
    eradication from 1998-2002 but suffered a major set-back in 
    2003-2004 as a result of controversy over the safety of the Oral 
    Polio Vaccine (OPV), he said: ÔÇťThat setback ensured that Nigeria is 
    one of only four countries yet to interrupt the wild poliovirus 
    transmission in the World. Following this, polio eradication 
    efforts were intensified. These include new innovations aimed at 
    improving effectiveness of polio eradication activities, 
    utilization of the more effective monovalent Oral Polio Vaccine 
    (mOPVs), and mOPV3 with an integrated approach, and adoption of the 
    Immunization Plus Days (IPDs+).</p>
    <p>During IPDs, a broad range of child survival interventions 
    resulted in marked improvement of the quality of vaccinations and a 
    significant decline in incidence of wild polio transmission. 
    However progress could not be sustained resulting in a major 
    resurgence of wild polio virus transmission in 2008 
    <error corrected="such.">such</error></p>
    <p>The Minister elaborated on how the nation placed emphasis on the 
    importance of vaccination is a crucial tool for preventing and 
    controlling the disease.</p>
    <p>Already, in line with the resolution adopted at the 61st World 
    Health Assembly urging Nigeria to ÔÇťreduce the risk of international 
    spread of poliovirusÔÇ?, Osotimehin said the nation had quickly 
    stepped up efforts aimed at stopping the polio outbreak in northern 
    Nigeria through intensified eradication activities that ensured 
    vaccination of all children with the oral polio vaccine.</p>
    <p>The 62nd WHA was assured that since the 61st WHA one year ago, 
    Nigeria has put in place important measures and have also recorded 
    commendable outcomes. Delegates <error corrected="heard">
    heared</error> that Nigeria has implemented six rounds of enhanced 
    Supplemental Immunisation Activities (SIAs), three of which have 
    been national campaigns. He said the quality of these campaigns 
    show a steady improvement and the number of Local Government Areas 
    (LGAs) achieving 90 per cent coverage of polio increased to 627 
    during the March 2009 SIAs. As a result of the steady improvement 
    in quality of the SIAs, the number of unvaccinated children during 
    campaigns declined significantly.</p>
    <p>On the revitalising the routine immunisation, the Minister said 
    efforts to improve routine immunisation performance are bearing 
    modest dividends and national routine OPV3 coverage increased from 
    47 per cent at the beginning of 2008 to 63 per cent in the first 
    quarter in 2009; a 75 per cent increase within 12 months.</p>
    <p>Other pointers he gave include Acute Flaccid Paralysis 
    Surveillance. ÔÇťIn this regard, certification standard (AFP) 
    performance was maintained at national level and in all but one 
    state in 2008. At LGA level, 73 per cent of all LGAs in the country 
    met the two main AFP surveillance performance indicators. Both 
    national polio laboratories in the country located at Ibadan and 
    Maiduguri maintained WHO accreditation in 2008.ÔÇ?</p>
    <p>On population immunity, the Minister recalled: ÔÇťThe improved 
    quality of immunisation activities has impacted positively on 
    population immunity. The proportion of non-polio AFP cases aged 
    6-35 months reported never to have received a single dose of OPV 
    declined from 15 per cent in 2006 to less than 5 per cent by the 
    first quarter of 2009.</p>
    <p>ÔÇťSimilarly, the proportion of non-polio AFP cases aged 6-35 
    months that were reported to have received at least three dose of 
    OPV increased from 62 per cent in 2006 to 78 per cent by the first 
    quarter of 2009. The most dramatic improvement in population 
    immunity was registered in <error corrected="Kano,">Kano ,</error> 
    where for the first time ever, the children never vaccinated, 
    reduced to less than 20 per cent.ÔÇ?</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
