<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2009-06-19</date>
    <place>http://thenationonlineng.net/web/</place>
    <author><gender>f</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>?</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>Lack of quality friendly games frustrates Siaisia</heading>
    <p>National Under-20 Coach Samson Siasia has expressed frustration 
    at the inability of his boys to play friendly matches which are up 
    to standard in preparation for the Under-20 World Cup which will 
    hold in Egypt in September.</p>
    <p>Siasia stated that he was disappointed he will not be playing 
    the Young Pharaohs of Egypt before the World Cup.</p>
    <p>He said: &quot;I don’t even know what is going on. But I am very 
    disappointed. I was actually looking forward to playing friendly 
    games with good football teams. For instance that of Malaysia was 
    because of the swine <error corrected="flu.">flu .</error></p>
    <p>&quot;But when we go to Qatar and come back we will arrange a 
    game between Ghana or Ivory Coast. We need to play games not just 
    any game at all. <error corrected="How">Hw</error> do you access 
    these players without playing a good game? So it’s going to be very 
    difficult. We will come back from Qatar and we will try to play 
    some friendly matches before we go to Spain.&quot;</p>
    <p>The Flying Eagles who won last year&apos;s Intercontinental Cup 
    in Malaysia, have continued to experienced hiccups in their various 
    attempts which include the assembling of players.</p>
    <p>On June 23 the Flying Eagles will take on the home-based Super 
    Eagles once again in friendly. It could be recalled that the 
    home-based Eagles defeated the Siaisa side by 1-0 few weeks ago.</p>
    <p>Meanwhile, the team is expected to go on a recess for ten days 
    after which they are expected to assemble back for a training tour 
    to Qatar on the 4th of July.</p>
    <p>Nigeria was drawn in group B alongside Spain, Venezuela and 
    Tahiti in the Under-20 World Cup to be hosted by Egypt.</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
