<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2009-06-10</date>
    <place>http://www.vanguardngr.com/</place>
    <author><gender>?</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>?</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>Zinox Computers bags international awards</heading>
    <p>Zinox Technologies <error corrected="Limited">Lim ited</error>, 
    one of the local PCs assemblers has consolidated its class as 
    Africa’s emerging technology power house with multiple 
    international awards from Intel Corporation and WITSA 
    respectively.</p>
    <p>At the just concluded Intel Solutions Summit Prague held in the 
    Czech Republic, Zinox Computers was declared, for the second time, 
    the Intel Global Award winner for Mobile computing in Africa, 
    Middle East and Turkey.</p>
    <p>The award consolidates the place of Zinox Computers in the Intel 
    Prestigious Champions Club for building a successful global brand. 
    In effect Intel research consultants would continue to work with 
    the Zinox team of Engineers to build new generation Zinox laptops 
    which would beat competition. This is one of the exclusive 
    privileges enjoyed by Zinox based on her achievements in the mobile 
    computing market.</p>
    <p>With this, it qualify Zinox to enjoy an intimate technical 
    collaboration in the design and building of systems that would 
    yield extra value to the end users. Zinox Computers would continue 
    to draw exclusively from the rich Research &amp; Development 
    resources of Intel and produce systems that rank among the very 
    best in the world.</p>
    <p>Reacting to the Award Leo Stan Ekeh, Chairman of Zinox 
    Technologies Limited, said that these recognitions are testimonials 
    to the steady growth of the Zinox Group in terms of high brand 
    equity which is as a result of established quality processes, 
    people and technologies going by the ratings of international 
    Agencies like the IDC. He reported that Intel was particularly 
    impressed by the commitment of the Zinox team to IT penetration and 
    promotion of knowledge democracy in Nigeria. He revealed that Intel 
    shared the Zinox passion that only an appropriately computerized 
    educational sector can pave the way for national development.</p>
    <p>He said that Zinox would become a world leader if given the 
    chance by the people and Governments of Nigeria. He further 
    revealed that the Nigerian consumers were already enjoying the 
    benefits of the Zinox membership of the Intel Champions Club. 
    Mr<punctuation>.</punctuation> Ekeh fingered the Zinox Smart Plus, the Bijimi Sage and 
    the sensational Bijimi PRO as some of the quality products from 
    that cooperative effort. He urged the Nigerian public to expect 
    more state of the art laptops from Zinox Computers.</p>
    <p>In a related development the World Information Technology &amp; 
    Services Alliance (WITSA) in partnership with the Information 
    Technology (Industry) Association of Nigeria (ITAN), in 
    collaboration with the Nigerian Computer Society (NCS) recently 
    recognized Zinox as a World renowned Information Technology 
    Champion in Nigeria.</p>
    <p>Tagged the Information Technology Champion Award 2009, the award 
    was presented by the WITSA Chairman, Dato&apos; Dan E<punctuation>.</punctuation> Khoo 
    at a banquet in his honour at the Transcorp Hilton Hotel, Abuja. 
    The citation preceding the Award said that the Award was in 
    recognition of Zinox Computers’ exemplary commitment to the 
    advocacy, application, promotion, use and deployment of Information 
    Technology infrastructure and contents in the work place as a means 
    of boosting productivity and fast tracking the business of 
    governance, learning, and creation of jobs towards the attainment 
    of the 21st Century Knowledge Society in Nigeria.</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
