<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2009-06-23</date>
    <place>http://www.vanguardngr.com/</place>
    <author><gender>m</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>Igbo</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>Let&apos;s take security seriously</heading>
    <p>A Premier League player with Warri Wolves, Chuks Nwokocha, has 
    called on the Nigeria Premier League to always provide adequate 
    security at match venues to prevent the ugly situation where 
    players and officials on away matches are intimidated and battered 
    by home fans.</p>
    <p>Nwokocha, who was one of the winners in the Oceanic Football 
    Challenge with Fashanu last year spoke to Sports Vanguard yesterday 
    at the National Stadium Surulere, Lagos, where he was training. 
    This reporter was attracted to the scene when he heard one of the 
    popular numbers of P-Square blaring away in a Kia Rio branded in 
    Oceanic Football Challenge.</p>
    <p>The Oceanic Talent Hunt star lamented the security situation at 
    match venues which makes it so easy for fans to attack players and 
    officials. He recalled that his team, Warri Wolves, were attacked 
    in Gasau, Zamfara State, by the fans of Zamfara United, while the 
    fans of Niger Tornadoes followed suit in Minna, with another 
    face-off at Nnewi in their match against Rangers.</p>
    <p>Nwokocha said he left for trials with Arab Contractors of Egypt 
    immediately after the Oceanic Bank Challenge, when the promise to 
    take six of them that were selected for trials in Europe failed, 
    but could not make it because of a knee injury and the winter in 
    that part of the world at that time, adding that his movement to 
    Egypt was facilitated by his France-based Nigerian agent.</p>
    <p>The Oguta, Imo State-born player joined Warri Wolves in the 
    January transfer window this year and expressed happiness that they 
    finished fourth on the league table.</p>
    <p>He thanked Oceanic Bank International Plc for providing him and 
    others the opportunity to excel while calling on other corporate 
    organisations to emulate Oceanic Bank and help take our teeming 
    youths away from vices.</p>
    <p>He challenged Nigerian youths to take advantage of the 2nd 
    Oceanic Bank Talent Hunt with Jay Jay Okocha to improve their 
    lots.</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
