<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2009-06-22</date>
    <place>http://www.vanguardngr.com/</place>
    <author><gender>m</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>Igbo</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>Oando records 52 per cent increase in PAT</heading>
    <p>Oando Plc has announced an increase in its Profit After Tax 
    (PAT) for its audited reports for the financial year ended December 
    31, 2009, with a 52% increase in the Group‚Äôs net profit.</p>
    <p>This grew from N5<punctuation>.</punctuation>48 billion in 2007 to N8<punctuation>.</punctuation>34 
    billion in 2008. This remarkable result was attributable to the 
    company‚Äôs improved operational efficiency and increased trade 
    volumes.</p>
    <p>The result which was made available to Vanguard show that the 
    company is paying a total dividend of N6<punctuation>.</punctuation>00 per share.</p>
    <p>Vanguard also gathered that the board voted to recommend a 
    dividend of N3<punctuation>.</punctuation>00 for each ordinary share of 50 kobo in 
    addition to the interim dividend of N3<punctuation>.</punctuation>00 paid within the 
    financial year. This brings to N6<punctuation>.</punctuation>00 each the total dividend 
    for the year subject to shareholders‚Äô approval at the next Annual 
    General Meeting.</p>
    <p>The result shows that turnover increased 83 per cent to 
    N339billion from N186bn in 2007. Gross profit grew 59 per cent to 
    N11billion from N7billion in 2007. Gross Profit Margin increases by 
    85 per cent to N40billion. Profit attributable to ordinary 
    shareholders rose by 53 per cent to N8billion from N5billion in 
    2007. Earning per share increases to N9<punctuation>.</punctuation>90 from N7<punctuation>.</punctuation>24.</p>
    <p>Other operational highlights show sterling improvement of 165 
    per cent from N8<punctuation>.</punctuation>1billion in 2007 to N21<punctuation>.</punctuation>4billion in 
    2008. Efficiency initiatives improved performance in traditional 
    marketing <error corrected="and.">and .</error>The company 
    concluded on the purchase of two rigs while an additional rig was 
    bought during the <error corrected="year.">year</error></p>
    <p>During the year under review the company acquired significant 
    stake in offshore blocks OML 125 &amp; 134. The strong performance 
    according stock market operators demonstrates the robustness of 
    Oando‚Äôs diversified business model that enables it deliver 
    consistent value despite a depressed macroeconomic environment 
    worsened by exchange rate fluctuations in the last quarter.</p>
    <p>In line with its corporate objectives, year 2008 was largely 
    devoted to expanding the Group‚Äôs diversified platform as the 
    company is geared to become the largest integrated energy solution 
    provider in <error corrected="Africa.">Africa .</error> The 
    performance during the year at each of the divisions supports this 
    goal and reinforces its belief in the sustainability of this 
    model.</p>
    <p>Market sources stated that the year will go down as a milestone 
    in Oando‚Äôs upstream diversification programme<punctuation>'</punctuation>It is 
    the year it emerged <error corrected="Nigeria&apos;s">Nigeria 
    &apos;s</error> first indigenous company with producing deepwater 
    assets by the acquisition of stakes in offshore blocks OML 125 
    &amp; 134 and increased its state-of-the-art rigs fleet to three‚Ä? 
    they added.</p>
    <p>Pursuant to this, Oando was able to grow its business 
    considerably within the year in the exploration and production 
    entity where revenue growth was propelled by these substantial 
    investments, and in its traditional marketing business, where 
    increased trade volumes and efficient supply chain management 
    resulted in significant performance improvements. In general, 
    Oando‚Äôs resilient performance in 2008 underlies the Group‚Äôs solid 
    fundamentals.</p>
    <p>Supply and Trading Limited ‚Äì the trading arm of the 
    <error corrected="Group -">Group-</error> took advantage of 
    emerging opportunities along the energy value chain as the largest 
    private importer of petroleum products into 
    <error corrected="Nigeria.">Nigeria .</error></p>
    <p>The Gas division also performed creditably, having completed the 
    Lagos Phase Three Project connecting the Industrial hubs in 
    <error corrected="Lagos.">Lagos .</error> Effort at replicating 
    same feat in the Eastern part of the country is near completion 
    stages.</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
