<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>?</date>
    <place>Lagos</place>
    <author><gender>?</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>?</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>THE XXX UNIVERSITY OF XXX</heading>
    <heading>I The Course Format or Housestyle</heading>
    <heading>1. The Course Guide</heading>
    <p>The Course Guide (CG) should precede all other Units of the 
    Course. The CG gives a general overview of the Course and provides 
    useful information to the student about the structure or format of 
    the course; the credit units attached to the course and how they 
    are to be obtained; assessment (assignments and examinations), and 
    the schedule of activities - important dates.</p>
    <heading>2. The Unit</heading>
    <p>A <boldface>Unit</boldface> is the smallest segment of an 
    instructional material that can stand alone, but which is also 
    linked to other <boldface>Units</boldface> to form a 
    <boldface>Module</boldface>. It should have the following 
    characteristics:</p>
    <p>i) It should engage an average Distance Learner (DL) student for 
    at least three hours of serious work, which is equivalent to one 
    hour of work under the conventional system.</p>
    <p>ii) Depending on the subject matter, <boldface>a full Unit of 
    structured content should cover between 7 and 10 pages (A4, 
    typeset, 10 or 11 points of Times Roman or any appropriate 
    font</boldface>)</p>
    <p>iii) A unit should have:</p>
    <p>a) A table of contents (TOC)</p>
    <p>b) Introduction (1<punctuation>.</punctuation>0)</p>
    <p>c) Objectives (2<punctuation>.</punctuation>0)</p>
    <p>d) Main content, which should have self-assessment exercises 
    (SAEs) and self-assessment questions (SAQs). The introduction may 
    also contain some SAEs and SAQs (3<punctuation>.</punctuation>0) Particular symbols or 
    icons may be adopted to signal theses activities in the text.</p>
    <p>e) Conclusion (4<punctuation>.</punctuation>0)</p>
    <p>f) Summary (5<punctuation>.</punctuation>0)</p>
    <p>g) References and recommended books (6<punctuation>.</punctuation>0)</p>
    <p>iv) At the end of the <boldface>Unit</boldface>, there should be 
    at least 1 standard tutor-marked assignment question (TMAQ), which 
    will form part of the TMAQs al the end of the 
    <boldface>Module</boldface>.</p>
    <p>v) Tables, diagrams, illustrations should be used where 
    appropriate.</p>
    <heading>3. The Module</heading>
    <p>i) Contains up to <boldface>5 Units</boldface>, which make up a 
    <boldface>Module</boldface>. The units, which make up a Module, 
    must be thematically linked to each other.</p>
    <p>ii) At the end there should be TMAQs there will be an assignment 
    file, which will contain all the TMAQs at the end of every Unit.</p>
    <p>iii) There should be references and a list of recommended books 
    at the end of each Module.</p>
    <heading>4. The Course</heading>
    <p>The Course is made up of all the 
    <boldface>Modules</boldface>.</p>
    <p />
  </text>
</annotated>
