<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>lc</transcriber>
    <date>?</date>
    <place>www</place>
    <author><gender>m</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>Igbo</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <p>Hi <indigenous>Mazi</indigenous> <x-anonym-x type="family-name"/>
     ,</p>
    <p>Thanks for your prompt reply. This is unlike those living in the 
    developing countries who do not read their emails often.</p>
    <p><error corrected="let&apos;s">Lets</error> kick off with us. We 
    are still man and wife. The children are yet to come, seven years 
    after.</p>
    <p>l can really see that you have done your 
    <error corrected="homework">home work</error> about the country you 
    will soon <error corrected="sojourn">surjourn</error>, God willing. 
    Your determination too is a challenge. This shows that you will be 
    neck-deep with your academic work once you set your foot in the 
    former communist country. The rush by these people to London over 
    the past months shows their own level of poverty. UK too is happy 
    to see all <error corrected="newcomers">new comers</error> because 
    the income tax and other deductions are so excruciating that people 
    lament. Yet you can&apos;t beat the system or pack your load and 
    leave, because people at home will ask what you have 
    <error corrected="achieved">acheived</error> abroad. lt is in 
    &quot;God&apos;s own country&quot; where l visited last year that 
    has what it takes to make life comfortable, in terms of cost of 
    living.</p>
    <p>How far with the Ph<punctuation>.</punctuation>D<error corrected="."/> programme l 
    thought you have been pursuing at UNI <x-anonym-x type="location"/> 
    ? Are you abandoning it? l would have thought that you would 
    complete that one first before making this other move so that you 
    will be a hot cake with choices to make on completion. Ethiopia is 
    today scrambling for Nigerian professors in various fields.</p>
    <p>l shall &quot;see&quot; you some other time. Duty calls now.</p>
    <p>Regards to <x-anonym-x/> and the children.</p>
    <p>Cheers</p>
    <p>Hi <indigenous>Mazi</indigenous> <x-anonym-x type="first-name"/> 
    ,</p>
    <p>How are you today, your family, church and fellowship?</p>
    <p>You may have read my last mails. The mails may not have been too 
    palatable l guess. l was just preparing you with some reality of 
    what you are likely to encounter soon. l want to add this other 
    dimension - ACCOMMODATION. You may need to find out if the fee 
    quoted for you includes accommodation. Over here in London the rent 
    is between £70-£100 a week. Multiply that by four to have the 
    monthly rent in central London. At the periphery it is cheaper. 
    This is not to say that the money comes that easy. The fact is that 
    no one will squat another without the landlord adding to the rent. 
    No church building takes in anyone so it is common to see people 
    sleeping on the street even in Winter. l do not know what the rent 
    is like in Poland. So it might be nice to sort this area out too to 
    be sure.</p>
    <p>lf l have tried compounding issues for you please pardon me, l 
    consider it necessary to let you know some of these things. God 
    bless you real good. Please don&apos;t fail to reply.</p>
    <p>Cheers</p>
    <p><indigenous>Mazi</indigenous> <x-anonym-x type="first-name"/> 
    ,</p>
    <p>lt is nice coming your way after some delays on my part since 
    <x-anonym-x type="first-name"/> spoke me. l was expecting to 
    receive your mailing address from the pastor but what l got was 
    your phone number. On the long run l have come to realise that your 
    mail which he once copied me carries your address. Phone call will 
    not undo what all these years of separation has caused especially 
    when the high cost of phoning Africa is put into view. lf it were 
    US you are calling from London you can speak for hours yet you 
    haven&apos;t spent too much.</p>
    <p>How is your family doing? Will l be able to recognise 
    <x-anonym-x type="first-name"/> if l see her? Remember l still have 
    her picture which you folks gave to me the last time l visited your 
    house over seven years ago.</p>
    <p><x-anonym-x type="first-name"/> told me of your 
    <error corrected="interest">intrerest</error> to study in 
    Poland,which to me is a welcome idea, all things being equal. What 
    l do not know now is the level your communication has gone as at 
    today. He said he needed to write you a covering letter on 
    <error corrected="which">whhich</error> <error corrected="strength">
    strenght</error> they would give you visa. l need to know what l 
    can do as contribution to this quest of yours <error corrected="."/>
    </p>
    <p>Write soon so that we can start talking.</p>
    <p>Greet <x-anonym-x type="first-name"/> and the 
    <error corrected="children">Childern</error> for us.</p>
    <p>Remain blessed.</p>
    <p><indigenous>Mazi</indigenous> <x-anonym-x type="first-name"/> 
    ,</p>
    <p>Welcome to <other-language language="igbo">obodo ndi 
    ocha</other-language>. l have really been postponing welcoming you 
    online with the view of phoning you instead. l have now been 
    incapacitated more because l do no want to call you when you are in 
    class, or have you not started anything classroom? At the time l 
    would consider appropriate to call l would be sleeping to prepare 
    for my night job.</p>
    <p>How have you been faring? There is no doubts that you have 
    started finding your feet. l will call within the week, maybe on 
    <coll for="Saturday">Sat</coll>. My cell phone no 
    <error corrected="."/> is <x-anonym-x/>. l 
    <error corrected="can&apos;t">cant</error> give you the house no 
    <error corrected="."/> cause we are moving home next week, God 
    willing.</p>
    <p>Remain blessed.</p>
    <p><indigenous>Mazi</indigenous> <x-anonym-x type="first-name"/> 
    ,</p>
    <p>This is a happy news. Congratulations!</p>
    <p>lt is not so nice that you are coming when the winters are 
    setting in though. Not to worry. You shall overcome, but get 
    yourself some winter jacket because you are most likely to start 
    shivering right at the airport. l would have come looking for you 
    at the airport with a jacket were it the UK you are headed.</p>
    <p>Hear more of you later. ln any case our house number is 
    <x-anonym-x/> while my mobile is <x-anonym-x/>.</p>
    <p>Bless you.</p>
    <p>Hi <indigenous>Mazi</indigenous> <x-anonym-x type="first-name"/> 
    ,</p>
    <p>How is the going? And how are your 
    <indigenous>pikins</indigenous> and their mum doing?</p>
    <p>l am writing to find out if the <indigenous>oyibo</indigenous> 
    have finally answered your application or if they have started some 
    delay tactics as they often do.</p>
    <p>Please <error corrected="let&apos;s">lets</error> hear of the 
    developments.</p>
    <p>Have a nice day and may the Good Lord be merciful to you.</p>
    <p>Cheers</p>
    <p>Hi <indigenous>Mazi</indigenous> <x-anonym-x type="first-name"/> 
    ,</p>
    <p>Merry Christmas and a prosperous new year mazi 
    <x-anonym-x type="first-name"/> . How are you doing?</p>
    <p>Could you tell me why l cannot reach you with the phone number 
    you supplied me? l have added 00 to <x-anonym-x/> using eurocity 
    card meant for W<punctuation>.</punctuation>Europe, USA and Canada but was told that l 
    was not allowed to reach this destination (which cannot be true 
    because a colleague reaches his Polish family with it).</p>
    <p>l&apos;m waiting to hear from you soonest.</p>
    <p>Cheers</p>
    <p><indigenous>Mazi</indigenous> <x-anonym-x type="first-name"/> 
    ,</p>
    <p>How are you today? So sorry we couldn&apos;t hear each other 
    very well a couple of days ago via <x-anonym-x type="family-name"/> 
    &apos;s connection. lt&apos;s really been quite a while since we 
    spoke last. One Sunday that l called you the line was so faint that 
    you couldn&apos;t hear me before it went dead.</p>
    <p>Congratulations for the success of your stay papers in 
    <x-anonym-x type="location"/> . Bro<error corrected="."/> 
    <x-anonym-x type="family-name"/> told me about it and l rejoice 
    with you.</p>
    <p>l guess that it has not been very easy with you even though l do 
    not know the state of things at the moment. <x-anonym-x/> told me 
    you were making inquiries about vacation jobs in 
    <x-anonym-x type="location"/> . l do not know much about it. lf you 
    have any hint of anybody who has crossed over for much a programme 
    do not fail to let me know so that l can follow up to 
    <error corrected="know">konw</error> the steps they took. The one 
    that l am sure about are international students studying in the UK. 
    They have the provision to work, even though they have a set number 
    of hours per week which they mustn&apos;t exceed.</p>
    <p>Please do me a piece soonest.</p>
    <p>Remain blessed and cheers.</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
