<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ew</transcriber>
    <date>2008-08-03</date>
    <place>TODO</place>
    <author><gender>f</gender><age>47</age><ethnic-group>Esan</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <p>Hello,</p>
    <p>I checked and compared <coll for="professor">Prof</coll>&apos;s 
    numbers. I&apos;m on track, I think. Later then. Bye.</p>
    <p><x-anonym-x type="first-name"/><punctuation>.</punctuation></p>
    <p>Hello <x-anonym-x type="first-name"/>,</p>
    <p>I say<punctuation>'</punctuation>AMEN<punctuation>'</punctuation> to your prayer. I&apos;m 
    sorry for keeping you awake, but I had no choice. I see my threat 
    worked wonders. Thanks, dear for replying me pronto. I knew I could 
    count on you. I look forward to reading from you on the other 
    issues raised.</p>
    <p>Meanwhile, I just received the original of my E-ticket. I liked 
    the bit in your mail about being<punctuation>'</punctuation>better late than 
    never, for this kind of... opportunity<punctuation>'</punctuation> That&apos;s a 
    lot of challenge, I must say. But, thank you.I need the push. 
    Please keep in touch. I&apos;ll pray for strength, and do my 
    utmost.</p>
    <p>Regards,</p>
    <p><x-anonym-x type="first-name"/><punctuation>.</punctuation></p>
    <p>Hello <x-anonym-x type="first-name"/>,</p>
    <p>I forgive you for not replying my last mail, but you must reply 
    this, failing which I&apos;ll have no choice but to withdraw my 
    last promise.</p>
    <p>A lot has happened concerning the workshop next month, but I 
    can&apos;t say I&apos;m on track yet. What worries me most is the 
    visa. I&apos;ve applied and gotten an appointment date - 12th - , 
    but it&apos;s so close to <error corrected="departure">
    depature</error> -14th - that I&apos;m worried. I&apos;ve 
    <error corrected="bared">barred</error> my mind to 
    <coll for="professor">Prof</coll> <x-anonym-x type="family-name"/>. 
    They asked for advice and I gave them yours and added 
    <error corrected="names">name&apos;s</error>, to contact the 
    <error corrected="embassy">embassey</error> and their servants in 
    Nigeria, to ensure it is not delayed. They did, but I don&apos;t 
    think they&apos;re getting any positive responses. Anyway, 
    I&apos;ve asked them to keep trying. Meanwhile, I&apos;m carrying 
    on with my preparations, believing that I&apos;ll be helped.</p>
    <p><coll for="professor">Prof</coll> 
    <x-anonym-x type="family-name"/> has asked for data on Nigerian 
    English. I&apos;m sure you&apos;re familiar with the request. 
    Please, give me hints on how to go about this and what to 
    <error corrected="gather">garther</error>.</p>
    <p>I&apos;ve also been sent maps and directions on how to get to 
    various locations in <x-anonym-x type="location"/>. No human 
    guides? I sincerely hope I won&apos;t get missing in transit 
    <coll for="[clitic] roughly equivalent to &apos;you know&apos;, &apos;really&apos; etc">
    o</coll>. There are other things <error corrected="I would">
    I&apos;ld</error> like <error corrected="to">yo</error> 
    <error corrected="discuss">discus</error> and clarify with you, as 
    soon as I arrive ( by HIS GRACE ), and can contact you. I&apos;ve 
    been sent a <error corrected="provisional">provissional</error> 
    timetable too. Meanwhile, if there are any other things I ought to 
    know, don&apos;t fail to <error corrected="acquaint">
    aquaint</error> me please.</p>
    <p>Hope I have your promise to reply this mail, no joking.</p>
    <p>Regards,</p>
    <p><x-anonym-x type="first-name"/><punctuation>.</punctuation></p>
    <p><x-anonym-x type="first-name"/>,</p>
    <p>I surely am willing to award you that Ph<punctuation>.</punctuation>D now, for 
    succeeding in cracking my ribs with laughter, all through your 
    mail, and all the way from Poland too. It&apos;s no mean feat, I 
    assure you. When you return, I&apos;ll vote that you be allowed to 
    open an autonomous department of humour.</p>
    <p>So, how are you? I&apos;m just about applying for my visa, now 
    that the passport is ready. Thanks for all your tips, and the 
    encouragement about U<punctuation>.</punctuation>I. I&apos;ll visit them in the coming 
    week to put a few things in place before my journey.</p>
    <p>The new H<punctuation>.</punctuation>O D is Dr<punctuation>.</punctuation> B<punctuation>.</punctuation>A<punctuation>.</punctuation> 
    <x-anonym-x type="family-name"/>. I just received a copy of my e - 
    ticket via email. I&apos;m told the original copy has been sent 
    today by express. Just pray that things work out for me. I&apos;ll 
    keep in touch, while looking forward to seeing you. Bye.</p>
    <p>Regards,</p>
    <p><x-anonym-x type="first-name"/>.</p>
    <p>Hello <x-anonym-x type="first-name"/>,</p>
    <p>I just read your mail. Did you write it in Nigerian or Esan or 
    Igbo English? I need to be sure, to enable me respond fully.</p>
    <p>Thanks for your extra tips. As my supervisor suddenly decided to 
    travel out<punctuation>'</punctuation>indefinitely<punctuation>'</punctuation>, I don&apos;t 
    know what to say about <x-anonym-x type="location"/>. Meanwhile 
    <error superfluous="yes">&apos;</error> I&apos;m eager to be in 
    <x-anonym-x type="location"/> next month, and look forward to 
    seeing you.I&apos;m praying and trying to get my papers. The CorPus 
    team are willing to ease my troubles. We&apos;ll talk in Germany. 
    Greetings from <x-anonym-x type="family-name"/>. Bye.</p>
    <p>Sincerely,</p>
    <p><x-anonym-x type="first-name"/><punctuation>.</punctuation></p>
    <p>Hello,</p>
    <p>My last mail came to you before I could even complete it. I 
    can&apos;t explain it. Anyway, here is Mrs 
    <x-anonym-x type="family-name"/>&apos;s address, as well as 
    Gladys&apos;.</p>
    <p>1 <x-anonym-x type="e-mail"/></p>
    <p>2<punctuation>.</punctuation> <x-anonym-x type="e-mail"/></p>
    <p>All the best always.</p>
    <p>Sincerely,</p>
    <p><x-anonym-x type="first-name"/><punctuation>.</punctuation></p>
  </text>
</annotated>
