<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2009</date>
    <place>yahoo.com</place>
    <author><gender>f</gender><age>48</age><ethnic-group>Esan</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <p>Hello &lt;<x-anonym-x type="first-name"/>&gt;</p>
    <p>I read your last mail the third time running, today... you know 
    I find it more cumbersome to understand messages in the language in 
    which you wrote that mail. I know I&apos;ve just given you 
    something to talk about, so fire on.</p>
    <p>Perhaps I&apos;ve lost my sense of speech <coll for="because">
    cos</coll> of the on going strike. Nothing to talk about, I 
    suppose. So how many millions were you paid back home. I finally 
    got reimbursed by <x-anonym-x type="organisation"/>. So, hope your 
    <error corrected="projects">projeccts</error> are going on 
    smoothly. Strike is still on. Talk some more later, if I do not 
    lose my sense of speech completely before I read from you again. 
    All the best always.</p>
    <p>Regards,</p>
    <p><x-anonym-x type="first-name"/></p>
    <p>Dear Mr<punctuation>.</punctuation> <x-anonym-x type="family-name"/>,</p>
    <p>You have my permission to make use of 
    <error corrected="excerpts">exerpts</error> from my use of 
    <error corrected="English">Engllish</error> as corpus for your work 
    on Nigerian English.</p>
    <p>Sincerely,</p>
    <p>Mrs &lt;<x-anonym-x type="first-name"/>&gt;&lt; 
    <x-anonym-x type="family-name"/>&gt;.</p>
    <p>Hello Sir,</p>
    <p>I hope you&apos;re fine and catching up with preparations for 
    your exams. I hope the cold is not unbearable.</p>
    <p>I got invited for that summer programme in 
    <error corrected="London">Lodon</error> <error corrected=", ">
    ,</error>but got no scholarship. I can&apos;t fund it.</p>
    <p>By the way<error corrected=", ">,</error>preparations are being 
    made to pay the long awaited monetisation arears. Since it&apos;s 
    by e-payment<error corrected=", ">,</error>I suppose your account 
    will be credited<error corrected=". ">.</error>I&apos;m writing 
    from <x-anonym-x type="location"/>. Nothing to scream about yet 
    <error corrected=". ">.</error>I&apos;ll keep you posted 
    <error corrected=". ">.</error>Cheers.</p>
    <p>Sincerely,</p>
    <p><x-anonym-x type="first-name"/></p>
    <p>Hello Sir,</p>
    <p>I only just succeeded in using the link you sent me about the 3L 
    Summer school billed for London. I&apos;ve also sent a reference 
    form to your box for filling and sending.</p>
    <p><error corrected="tomorrow">Tommorow</error>, August 15th is 
    deadline. <coll for="Please">Pls</coll>, oblige me. I&apos;ll reach 
    you. Have you applied. Thanks a lot for the links.</p>
    <p>Regards,</p>
    <p><x-anonym-x type="first-name"/></p>
    <p>Hello Sir,</p>
    <p>Compliments of the season to you <error corrected=". ">
    .</error>How are you keeping back in <x-anonym-x type="location"/>? 
    Will your family have the <error corrected="privilege">
    priviledge</error> of your <error corrected="presence">
    presesnce</error> this yuletide? Hope all is well with you.</p>
    <p><error corrected=" Ibadan">I badan</error> is yet to come to 
    terms with the fact that I&apos;ve come of age. As for me I 
    won&apos;t get tired of waiting for them, <coll for="because">
    cos</coll> I know it&apos;s a reality they&apos;ll have to face, 
    sooner than they think. So I&apos;m waiting.</p>
    <p>Pity, I couldn&apos;t make CLAN this time. I look forward to the 
    next meet<error corrected=". ">.</error>
    <x-anonym-x type="organisation"/> and <x-anonym-x type="location"/> 
    are just as usual. All are hoping to survive. Wish you the best 
    alaways. Cheers.</p>
    <p>Regards,</p>
    <p><x-anonym-x type="first-name"/></p>
    <p>Hello Sir,</p>
    <p><error corrected="Good morning">Goodmorning</error> Nigerian 
    time. Sorry it&apos;s been so busy, I couldn&apos;t write a reply 
    to your mail before now. Even this is not much of a reply as I 
    won&apos;t be able to respond to all the issues raised.</p>
    <p>Monetisation is on hold. No payments have been made yet...trust 
    FGN. First semester exams are on, ASSU is threatening a major 
    strike as from the 22nd June, - nothing to do with monetisation - 
    so the goal is to conclude exams before then.</p>
    <p>I suppose your exams are well under way, so I won&apos;t trouble 
    your noble head. I&apos;ll be in touch. All the best and CHEERS.</p>
    <p>Sincerely<error corrected=",">&apos;</error></p>
    <p><x-anonym-x type="first-name"/></p>
    <p>Dear Sir,</p>
    <p>I thank you for your mails, and for ever again keeping me 
    abreast of happenings in Linguistics. Concerning the workshop on 
    phonology you mentioned, I doubt if I want to venture out again 
    <error corrected="until">untill</error> I see the U<punctuation>.</punctuation>I<punctuation>.</punctuation> project to a logical conclusion. ASSU is right now rounding off 
    a warning strike, during which time my daughter was delivered of a 
    baby girl - her first child, my first grandchild, and my 
    mother&apos;s first great grandchild. See, one&apos;s not getting 
    any younger.</p>
    <p>I also got an invitation from Prof<punctuation>.</punctuation> &lt; 
    <x-anonym-x type="family-name"/>&gt; to help source young Ph<punctuation>.</punctuation>D students willing to spend one year in Germany. I&apos;ll give 
    &lt; <x-anonym-x type="first-name"/>&gt; that information. 
    <other-language language="nigerian-pidgin">So I just 
    dey</other-language>. I&apos;m writing you from The Lagos State 
    University Teaching Hospital, where my daughter had her baby. 
    I&apos;m due back in <x-anonym-x type="location"/> early next week, 
    when the strike will end and preparations for exams commence. 
    Meanwhile, did I tell you I&apos;m the new exams officer - your 
    prayers came to pass, didn&apos;t they. I told you a lot was 
    happening, and that&apos;s some of it. We&apos;re struggling to 
    clear up a lot of mess.</p>
    <p>So long Sir. I&apos;ll keep in touch. Meanwhile, listen to the 
    advice of the latest grandma on the Black continent, and remain 
    steadfast. I&apos;ll be in touch.</p>
    <p>Sincerely,</p>
    <p>&lt;<x-anonym-x type="family-name"/>&gt;,</p>
    <p>Dear <x-anonym-x type="first-name"/>,</p>
    <p>I read your reply to my last mail. The fact about your salary 
    was news to me. I&apos;m sorry. I should however think that 
    you&apos;ll benefit from the package I talked about as it&apos;s a 
    back log thing. I&apos;ll make enquiries along the lines you have 
    stated and feed you back.</p>
    <p>Meanwhile, remain as strong, steadfast and undaunted as I know 
    you to be. I&apos;m certain you&apos;ll pull through. Things are 
    happening back here in Nigeria, <x-anonym-x type="location"/> and 
    the department. I&apos;ll let you on as they unfold. I&apos;m 
    watching Ibadan closely. Dr<punctuation>.</punctuation> &lt;
    <x-anonym-x type="family-name"/>&gt; sends warm greetings. 
    <x-anonym-x type="organisation"/> still has not and did not 
    reimburse me for all kinds of administrative excuses. I&apos;ll 
    keep in touch<error corrected=". ">.</error>Cheers.</p>
    <p>Sincerely,</p>
    <p><x-anonym-x type="first-name"/></p>
    <p>Dear <x-anonym-x type="first-name"/>,</p>
    <p>How are you? I hope am allowed to say, &quot; <quote>long time 
    no hear</quote> .&quot; I really hope you&apos;re fine, body and 
    soul. I found some time to take a breath and thought I could get in 
    touch with you. How&apos;s <x-anonym-x type="location"/> treating 
    you, and how&apos;re you treating <x-anonym-x type="location"/>. I 
    really wish to read from you.</p>
    <p>There&apos;s an issue I&apos;ve avoided raising with you since 
    our return from <x-anonym-x type="location"/>, which I now feel 
    urged to mention. Soon after return from 
    <x-anonym-x type="organisation"/>, I received a mail to the effect 
    that I had reimbursement to collect. I was requested to send 
    originals of my receipts and account number and other information. 
    All this took about two to three months. The mails were 
    <error corrected="signed">singned</error> by one &lt; 
    <x-anonym-x type="first-name"/>&gt;. The receipt of my documents 
    was acknowledged, and I was <error corrected="assured">
    assurred</error> that I would receive <error corrected="reimbursed">
    re-embursed</error> in the shortest time possible.</p>
    <p>Till date, I&apos;ve not received any further communication on 
    the matter. I didn&apos;t think it proper to send a reminder. But I 
    wondered whether you were communicated as well, and thought I could 
    ask you. I would like to know your thoughts on the matter, and if 
    there&apos;s anything I should know, I trust you&apos;ld inform 
    me.</p>
    <p>I believe you get word regularly from your family. I wish you 
    strength as you rough it out over there, and look forward to seeing 
    you again. &lt;<x-anonym-x type="family-name"/>&gt; and I truly 
    miss your presence. Please, be strong........for everyone and for 
    the good. Bye.</p>
    <p><error corrected="Sincerely">Sicerely</error> yours.</p>
    <p><x-anonym-x type="first-name"/></p>
  </text>
</annotated>
