<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>TODO</date>
    <place>web</place>
    <author><gender>m</gender><age>40</age><ethnic-group>Yoruba</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <p>Dear Sir,</p>
    <p>Good day to you and the family. It was a very interesting moment 
    getting to know you and living with you in 
    <x-anonym-x type="location"/>. I strongly feel that 
    <error corrected="I">i</error> ought to have known you much earlier 
    than now, but of course our two days interractions seemed to have 
    bridged the gaps (though not enough) of our imagined relationship 
    that should have being in the longer time. I hope that as we keep 
    to the established contact, we will in the future overcome the 
    remaining gaps.</p>
    <p>I had a nice trip back to <x-anonym-x type="location"/> and 
    delivered your felicitation to Dr<punctuation>.</punctuation> 
    <x-anonym-x type="family-name"/>. He is highly happy that we met. I 
    will compile the list of the fellowships <error corrected="I">
    i</error> have and send it to you before the week runs out.</p>
    <p>Kindly remain blessed and have my best regards for every member 
    of your family.</p>
    <p>Thanks. <x-anonym-x type="first-name"/></p>
    <p>Dear Dr<punctuation>.</punctuation> <x-anonym-x type="family-name"/>,</p>
    <p>Thank you for your reply. Good to know that your presentation 
    went well, and that you got back to <x-anonym-x type="location"/> 
    two hours earlier than scheduled. Thanks too for asking after my 
    family. Everybody is fine, and yes, they were all happy to see me. 
    I tried the landline you indicated in your mail just now. The 
    answer I received was to the effect that the number does not exist. 
    Could there have been an error somewhere?</p>
    <p>My own number (home) is <x-anonym-x /></p>
    <p>Let&apos;s keep in contact.</p>
    <p>Best wishes,</p>
    <p><x-anonym-x type="first-name"/></p>
  </text>
</annotated>
