<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2005-03-23</date>
    <place>internet</place>
    <author><gender>m</gender><age>28</age><ethnic-group>Ukwuani</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <p>Hello Sis <x-anonym-x type="first-name"/>,  </p>
    <p>I&apos;m very glad to read your email this Wednesday morning 
    (1.03 am). I&apos;m sorry that I don&apos;t check the hotmail very 
    often but you can always get me on yahoo. Glad to hear that you are 
    doing well spiritually and that you passed your exams. That you 
    even scored the highest in my subject<error superfluous="yes"> 
    </error>: English! Glory be to God. It is a sign of greater heights 
    in <error corrected="Jesus&apos;">Jesus</error> name.  </p>
    <p> How are your parents, brothers and sisters? How is 
    <x-anonym-x type="first-name"/>? How is Bro 
    <x-anonym-x type="first-name"/>? Is Bro 
    <x-anonym-x type="first-name"/> still in your house? Please tell me 
    about everybody in your reply.  </p>
    <p> I am sorry that I couldn&apos;t contact you ever since I left 
    <x-anonym-x type="location"/>. I hope you forgive me? I really 
    tried to send emails to your former address but there was no reply. 
    Well, that is all now story because I now have your email address. 
    Do you have a phone number that I can reach you on?  </p>
    <p> Have you registered for JAMB? What course are you planning to 
    study and how are you getting along? What are you doing at the 
    moment? Has <x-anonym-x type="first-name"/> gained admission?  </p>
    <p> I thank Almighty God for bringing me to 
    <x-anonym-x type="location"/> for my studies. I have wonderful 
    brethren who we fellowship together. In fact, we are having the 
    Easter retreat in the church headquarters here this weekend.  </p>
    <p> You asked about daddy&apos;s ministry in your mail. By the 
    grace of God the ministry is fine and everybody is fine in 
    <x-anonym-x type="location"/>.  </p>
    <p> I know that victory is certain for you in Jesus name because 
    you are God&apos;s beloved. It is well with you.  </p>
    <p> I eagerly look forward to hearing from you. I wish you the best 
    of Easter blessings. Hope you are attending the retreat?  </p>
    <p> Remain blessed. Please reply soonest.  </p>
    <p> Bro<punctuation>.</punctuation> <x-anonym-x type="first-name"/> 
    </p>
    <p />
  </text>
</annotated>
