<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2009-07-12</date>
    <place>www.thenationonlineng.net/web/</place>
    <author><gender>m</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>Yoruba</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>These troublesome 76 oil wells</heading>
    <p>A Pandora box was opened in August last year when the Revenue 
    Mobilisation, Allocation and Fiscal Commission (RMAFC) went for a 
    retreat in Kano and <punctuation>‘</punctuation>resolved<punctuation>’</punctuation> the 
    maritime boundary issue between Akwa Ibom and Cross River States. 
    At the end of the meeting, the disputed maritime territory was 
    resolved in favour of Akwa Ibom State. Consequently, 76 oil wells 
    hitherto belonging to Cross River State were ceded to Akwa Ibom, 
    leaving the former virtually without oil well, the implication of 
    which is that Cross River was struck off the list of the 
    prestigious club of oil producing states.</p>
    <p>One might ask: what is the big deal about being an oil producing 
    state, what about other states that are not producing oil? The 
    problem is that first, non oil producing states do not have 
    expectation of derivation income from the Federation Account and so 
    do not plan big. Secondly, they are not used to large income and so 
    are never big spenders. States like Delta, Rivers, Bayelsa, Akwa 
    Ibom and Cross River are big earners and big spenders. By virtue of 
    their income, they have acquired a large appetite and capacity for 
    spending. This is why the delisting of Cross River from the league 
    of oil producing states is bound to lead to serious financial, 
    social and security crisis in the state. The corollary to this is 
    the way Benin Republic and Niger are not likely to be distressed 
    over falling oil prices since they are not oil exporters.</p>
    <p>For a state collecting N5 billion, N6 billion or N8 billion from 
    the Federation Account in the past, it would have employed workers 
    commensurate with its income. It also would have embarked on 
    projects along this line. It is not unlikely too that it had 
    enlisted militants and idle local chiefs on its payroll. The 
    cessation of funds and reduction of income to a paltry N1 billion 
    meant that contractors would no longer be paid, workers would have 
    to be retrenched, and even the lifeline to the militants cut off. 
    It is a recipe for economic and social chaos.</p>
    <p>All these happened as fallout of the ceding of Bakassi to 
    Cameroon. Nearly all the oil wells belonging to the two states are 
    actually offshore, as part of Nigerian territorial waters. It is 
    interesting to note that Akwa Ibom in particular has no onshore oil 
    wells.</p>
    <p>The two states, indeed the entire Niger Delta States, were 
    thrown into apprehension when late Chief Bola Ige as the then 
    Attorney General and Minister of Justice, went to the Supreme Court 
    to affirm the Federal Government’s exclusive right to the offshore 
    oil wells. The court concurred by making the low watermark to be 
    the seaward boundary of the states, cutting the two states off from 
    derivation. But wisdom prevailed and a political solution was found 
    which extended the seaward boundary by 200 metres isobath from the 
    low watermark of the littoral states and practically dumped the 
    Supreme Court’s judgement. This is why Akwa Ibom gets as much as 
    N16 billion from the Federation Account.</p>
    <p>Cross River’s problem is that the ceding of Bakassi, which was 
    part of her territory, to Cameroon, redrew the map of the two 
    states. Since her offshore oil extends from Bakassi, the loss of 
    that territory should imply the loss of the offshore oil wells. But 
    there is a cruel twist of geography here. What the ICJ gave 
    Cameroon was the land and not the oil wells which still belong to 
    Nigeria. However, with Bakassi out of Cross River, the oil wells 
    now abut Akwa Ibom and this is what RMAFC quickly adjusted to and 
    gave the oil wells to the <error corrected="latter">
    later</error>.</p>
    <p>Nevertheless, the matter is not that straightforward. Redrawing 
    maritime boundary is problematic and when it is within an economic 
    zone, it is a sure conflict generator. That is why we are where we 
    are at the moment. Cross River, the loser in this maritime 
    mathematics, had her revenue reduced to less that N1 billion and 
    has gone to court. It has also appealed to the Presidency.</p>
    <p>When this kind of conflict arises, the parties had the options 
    of looking at the matter strictly from a technical point. It could 
    also take the benefit of history or adopt a political solution. The 
    technical option is the reliance on equidistance and strict 
    cartography by drawing a straight line between two points. This 
    option will appear superfluous at the moment since the conflict 
    emerged from this cartography. The historical option can be of 
    help. One, the oil wells have always belonged to Cross Rivers. 
    Indeed, they were the subject of boundary dispute between the two 
    states before the Bakassi imbroglio. When the dispute could not be 
    settled through technicalities, the National Boundaries Commission 
    (NBC) had to rely on history titles and awarded 76 oil wells, out 
    of the disputed 80, to Cross River. As recommended by ONCLOS 82, 
    there should be recourse to equidistance method in resolving 
    maritime boundary dispute only when there is no bilateral 
    agreement, historical titles and special circumstances.</p>
    <p>One implication of relying on technicality is that RMAFC would 
    have redrawn the boundary between Cross River and Akwa Ibom. This 
    would appear illegal since it will take an act of the National 
    Assembly to do so.</p>
    <p>I must confess that there is no easy solution. From the way the 
    issue is engaged, one state’s gain would be another’s loss. 
    Technicality gives it to Akwa Ibom while historical title says the 
    oil wells belong to Cross River. There must be a third way out 
    which is the political solution. In the balance of probabilities, 
    even when the oil wells are returned to Cross Rivers, Akwa Ibom 
    will still be in a good stead. Although it is not before us what a 
    state earns, ceding the oil wells to Cross River will not 
    impoverish Akwa Ibom.</p>
    <p>I will suggest that the matter be settled out of court and a 
    middle way be found such that most, if not all, the oil wells are 
    returned to Cross River State. It is in the spirit of good 
    neighbourliness. The Presidency should broker this deal. RMAFC 
    should also learn to thread carefully in the future and consider 
    the political and economic circumstances before taking a 
    precipitate action.</p>
    <p>The dispute over the oil wells is an opportunity for all the oil 
    producing states, including Cross River, to factor in the finite 
    nature of a God-given resource and widen the base of their economy. 
    Anything can happen tomorrow that will leave you high and dry. This 
    lesson should be learnt by Nigeria, more than anyone.</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
