<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2009-06-17</date>
    <place>http://thenationonlineng.net/web</place>
    <author><gender>m</gender><age>52</age><ethnic-group>?</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>The <punctuation>‚Äò</punctuation>confessions<punctuation>‚Äô</punctuation> of 
    Bafyau</heading>
    <p>Paschal Bafyau is a known name in Nigeria. But I am not aware if 
    there is any other worthwhile credit to his name other than that he 
    was a one-time president of the Nigeria Labour Congress. He later 
    made incursions into politics and failed woefully.</p>
    <p>After this disastrous adventure in the late 1980s and early 
    1990s, Bafyau had recoiled into his shell, perhaps to lick his 
    wounds. His last political showing was his 
    <error corrected="much-touted">much- touted</error> ambition to 
    become the Vice President of Nigeria on the banner of the Social 
    Democratic Party (SDP) in the 1993 presidential election. That 
    election featured Moshood Kashimawo Olawale Abiola as the 
    standard-bearer of the SDP.</p>
    <p>But by a stroke of ill-luck or other reason, the candidacy of 
    Bafyau was jettisoned at the last minute to pave the way for the 
    emergence of a better positioned Babagana Kingibe. Before his 
    emergence, Kingibe had given a good account of himself as a top 
    civil servant, a highly valued technocrat and an accomplished 
    diplomat. His ability to speak several foreign languages is 
    attributed to the dexterity and intellectual gift with which God 
    has endowed him.</p>
    <p>In fact, many people who were hitherto not too comfortable with 
    an Abiola-Bafyau ticket in the first instance must have heaved a 
    sigh of relief. The argument was that Bafyau had hobnobbed too 
    dangerously with the military oligarchy that was in power at that 
    time and it might not be wise to entrust him with such a sensitive 
    position. He was also reputed to be very friendly with green 
    bottles. So, for someone who is said to be perpetually foggy 
    upstairs, it would have been unhealthy to catapult him to the 
    pinnacle of power.</p>
    <p>Now, 16 years on, Bafyau, who might have secretly been bearing 
    some grudge against Abiola since he was unceremoniously shoved 
    aside, has at last opened up. Last week, Bafyau chose an auspicious 
    occasion to empty his venom before an unwilling audience. The 
    setting was a lecture organised to mark the 16th anniversary of the 
    June 12 election organised by the Ekiti State chapter of the 
    Peoples Democratic Party (PDP) in Ado-Ekiti last Friday.</p>
    <p>Bafyau, who was the guest lecturer at the occasion, said that 
    the decision by Abiola, the winner of the June 12, 1993 
    presidential election, to drop him as his running mate was what 
    cost Abiola<error>,</error> the annulment of that election. He said 
    his (Abiola‚Äôs) preference for Kingibe was a betrayal of trust and 
    that the development was the genesis of the annulment of the 
    election. Bafyau also claimed that Abiola had breached a purported 
    agreement reached with the then military president, General Ibrahim 
    Babangida (retd), by ditching him as his (Abiola‚Äôs) running 
    mate.</p>
    <p>According to Bafyau, ‚ÄúAbiola promised to announce me as his 
    running mate on May 1, but he announced Kingibe instead. That 
    marked the beginning of the problem of June 12 election.‚Ä? 
    Furthermore, Bafyau stated that ‚ÄúMKO had a secret deal with the 
    military and they gave him the condition to make me his running 
    mate, but he reneged on the agreement. At that point, the military 
    no longer trusted him.‚Ä? As if to further drive home his point, he 
    said: ‚ÄúThe military saw him as somebody who could not be trusted. 
    Babangida was not happy with him and he no longer wanted to see 
    him. They said he was not a man of his words.‚Ä?</p>
    <p>When Bafyau was done with his disclosure, he rubbed in some 
    soothing balm for Abiola‚Äôs followers who would have been hurt to 
    the marrow by his grandiloquent utterances. He described ‚ÄúAbiola as 
    the martyr of democracy who laid his life for the democracy the 
    country is enjoying today‚Ä?.</p>
    <p>Beyond political rascality and cantankerous posture, I 
    personally do not see anything that qualifies Bafyau to deliver 
    such a lecture on such an important occasion. But I see this 
    development as some of the truths that are yet to be unearthed on 
    why that election which was globally adjudged to be the freest and 
    fairest in Nigeria was annulled.</p>
    <p>In the first instance, if not for the kind of <punctuation>‚Äò</punctuation>politics of the stomach<punctuation>‚Äô</punctuation> that we play in this part 
    of the world, how would a Bafyau have been considered the number 
    two man in Nigeria? I do not want to sound too personal, but the 
    truth is that I would not have been proud to point to a person as 
    drab as Bafyau as my Vice President. Not at all.</p>
    <p>That is why in the National Think-Tank, of which I am a founding 
    member, we have always hammered on the type of characters we parade 
    as leaders in this country. Most of the people who emerge as 
    leaders in Nigeria do so because of the enormous wealth at their 
    disposal or on the crest of the powerful, dubious and faceless 
    people behind them. The unfortunate thing is that, today, we have 
    drug pushers, advance fee fraudsters and all manners of individuals 
    with despicable attitudes and behaviour parading themselves as 
    elected or appointed officials in the corridors of power. They are 
    everywhere.</p>
    <p>Every day you open newspapers, you are greeted by a litany of 
    fraudulent activities perpetrated by top government officials, I 
    mean officials in high places who should have showed good examples 
    by their conduct. Even at that, the system is so rotten and maggoty 
    that most, if not all, these miscreants masquerading as government 
    officials usually escape the wrath of the law even when they are 
    reined in. And the looting and brigandage continue on a daily basis 
    with such reckless abandon.</p>
    <p>What Bafyau has simply told Nigerians is that he was one of the 
    people who worked tirelessly to truncate Abiola‚Äôs victory in 1993. 
    Except that he wants us to believe that when he was shoved out of 
    the race, he simply went back home to his wife to drink 
    <indigenous>fura</indigenous>. But that would have been an 
    impossible option for someone who could nurse such a grudge for 16 
    years. He must have adopted a stance akin to a Yoruba proverb which 
    says ‚Äú<indigenous>kaka ki eku ma je sese, a fi se awa 
    danu</indigenous>‚Ä?, meaning ‚Äúinstead of the mouse not to eat 
    something, it would simply mess it up to prevent others from having 
    it‚Ä?.</p>
    <p>Abiola might have had his own problems with the rapacious and 
    ruthless military while he was alive, but what we all are saying is 
    that this man won an election ‚Äúclean and clear‚Ä?. Therefore, there 
    was no justification for its annulment. It is a pity that all we 
    have been inundated with since the criminal annulment are a 
    potpourri of lies, half-truths and blatant deceit from the major 
    actors in the tragi-comedy that almost shook the nation to its 
    foundations.</p>
    <p>However, the most appalling thing is that we have not utilized 
    the lessons of June 12 to shape our national life. Herein lies the 
    real tragedy of the whole saga.</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
