<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2009-08-07</date>
    <place>http://www.thisdayonline.com/</place>
    <author><gender>?</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>?</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>Judiciary and the Anti-Graft War</heading>
    <p>Chairman of the Economic and Fin<punctuation>-</punctuation>ancial Crimes 
    Com<punctuation>-</punctuation>mission (EFCC), Mrs<punctuation>.</punctuation> Farida Waziri and others 
    have attributed the slow pace of the anti-graft war in Nigeria to 
    flaws in the judicial process. According to them, many accused 
    persons standing trial in anti-graft cases, have, through their 
    lawyers, systematically devised effective means of whittling down 
    and undermining the effectiveness of the courts in the speedy 
    disposal of the cases against them.</p>
    <p>We cannot agree more that our flawed judicial process has 
    consistently impeded the sweeping measures to combat corruption in 
    Nigeria. Not infrequently, former State Governors and political 
    bigwigs standing trial in high profile anti-graft cases bribe their 
    way to obtain dubious court injunctions to impede their prosecution 
    in court. Anti-graft cases are stalled by unnecessary court 
    adjournments.</p>
    <p>Distressfully, some lawyers handling anti-graft cases, who are 
    supposed to be officers in the temple of justice, throw decorum and 
    professional ethics overboard to bring frivolous court applications 
    aimed at scuttling the judicial process.</p>
    <p>Having said this, we are not unmindful of the fact that the 
    greatest obstacle in the wheel of the criminal justice system in 
    Nigeria is executive interference in the affairs of the judiciary. 
    Contrary to the principle of separation of power, some members of 
    the executive manipulate some anti-graft cases in favour of some 
    former State governors and high personalities. Some former State 
    governors who have benefited from this unjustified largesse are 
    walking the streets today as canonized saints.</p>
    <p>Even the EFCC cannot be exculpated from the tardiness and moral 
    degeneration which have flawed our judicial process. Oftentimes the 
    delay in the prosecution of those suspected to have been involved 
    in graft and official corruption results from poor preparation and 
    presentation of cases by the EFCC. In some cases, charges preferred 
    against some suspects by the EFCC are later dramatically dropped by 
    the same EFCC without genuine reasons. Some of the suspects being 
    publicly paraded by the EFCC are always beaming with smiles with 
    the belief that they would be let off the hook sooner or later.</p>
    <p>Till date, no suspect who has been investigated by the EFCC has 
    been duly convicted and sent to long imprisonment. The EFCC 
    pre-bargain option has drawn public outcry. Even the integrity of 
    the office of the Federal Attorney-General in the prosecution of 
    the anti-graft war is sometimes called into question by the 
    public.</p>
    <p>Consequently, we call on the Bar and the Bench to live up to 
    expectation in the dispensation of justice in anti-graft cases. Let 
    there be responsible criminal investigation and prosecution. 
    Quality criminal justice system stems from quality criminal 
    investigation and prosecution. When our judiciary is corrupted by 
    the very people who should labour to maintain its prestige, the 
    inevitable outcome is huge stranglehold on the judiciary, 
    bare-faced injustice and enthronement of corrupt criminal justice 
    system.</p>
    <p>All said, an efficient and effective criminal justice, 
    predicated upon the basic principles of law and justice and 
    propelled by a vibrant judicial system is indispensable in winning 
    the <error corrected="anti-">ant-</error>graft war in Nigeria.</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
