<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2009-07-05</date>
    <place>http://www.vanguardngr.com/</place>
    <author><gender>?</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>?</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>Oaths, Oath-takers</heading>
    <p>NUDE pictures of some members of the Ogun State House of 
    Assembly published last week in newspapers are minor indices of 
    where we are as a country.</p>
    <p>Unexpectedly, the owners of the pictures have admitted that the 
    pictures were theirs, with slight disagreements about whether they 
    were taken in a shrine or the private home of the Ogun State 
    governor.</p>
    <p>These are the latest scenes from the apathetic drama that has 
    been on in the State for some months. The Executive and the 
    Legislature are locked in disputes that bear no relevance to 
    discharging their responsibilities for the well-being of the 
    people.</p>
    <p>An initial newspaper report was that those involved swore to an 
    oath to fight the governor to the end. The oath-takers claimed the 
    oath was a forced pledge of their allegiance to the governor ‚Äì a 
    practice they said was common state-wide.</p>
    <p>None of these interests us. Our concerns are over the depravity 
    that has taken over our politics. We thought the days allegiance to 
    individuals were through with incidents at the Okija Shrine six 
    years ago.</p>
    <p>It seems that there are other shrines still in business, thanks 
    to the desperate desires of politicians to lay their hands on power 
    at all costs.</p>
    <p>The Constitution which the Executive, Legislature and Judiciary 
    swear to uphold, prescribes two oaths in the Seventh Schedule, oath 
    of allegiance and oath of office or membership.</p>
    <p>The oath of allegiance states, ‚ÄúI do solemnly swear that I will 
    be faithful and bear true allegiance to the Federal Republic of 
    Nigeria and that I will preserve, protect and defend the 
    Constitution of the Federal Republic of Nigeria. So help me 
    God‚Ä?.</p>
    <p>Each state legislature swears or affirms thus, ‚ÄúI do solemnly 
    swear that I will be faithful and bear true allegiance to the 
    Federal Republic of Nigeria; that as a Member of the State House of 
    Assembly, I will perform my functions honestly to the best of my 
    ability, faithfully and in accordance with the Constitution of the 
    Federal Republic of Nigeria and the law, and the rules of the House 
    of Assembly and always in the interest of the sovereignty, 
    integrity, solidarity, well-being and prosperity of the Federal 
    Republic of Nigeria;</p>
    <p>that I will strive to preserve the Fundamental Objectives and 
    Principles of State Policy contained in the Constitution of the 
    Federal Republic of Nigeria; and that I will preserve, defend and 
    protect the Constitution of the Federal Republic of Nigeria; and 
    that I will abide by the Code of Conduct that is contained in the 
    Fifth Schedule of the Constitution of the Federal Republic of 
    Nigeria. So help me God‚Ä?. Allegiance is to Nigeria and the Nigerian 
    people.</p>
    <p>The Fifth Schedule Part I, Article 10 of the Constitution (Code 
    of Conduct) states, ‚ÄúA public officer shall not be a member of, or 
    belong to, or take part in any society the membership of which is 
    incompatible with the functions or dignity of his office‚Ä?.</p>
    <p>The Code of Conduct Bureau should investigate this 
    embarrassment.</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
