<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2009-07-23</date>
    <place>www.thisdayonline.com</place>
    <author><gender>?</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>?</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>Wole Soyinka at 75</heading>
    <p>Over the years, Professor Oluwole Akinwande Soyinka (better 
    known as Wole Soyinka) has amply demonstrated how best to use one’s 
    talents for the advancement of society. His award of the 
    prestigious Nobel Prize for Literature a boost to the international 
    rating of Nigeria, especially at a time the country’s image was at 
    its lowest ebb. Still, the literary icon is so dissatisfied with 
    the socio-economic and political situation in his native country 
    that his entire life has been devoted to the quest for a better 
    society. </p>
    <p>Soyinka, who clocked 75 on July 13, is one of the greatest gifts 
    of Mother Nature to Nigeria. Born in Ake, Abeokuta in the present 
    Ogun State on July 13, 1934, the first African Nobel laureate in 
    Literature has, through the years, made his marks as an erudite 
    scholar, a literary giant, a formidable critic of bad governments 
    and especially an ardent foe of military regimes. He could even be 
    described as a one-man opposition to bad governance, where 
    government appears to have suppressed or bought over political 
    opposition. </p>
    <p>His interest in the arts manifested early when, as a pupil of 
    St<punctuation>.</punctuation> Peters School, Ake, Abeokuta, he perfectly acted the 
    role of a magician in a drama presented during one of the school’s 
    prize-giving day ceremonies. Even at Government College, Ibadan, 
    Soyinka distinguished himself as a prominent member of the school’s 
    drama society. </p>
    <p>In 1952, he was admitted into the then University College, 
    Ibadan where he studied English, History and Greek. His first poem 
    was published in The University Voice, the official newsletter of 
    the students union in 1953. </p>
    <p>Soyinka left Ibadan for Leeds University, UK in 1954. His first 
    short story, Madam Etinne’s Establishment, was published in the 
    university’s magazine, The Gryphon in 1957. He returned to the 
    country in 1960 and formed a drama group, <punctuation>‘</punctuation>The 1960 
    Masks<punctuation>’</punctuation>, which acted as a catalyst to his theatre 
    activities. His play, A Dance of the Forests, won the first prize 
    for the Independence play-writing contest. </p>
    <p>Probably Africa’s most influential playwright, Soyinka is one of 
    the wittiest and most sophisticated writers Nigeria has ever 
    produced. His polymathic literary accomplishment is legendary, 
    being unusually versatile in all the three genres of literature --- 
    Poetry, Prose and Drama.  His versatility was handsomely rewarded 
    in 1986 with the prestigious Nobel Prize for Literature, making him 
    the first African to win that award. </p>
    <p>Soyinka has survived many attempts to silence his voice, 
    including imprisonment, harassment by security agents and even 
    exile in the course of his relentless agitation for peace, freedom 
    and good governance. </p>
    <p>In the aftermath of the annulment of the June 12 1993 election, 
    believed to have been won by the late Chief M<punctuation>.</punctuation>K<punctuation>.</punctuation>O<punctuation>.</punctuation> Abiola, Soyinka was in the forefront of pro-democracy 
    activists agitating for the restoration of the Abiola mandate. He 
    went on exile in November 1994 to escape persecution by the Sani 
    Abacha regime but he continued the struggle for democratic rule 
    from there.   </p>
    <p>Soyinka is not an armchair critic. He was once involved in 
    policy formulation during the Ibrahim Babangida regime. One of his 
    concerns led to the establishment of the Federal Road Safety 
    Commission (FRSC), which he briefly headed as the pioneer corps 
    marshal. </p>
    <p>Some people however criticise him for being instrumental to the 
    founding of Pyrates Confraternity in his University of Ibadan days. 
    The concept of the group, which was a noble intention of fighting 
    elitism and tribalism on campus, was invariably contaminated to be 
    the foundation for campus terrorism across the country today. </p>
    <p>We salute this irrepressible critic and illustrious son of 
    Nigeria who has remained the conscience of the nation, forever 
    keeping corrupt regimes on their toes. </p>
  </text>
</annotated>
