<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2009-07-12</date>
    <place>www.thisdayonline.com</place>
    <author><gender>?</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>?</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>Nigeria‚Äôs Unknown Unemployed</heading>
    <p>Recently, Labour and Productivity Minister Adetokunbo Kayode 
    admitted that Nigeria has no accurate figure of its unemployed 
    population. That honest admission is commendable, but we find it 
    unacceptable.  </p>
    <p>Speaking at a conference of the Association of Vice Chancellors 
    of Nigerian Universities, the minister said that there was no 
    accurate figure of unemployed Nigerians, and so he had to adopt an 
    ‚Äúanecdotal figure‚Ä? of 40 million pending the report of the 
    committee set up by the Federal Government to determine the real 
    figure.  </p>
    <p>According to him, the unemployed make up about 32 per cent of 
    the population. The figures are similar to those of the World Bank, 
    which have been disputed by some scholars. There are concerns that, 
    going by the evidence on the streets, the figure may be far 
    higher.  </p>
    <p>However, there is no point arguing about the high rate of 
    unemployment in Nigeria. Even the Minister‚Äôs anecdotal figure is 
    depressing considering the country‚Äôs enormous resources; and scary 
    because of the economic, physical and psychological effects of 
    unemployment.  </p>
    <p>One, there is a strong correlation between unemployment and 
    poverty, both of which are high in Nigeria.  </p>
    <p>Two, it has high private cost to those directly affected. In 
    addition to the pain of poverty and deprivation, unemployment is 
    associated with depression, anxiety and low self-esteem.  </p>
    <p>Three, its social cost is also high. Unemployment is associated 
    with higher levels of family breakdowns, alcohol and drug abuse, 
    suicide and crime.  </p>
    <p>Four, and what should also be of concern to Government is that 
    unemployment affects the entire economy, not just those unfortunate 
    to be unemployed. Since many unemployed people have skills and 
    training that are not being utilised in production, national income 
    and production are reduced if these people were gainfully working.  
    </p>
    <p>These are reasons why governments all over the world, worry 
    about rising unemployment and so strive to keep it at the barest 
    minimum. The global economic meltdown has caused job losses in many 
    countries, but Nigeria seems to have been living with the problem 
    of unemployment for so long that its significance must have been 
    lost on the people.  </p>
    <p>The lack of reasonable unemployment statistics does not speak 
    well of the government. Of course, no proper planning can be done 
    without reliable statistics. That there is no statistical backup 
    explains why, too often, the nation cannot do effective long term 
    planning, and our penchant for always adopting ad hoc measures. 
    Indeed, how can a nation plan for a group of people without knowing 
    their number?  </p>
    <p>Although the minister said a committee is working towards 
    scientific unemployment statistics, we are wondering when it would 
    be ready for use by a government that has gone past its mid-term. 
    Unemployment is one of the government‚Äôs 7-point agenda.  If it 
    takes two years and more to get the figures, how long then will it 
    take to provide the needed jobs?  </p>
    <p>At this stage of our development, we should have a working 
    estimate of graduates from our tertiary institutions annually, what 
    job openings there are for them, what numbers would be left, what 
    they are likely to do to survive and what support can be given 
    them.  </p>
    <p>We wonder what has become of the registration of the unemployed 
    by the National Directorate of Employment in 2007.  </p>
    <p>As the committee continues its work, more and more people are 
    added by the growing number of universities and other tertiary 
    institutions to the unemployment figure.  </p>
    <p>Also added are many artisans who depend on public electricity 
    supply but can no longer work because of the epileptic nature of 
    the supply. There are also youths who continue to abandon 
    agriculture in the rural areas for non-existent urban jobs and of 
    course, the victims of the global economic meltdown.    </p>
    <p>Yet, there are other problems. Mr<punctuation>.</punctuation> Kayode  lamented that 
    ‚Äúlack of proper skills, re-skilling, poor facilities for skills 
    development, lack of planning and lack of co-ordination, confusion, 
    inefficient application of scarce resources‚Ä¶ greatly contributed to 
    put our country in a very precarious job deficit.‚Ä?  </p>
    <p>But it is not enough understanding the problems, or decrying the 
    situation. It is more helpful designing schemes and measures to 
    combat identified problems.  </p>
    <p>Now that the minister has adopted the ‚Äúanecdotal figures‚Ä? of 40 
    million Nigerians, what plans are underway to decongest the labour 
    market? That is what will count for this government at the end of 
    the day. Government has an obligation to create job opportunities 
    or at the very least, create an enabling environment for private 
    enterprises to provide employment for people.  </p>
    <p>We believe that the only enduring solution to unemployment and 
    poverty is economic growth.  </p>
  </text>
</annotated>
