<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2009-07-13</date>
    <place>http://thenationonlineng.net/web/</place>
    <author><gender>?</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>?</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>Debtors roll</heading>
    <p>In a move akin to disrobing the masquerade in the public square, 
    the Senate took the unusual step of naming erstwhile directors and 
    chief executives of failed banks involved in N53<punctuation>.</punctuation>3 billion 
    insider loans abuse. The amount is apparently the outstanding sum 
    after the Nigeria Deposit Insurance Corporation’s (NDIC) recovery 
    of N4<punctuation>.</punctuation>722 billion, which the former directors gave out in 
    loans to the companies where they had interests.</p>
    <p>The Senate is also reported as pressing to create special courts 
    to try failed banks’ loan defaulters, as a measure to bring succour 
    to innocent depositors of the banks, said to be owed a whopping 
    N188 billion.</p>
    <p>We welcome the Senate’s bold move to revisit a matter over which 
    many innocent Nigerians not only lost their entire life savings, 
    but in which some actually died in the long wait for restitution 
    from the NDIC, after those banks were ran aground by their owners 
    and managers.</p>
    <p>As unsettling as naming names is to some, its significance lies 
    in its ripping the anonymity shield behind which the actors took 
    shelter, after killing their institutions. We consider it a first 
    step in the quest to deal with the impunity of the era in which 
    ownership of a financial institution, and the privileges that went 
    with it, became license to feather individuals’ business interests, 
    to the detriment of the entire financial system.</p>
    <p>At this stage, we can only consider the job only as half done, 
    given what we know of the elite penchant for diversionary, 
    hair-splitting legalese. We suspect that a lot of noise would be 
    made around the so-called legal or ethical issues of making names 
    of the debtors public, as if those issues are far more important 
    than the duty of making good the payment of the debts owed.</p>
    <p>The nation has apparently come full circle from the 1990s when 
    the late General Sani Abacha herded distressed banks’ chiefs to 
    jail for the same reason of insider-credit abuses, albeit, without 
    the rigours of due process. In the past decade, the system appears 
    to have lapsed into the other extreme where impunity is condoned 
    and where criminal violators of rules and regulations are rewarded 
    with public appointments.</p>
    <p>We therefore see the need to bring a closure to the sordid 
    chapter as an imperative, to restore integrity into the system and 
    to send the signal that such ignoble conduct would never escape 
    sanctions. The Senate has taken an important step in this regard. 
    Pressure must be made on debtors to pay off what they owe by 
    whatever means legal and constitutional, including the possibility 
    of a blacklist from the financial system, when all suasions 
    fail.</p>
    <p>Do we need special courts to try the alleged offenders? The 
    sentiment behind the recommendation is understandable, given the 
    belief that the slow wheel of the administration of justice may 
    impede the process of their prosecution and, the objective, which 
    is, restitution. However, the point is that we haven’t yet seen 
    evidence of diligence on the part of either the NDIC or even the 
    apex bank to prosecute the alleged offenders, to convince on the 
    need for special courts.</p>
    <p>The lesson of the failed banks’ loan defaulters, yet again, 
    reminds of the need for the regulators, particularly the Central 
    Bank of Nigeria (CBN) and the NDIC to be alive to their duties of 
    regulation. That the nation is saddled with pervasive operators’ 
    delinquencies is only to be explained by the failures of the 
    regulatory institutions.</p>
    <p>This is where the declared resolve of the CBN governor, Sanusi 
    Lamido Sanusi, to be proactive in regulation makes eminent sense. 
    We must say never again to the financial system pathology in which 
    operators would run institutions aground while helping themselves 
    to depositors’ funds.</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
