<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2009-07-13</date>
    <place>www.thenationonlineng.net/web</place>
    <author><gender>f</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>?</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>For the Michaels, who will never be something</heading>
    <p>He was the king of pop. He came, saw, changed, and left. Did he 
    conquer, some of us have been asking? Some have made music of his 
    failings. Some have created stories of his frailties. Many others 
    have feasted on his victories. All have their views; some sound, 
    some warped and many others bizarrely illogical. But then, who made 
    us judges over him? Who?</p>
    <p>Who made us judges over Michael Jackson? Who? Yes, he had 
    problems with being an adult. He had challenges forgetting the 
    scars of childhood; he could not handle well his <punctuation>‘</punctuation>blackness,<punctuation>’</punctuation> some have said. It was tough getting to 
    the top, tougher staying there, we all know. In the midst of the 
    Babel of voices surrounding Michael Jackson though, it cannot be 
    lost on any that he created a Jackson, out of an ordinary Michael. 
    He made a person out of his being. He was not lost in the crowd, he 
    stood out. That is the tragedy of the other Michaels.</p>
    <p>Across the globe, continents far and near, countries hidden and 
    prominent, towns and cities, here and there, there are several 
    Michaels trying to model their lives around others. They seek, 
    without knowing, to create a new personality out of their perceived 
    blighted self. Rightly, they are not comfortable with their present 
    situation like Jackson. They want to change it. They however do not 
    know how.</p>
    <p>You will see them in the music sector with dreadlocks, the type 
    made popular by Bob Marley. They love good music, but are not ready 
    to make them. At parties, they mime others and are too busy to 
    create their own. They take weed, 
    <italics><indigenous>ganja</indigenous></italics> and other harmful 
    substances as if these breed greatness. These other Michaels love 
    good things but are far too concerned about the bad ways around 
    good deeds. They end up either in various psychiatric homes or on 
    the streets as <punctuation>‘</punctuation>children of government<punctuation>’</punctuation> 
    as the Yoruba refer to them.</p>
    <p>One thing that stands these Michaels out in Nigeria is their 
    love for all that is alien and a commensurate disdain for all that 
    is ours. They have accents that are unfamiliar to all; mannerisms 
    that no one can link to any civilisation; a dress sense that no one 
    can identify with and slang that are either too weird or too loose. 
    They are pursuers of the shallow things around stardom. In fact 
    they crave the stars but are not ready to lift themselves off 
    ground zero.</p>
    <p>In sports, they cheat at every turn. They are 16 on their 30th 
    birthdays; under-20s when they are over 30. They help themselves to 
    drugs instead of work. They lobby to be selected; and then pay to 
    keep in the limelight. Whenever talent is to be celebrated, they 
    show their latency for quackery. For every failure, they craft some 
    tricky excuses. They do not care to prepare to excel, after all; 
    you could blame others for failure.</p>
    <p>In the academia, they work their ways to make qualifying grades; 
    do more to move on and end up selling everything from marks to 
    handouts, all to keep the pretence to intellectualism. They ape 
    every move of those in authority; ask no questions, so deserve no 
    answers. They are like robots in the hands of power, pliable and 
    manoeuvrable all the time. They have no elastic limits; they take 
    abuses and rape and give as much to their hapless students. They 
    struggle for nothing and seek to benefit from everything. 
    Conscience, to them, is alien, so there is no truth to be healed 
    around them.</p>
    <p>In politics, they are examples of all that is vain. Some bleach 
    their skins only to woo their next consorts; steal as if today is 
    the last. They think only about aspiring to power. They kill to get 
    into office, murder to stay there. They do everything that is 
    wrong, pretending they want to right the past. They claim they want 
    to take us forward while they are driving us backward.</p>
    <p>They dream dreams of the past and present them as hope for the 
    future. The Michaels in the political firmament are not concerned 
    about today, they care little about tomorrow; they are so steeped 
    in inglorious fantasies about themselves. They are verbose when 
    they should be taciturn and reticent when they ought to speak out. 
    They are meticulous concerning frivolity and flippant on matters of 
    grave concern. They speak when they ought to be listening and keep 
    sealed lips when they ought to speak out.</p>
    <p>They are there in journalism; as quacks selling their by-lines 
    for a <indigenous>kobo</indigenous>. In medical practice they are 
    there, in law they are many. In all their areas of endeavour, the 
    Michaels never dared to be different. When they do attempt 
    brilliance, it is in breaking all records of indecency, throwing 
    politeness and decorum to the dogs. They are therefore always lost 
    in the crowd, or consigned to infamy. Unlike Michael Jackson, the 
    other Michaels are comfortable with just being there.</p>
    <p>And so as their voices are lost in condemning the excellence 
    that Michael Jackson was, we write about the men and women who have 
    refused to move beyond their limitations; who have refused to live 
    above their weaknesses and have become prisoners of their 
    circumstances. They may live to be a million years, but they will 
    leave this part unsung, uncelebrated; alone, and go either to 
    heaven or to hell, unheralded.</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
