<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2009-06-11</date>
    <place>http://thenationonlineng.net/web</place>
    <author><gender>m</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>Etsakor</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>Missing Adedibu in Ibadan</heading>
    <p>When the elephant fell in Ibadan last year, the forest shook and 
    the people knew that the man many of them love to hate is gone. 
    Today marks the first anniversary of the death of Lamidi Ariyibi 
    Adedibu, the man who was popularly referred to as the strong man of 
    Ibadan politics. In the politics of Ibadan, Adedibu was the alpha 
    and omega. He made and unmade politicians. Those interested in 
    political office knew that it was in their own interest to court 
    Adedibu. To cultivate Adedibu is not an easy task. For someone who 
    had virtually turned himself into an idol those who curried his 
    favour came to him on bent knees.</p>
    <p>Since an idol is not a mere mortal like the rest of us, they 
    also brought along the necessary items for appeasing Adedibu, who 
    was at his best dispensing political favours. In Ibadan, the fear 
    of Adedibu was the beginning of wisdom. He was larger than life and 
    everybody including those who held power in Oyo State deferred to 
    him. Why won’t they defer to him? Was he not the kingmaker; the 
    power behind the throne?</p>
    <p>Because he single-handedly installed governors, local government 
    chairmen, councillors and commissioners, Adedibu was Ibadan and 
    Ibadan was Adedibu. As the <error corrected="indigeneous">
    indigenes</error> would put it, <indigenous>Adedibu kan, Ibadan 
    kan</indigenous>. His home in Molete was a mecca of sorts for all 
    manner of people – the high and mighty, the low and unlettered, 
    widows and political jobbers. They were always in 
    <italics>Molete</italics> to pay homage to the master. Even though 
    Ibadan has an <indigenous>Oba</indigenous> under whom Adedibu 
    served as a chief, his influence surpassed that of the monarch. He 
    was law unto himself and as such he broke the laws of the land with 
    impunity.</p>
    <p>What made Adedibu tick was apparently the political influence he 
    wielded in his lifetime. He was a grassroots man who understood the 
    poor very well. He felt their pangs and pains. Since the lowly saw 
    him as their benefactor, they thronged his residence. 
    <italics>Afin</italics> Molete as his residence was called was 
    always thick with people, who came calling anytime of the day. Come 
    rain, come shine, they were there. They ate and slept in Adedibu’s 
    house. Adedibu made them feel important by eating from the same 
    bowl with them. He shared almost everything he had with them. 
    Through his generosity and kindness, he bought their loyalty.</p>
    <p>This was why these <punctuation>‘</punctuation>boys<punctuation>’</punctuation> were ready 
    to do anything for the apostle of <indigenous>amala</indigenous> 
    politics. When Baba as they called him died on June 11, last year, 
    something also died in them. A part of them died because they knew 
    that there would no longer be freebies for them. Besides, 
    politicians would now be using and dumping them. Unlike Adedibu who 
    used and shielded them. One year after Adedibu’s passage, Ibadan 
    seems to be missing him and his troubles.</p>
    <p>Trust Adedibu. If he was alive today, he may be spearheading the 
    second term campaign for President Umar Yar’Adua in defiance of the 
    President’s directive stopping such campaign. By now, Adedibu would 
    have set up shop in Ibadan and mobilised his <punctuation>‘</punctuation>boys<punctuation>’</punctuation> to go about town rooting for Yar’Adua. In the 
    process, Adedibu would not give a hoot if heads and limbs are 
    broken. All that matters to him would be that Ibadan, nay Oyo 
    State, supports Yar’Adua. By now too, he would be working to get a 
    second term ticket for his political godson and acolyte Governor 
    Adebayo Alao-Akala. Alao-Akala was totally loyal to Adedibu in his 
    lifetime. He used the master’s political structure to get to office 
    in 2007. With Adedibu’s death, Alao-Alaka seems to have come of age 
    politically. He is ready to run on his own steam in 2011.</p>
    <p>Since Adedibu’s death, Alao-Akala has built his own political 
    structure. He is now the undisputable leader of the Peoples 
    Democratic Party (PDP) in Oyo State. With his new found power, he 
    has become a threat to some people, among them those close to his 
    late political godfather. The political ambition of these people is 
    hanging in the balance, all because of their differences with 
    Alao-Akala. See what death has caused! With Adedibu’s passage, the 
    terrain now belongs to Alao-Akala.</p>
    <heading>The June 12 saga</heading>
    <p>As a friend to many generals, the late Chief M<punctuation>.</punctuation> K<punctuation>.</punctuation>O<punctuation>.</punctuation> Abiola was expected to know the mindset of the 
    military. Abiola probably thought he knew how military men think, 
    and this perhaps informed his decision to contest the June 12, 1993 
    presidential election. Abiola was not new to politics when he 
    decided to go for the nation’s plum job 16 years ago. He had tried 
    and burnt his fingers in politics in the Second Republic. His wife, 
    the late Simbiat, also ran for the Senate and lost.</p>
    <p>After that experience, Abiola and his wife quit politics and 
    faced their business squarely. To manage the chains of business 
    owned by the Abiolas is not easy, not to talk of mixing it with 
    politics. Abiola quit politics then because the defunct National 
    Party of Nigeria (NPN) to which he belonged felt he could not 
    aspire to lead it. Abiola had wanted to be the party’s chairman, 
    but the Northerners who were in the majority in NPN thought 
    otherwise. They told him unequivocally that the chairmanship was 
    not for sale, meaning that with all his wealth, he could not head 
    the party.</p>
    <p>Abiola felt slighted because he had done much for the party and 
    also used his then flourishing newspaper, <italics>National 
    Concord</italics>, to fight the defunct Unity Party of Nigeria 
    (UPN) and its leader, the late Chief Obafemi Awolowo, who was and 
    still is highly-revered in Yorubaland. By taking on Awo, many 
    Yoruba <error corrected="indigeneous">indigenes</error> believe, 
    Abiola committed sacrilege. And for this, they were not prepared to 
    forgive him politically. If not for his large-heartedness and 
    legendary generosity, what his people considered his misdemeanour 
    would have affected his chances at the polls in 1993.</p>
    <p>But because of his nature and the forgiving spirit of his 
    people, Abiola pulled through. He emerged winner of the June 12, 
    1993 presidential election, which has been described as the freest 
    and fairest ever held in the country. But the military, or better 
    still the friend he thought he knew so well – General Ibrahim 
    Babangida - was waiting in the wings to scuttle his victory. Till 
    today, Babangida has not been able to tell Nigerians why he 
    annulled the election. Whenever he has the opportunity to tell the 
    nation why he took that action, he skirts around the issue, 
    preferring to talk from both sides of the mouth.</p>
    <p>For how long will Babangida continue to take us for a ride? Will 
    he ever come clean with the nation on why he annulled the June 12 
    election? Why is he afraid of a full disclosure? Is he no longer 
    the general who dominates his environment? Whether he talks now or 
    in the future, some day, somehow, the truth about the June 12 saga 
    will be told.</p>
    <heading>Adieu, the people’s chair</heading>
    <p>The news of the death of Alhaji Ladi Lawal in the early hours of 
    Saturday, May 23 came to me through a text message from my 
    colleague, Mrs Dupe Olaoye-Osinkolu popularly known as 
    <italics>Mama Labour</italics>. Until his death, I never knew that 
    &quot;my chair&quot; as we used to call him those days was ill. It 
    has been long since I saw him except when I occasionally watch him 
    on television.</p>
    <p>I knew Ladi Lawal when I was a rookie reporter with <italics>The 
    Punch</italics>Newspaper. He was then with the Federal Radio 
    Corporation of Nigeria (FRCN) and was campaigning for the chairman 
    of the Lagos State Council of the Nigeria Union of Journalists 
    (NUJ). <italics>Baba Africa</italics>, yes, the one and only 
    <italics>Baba Africa</italics>, Mr Dapo Aderinola, who was then the 
    council chairman and our Chief News Editor in the <italics>The 
    Punch</italics>, was rooting for Lawal who had served diligently as 
    his secretary.</p>
    <heading>Africa</heading>
    <p>got us all in The Punch to vote for Lawal and the rest, as they 
    say is history. Lawal served two terms and crowned it with the 
    president of our union in 1993. Lawal was a great unionist who 
    never allowed his unionism to clash with his job. This was why the 
    Federal Government found it difficult to sack him even when he was 
    a thorn in its flesh at FRCN.</p>
    <p>I learnt one thing from Lawal and that is: you can be a great 
    unionist without <error corrected="compromising">
    compremising</error> your job. The naming of the Lagos NUJ Press 
    <error corrected="Centre">cCentre</error> at Ikeja after him last 
    Saturday is an honour well deserved. My chair, you made us proud as 
    our leader. I thank God for your life but I thank you for giving us 
    Mrs Funke Fadugba, the woman who elevated the status of many Lagos 
    journalists.</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
