<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2009-07-13</date>
    <place>http://thenationonlineng.net/web/</place>
    <author><gender>m</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>?</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <heading>An aborted presidential visit and a funeral</heading>
    <p>Two dubious public expenditure items from Bayelsa and Enugu 
    States were buried inside a few newspapers last week, causing 
    hardly a whimper among scandal-fatigued Nigerians, but reinforcing 
    the general perception that venality in public office has worsened 
    in recent years.</p>
    <p>The first was the revelation that the 16 standing committees set 
    up by the Bayelsa State Government to organize a reception for 
    Umaru Musa Yar’Adua had submitted a bill of N1<punctuation>.</punctuation>2 billion out 
    of which N456 million had been shared out before Abuja abruptly 
    announced the postponement of the two-day presidential visit for 
    reasons still unclear.</p>
    <p>The other curious bill was the N600 million burial expenses 
    submitted to the Enugu State Government by the committee planning a 
    state burial for Chief Christian Chukwuma Onoh, Governor (for three 
    months only) of old Anambra State.</p>
    <p>Media reports last week quoted officials of the Bayelsa State 
    Government appealing to the committee members not to divert the 
    N456 million elsewhere since there was still hope that the visit 
    could be rescheduled soon. The governor’s security adviser, Chief 
    Pereneme Kpodoh, even wrote a rambling, sycophantic open letter to 
    Yar’Adua pleading for a rescheduling of the visit and blaming 
    Governor Timipre Sylva’s political opponents for aborting a visit 
    which he said would have brought &quot;positive changes&quot; to 
    the &quot;developmental landscape&quot; of the state. The 
    advertorial which ran in most national newspapers last week did not 
    say what positive changes a two-day presidential visit would have 
    wrought on Bayelsa’s developmental landscape that could warrant or 
    justify spending N1<punctuation>.</punctuation>2 billion on Yar’Adua’s reception.</p>
    <p>Enugu and the other states that constituted the old Anambra are 
    yet to make public how much of the N600-million pricy burial 
    expenses they made available to the planning committee. But judging 
    from the vituperations and angry denunciations of the Enugu State 
    government last week by Onoh’s son, Joseph, it was clear that the 
    ever reticent and focused Governor Sullivan Chime did not play 
    ball. He must have been highly scandalized by the huge funeral 
    budget submitted by the planning committee and might have resolved 
    to throw it back at the committee, perhaps with an advice that they 
    could very well auction a part of Onoh’s vast estate to raise the 
    ridiculous funeral fee.</p>
    <p>&quot;Despite all the disappointment by the Enugu 
    government&quot;, Joseph Onoh told newsmen last week on the eve of 
    the burial of his father, a wealthy lawyer and politician who was 
    said to have owned over 100 houses in Enugu alone during his 
    lifetime. &quot;We are ready to bury our father&quot;. He accused 
    Enugu State government of frustrating &quot;our burial plans&quot; 
    and commended the &quot;high level of commitment shown by other 
    governors of the South-East&quot; – a hint that those other 
    governors must have been blackmailed to contributed a chunk of the 
    hefty burial sum.</p>
    <p>The irony was lost on Joseph and members of the burial committee 
    that Onoh, a self-made man who was well known for his disciplined 
    and frugal lifestyle, would have fought against the very idea of 
    wasting N600 million scarce public funds on his burial. Had such a 
    budget been drawn up before his death, those who knew him swore 
    that he would have gone to court to stop the state government from 
    indulging in such a monumental waste. He would have seen through 
    the gluttonous proclivity of the committee members to pad up the 
    burial budget as part of the usual mercantile schemes to make some 
    quick money from every government-sponsored public event. Onoh 
    would have argued that the money be invested in building more 
    classrooms or in buying books for schools or in stocking hospitals 
    with drugs or in constructing a few rural roads or in drilling over 
    600 boreholes. As a shrewd businessman, he knew that these 
    investments would bring more tangible benefits to the people of the 
    South-East than a N600 million funeral revelry.</p>
    <p>Cleverly, both the burial and presidential visit planning 
    committees did not provide a breakdown of how they arrived at these 
    bizarre figures. It is left to a bewildered populace to speculate 
    whether the committees had decided to put Onoh to sleep in an all 
    diamond coffin and make Yar’Adua pass the night in a diamond 
    bedecked bed in Yenagoa village and treat him to a feast of oysters 
    and lobsters. How did it all add up?</p>
    <p>These two highly inflated budgets have once again shown our 
    absolute lack of regard for public money. We tend to see public 
    money as belonging to no one in particular and, therefore, have no 
    qualms squandering it on worthless causes. At every available 
    opportunity, we are often too eager to <error corrected="devise">
    device</error> all sort of schemes to line up our pockets. It is 
    done with impunity. There is no sense of guilt or shame or 
    moderation. And it is getting worse by the day. It used to be in 
    hundreds and thousands of Naira. Today, it is in millions and 
    billions. Kleptomaniacs are getting more audacious. Because they 
    know that there are often no questions asked, let alone sanctions 
    imposed. Life has become one mad rush for material wealth, a 
    primitive acquisition of money, houses, cars, and wives and 
    mistresses.</p>
    <p>It is in this context that we must situate the decision of the 
    Bayelsa committees to vote N1<punctuation>.</punctuation>2 billion for the hosting of 
    Yar’Adua and for the burial committee in Enugu to demand N600 
    million for the burial of Onoh. People generally see these two 
    events as a chance to partake in the sharing of the commonwealth 
    since public office holders and their cronies are also believed to 
    be helping themselves to such common resources.</p>
    <p>One of the lessons we must draw from these scandals is the 
    abysmal failure of governance or the embarrassing poor quality of 
    leadership in the country. Why would any serious government allow 
    N1<punctuation>.</punctuation>2 billion (about N2<punctuation>.</punctuation>5 million per hour for the two 
    days Yar’Adua would have spent in the state) to be wasted in 
    hosting a leader who has not done anything in the last two years to 
    improve the lives of the people of the Niger Delta? What then is 
    the basis for all the hoopla and excitement about the visit? Would 
    these people spend their personal money with such recklessness? 
    Besides creating the Niger Delta Ministry, what has Yar’Adua to 
    show the people of the region as his achievements in the past two 
    years? Rather than make them richer with his presence, Yar’Adua has 
    made them poorer even by his absence (N456 million has gone with 
    the wind of Yenagoa).</p>
    <p>The people of the Niger Delta must learn to hold their leaders 
    accountable for the use of their money. They must have the courage 
    to ask why hosting Yar’Adua for two days should cost them N1<punctuation>.</punctuation>2 billion. In the same vein, the people of the South-East must 
    ask their governors how much they actually coughed out for the 
    burial of Chief C<punctuation>.</punctuation> C<punctuation>.</punctuation> Onoh. They should demand to 
    know whether these governors allowed their states to be robbed in 
    broad daylight in the name of a needless state burial.</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
