<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2009-07-10</date>
    <place>Ife</place>
    <author><gender>m</gender><age>53</age><ethnic-group>Yoruba</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <p>Dear Prof<punctuation>.</punctuation> <x-anonym-x type="family-name"/>,</p>
    <p>I am <x-anonym-x type="first-name"/> 
    <x-anonym-x type="family-name"/>, PhD, a Professor of English and 
    Applied Linguistics in the Department of English, 
    <x-anonym-x type="organisation"/> University, 
    <x-anonym-x type="location"/>, Nigeria.</p>
    <p>I wish to request your kind assistance to support my application 
    for a DAAD=A0 Post-doctoral scholarship for 3 months, from XXX, to 
    enable me research further into, write and share knowledge on the 
    topic of my inaugural lecture, which I intend to present by the end 
    of <x-anonym-x/> in my home <error corrected="institution.">
    institution .</error></p>
    <p>I shall be grateful if you could, please, serve as my host 
    professor and also help to process a letter of invitation from your 
    university during the period of my stay in Germany.</p>
    <p>I have chosen you along with two other professors as my 
    potential host after due consideration of your pedigree as a 
    renowned scholar of Applied linguistics and your sustained interest 
    in English language studies in native and non-native contexts. 
    Although my research will be largely independent, I shall 
    undoubtedly benefit from useful comments and ideas from other 
    experts in the field, to enhance the quality of the project.</p>
    <p>Advanced Information on the project is provided thus:</p>
    <p>Title of Proposal: English Language Usage, Use and Misuse in a 
    Non-host Second Language Context, Nigeria</p>
    <p>Objectives: a. Review the current state of English in Nigeria as 
    presented in existing studies; b. Analyse and describe data on 
    English usage and micro- and macro-uses in Nigeria with respect to 
    the prospects and problems; and c. Determine the extent and limits 
    of the status of English vis-a-vis other languages in Nigeria for 
    achieving sustainable national development</p>
    <p>Methodology: Report from empirical studies, natural observation, 
    interviews and questionnaire</p>
    <p>Perspectives: Sociolinguistics, Bilingualism/Multilingualism</p>
    <p>Outline (Tentative)</p>
    <p>1.Nigerian English as an Institutionalized ESL Variety of 
    English</p>
    <p>2.Aspects of English Language Studies in Nigeria</p>
    <p>3.Uses and Misuses (Micro-and Macro-) of the English language in 
    Nigeria</p>
    <p>4.Re-positioning the English Language and other languages in 
    Nigeria <error corrected="fo rsustainable">forsustainable</error> 
    national development and global relevance</p>
    <p>I am already writing the study proposal for the application and 
    shall send it to you for your input when I finish.
    <error corrected=" "/>I have attached my CV to this request to 
    familiarize you with my academic and professional activities to 
    date.</p>
    <p>Thank you and best regards,</p>
    <p><x-anonym-x type="first-name"/> <x-anonym-x type="family-name"/>
    </p>
  </text>
</annotated>
