<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2010-02-22</date>
    <place>www.thenationonline.net/web2</place>
    <author><gender>m</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>Igbo</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <p>SIR: In their zeal to govern Anambra State, two governorship 
    candidates in the February 6 election, Dr<punctuation>.</punctuation> Chris Ngige of 
    the Action Congress (AC) and Prof<punctuation>.</punctuation> Charles Soludo of the 
    Peoples Democratic Party (PDP), have turned mathematics, which is 
    an exact science, into politics, which is not science in the real 
    sense. But two plus two must be four, no matter how the two 
    previous candidates went to juggle figures politically or 
    emotionally.</p>
    <p>Ngige and Soludo claim that Governor Peter Obi did not make the 
    statutory 25 per cent of votes cast in two-thirds of the 21 local 
    councils in the State, as contained in the electoral law. Ngige 
    said Obi won 25 per cent in only 13 local councils, instead of 14 
    as required by the law. Countering the claim, however, the INEC 
    Resident Electoral Commissioner, Mr<punctuation>.</punctuation> Josiah Uwazuruonye, 
    insists Obi actually scored 25 per cent of votes cast in 15 local 
    councils.</p>
    <p>A copy of the detailed results of the governorship election, 
    issued by INEC, shows that though 301,232 votes were cast at the 
    election, 16,685 were rejected, invalidated or voided, leaving only 
    284,547 as valid votes. Therefore, the percentage of votes scored 
    by Obi or any other candidate was rightly and legally based on 
    valid votes of 284,547 cast, and not on 301,232. In this way, INEC 
    rightly calculated that Governor Obi won 25 per cent in 15 local 
    councils, and therefore triumphed in the election.</p>
    <p>If Ngige wants to go to the electoral tribunal, jolly well good, 
    let him do so. It is his right. Indeed, tribunals and law courts 
    exist to ensure that everyone stays within the rules. They are 
    bulwarks of liberty, champions of the individual against abuses of 
    power by scheming politicians, arrogant bureaucrats and the 
    emotional excesses of transient majorities.</p>
    <p>Maybe Ngige believes mathematics is politics, but surely, he 
    cannot convince the tribunal so. Perhaps in realization of the 
    futility of his case, he has forged an alliance with a group known 
    as &quot;Association of Disenfranchised Voters&quot;, who armed 
    with fuel and lighter, and loaded in buses, were heading to the 
    INEC office in Awka. It is a reminder of Ngige’s inglorious 
    governorship tenure when Anambra was reduced to rubbles by hired 
    thugs.</p>
    <p>Anambra people will not allow this to happen again in our state. 
    Under Governor Obi, in the past four years, we have been enjoying 
    abundant peace and comfort. Luckily, too, the last concluded 
    election was peaceful, free and fair.</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
