<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2007-09-05</date>
    <place>Ile-Ife</place>
    <author><gender>m</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>Itsekiri</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <p>Dramatic Arts Department,</p>
    <p>Obafemi Awolowo University,</p>
    <p>Ile-Ife.</p>
    <p>5<superscript>th</superscript> September, 2007.</p>
    <p>The Registrar,</p>
    <p>Obafemi Awolowo University,</p>
    <p>Ile-Ife.</p>
    <p>Dear Sir,</p>
    <p>APPLICATION FOR AN ACADEMIC STAFF POSITION.</p>
    <p>I humbly wish to apply as one of the Institution&apos;s 
    Assistant Lecturers in the Dramatic Arts Department.</p>
    <p>As would be clear from the enclosed resume, I have a 
    professional certificate, a Radio, Television and Film Production, 
    as well as a Bachelor and Master&apos;s degree, at the Obafemi 
    Awolowo University, Ile-Ife and the University of Ibadan 
    respectively. During these periods, I had immense theoretical and 
    practical experience in the theatre. More so, under the tutelage of 
    theatre icons like Foluke Ogunleye, Oku Atai, Bayo Afolabi, Kola 
    Oyewo, Lanrele Bamidele, Mathew Omukoro, Dele Layiwola, Femi 
    Osofisan and the Late Ola Rotimi to mention but a few.</p>
    <p>In view of the above and coupled with my other qualifications 
    and experience, I shall be useful and will perform creditably will 
    in the following areas of specialization: Script writing (Radio, 
    Television, Stage and the Print Media), Theatre Arts Theory and 
    Criticism, Film Theory and Criticism, Acting and Speech Arts, 
    Radio, Television and Film Production as well as in other academic 
    and administrative duties that would be assigned to me.</p>
    <p>I shall be very much obliged if this application is given due 
    consideration as I crave to be a member of academic staff in 
    Africa&apos;s number one citadel of learning, Obafemi Awolowo 
    University.</p>
    <p>Thanks for the anticipated and favourable response.</p>
    <p>Yours faithfully,</p>
    <p><signature /></p>
    <p><x-anonym-x type="first-name"/> <x-anonym-x type="family-name"/> 
    .</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
