<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2005-06-25</date>
    <place>Ota</place>
    <author><gender>?</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>?</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <p><object/></p>
    <p>OFFICE OF THE REGISTRAR</p>
    <p>June 25, 2005</p>
    <p><italics>DR <x-anonym-x type="first-name"/> 
    <x-anonym-x type="first-name"/> <x-anonym-x type="family-name"/>
    </italics></p>
    <p>College of Human Dev.</p>
    <p><x-anonym-x type="organisation"/> University,</p>
    <p><x-anonym-x type="location"/>.</p>
    <p><italics><underline>Salary Review 2005</underline></italics></p>
    <p><italics>Dear</italics> <x-anonym-x type="family-name"/></p>
    <p>Following presentations made to it, the Board of Regents has 
    approved a new salary structure tor the University and also 
    approved increases in pay volume for faculty and staff.</p>
    <p>The effective date for the new structure and the new pay is 
    1<superscript>st</superscript> July 2005 as against the 
    1<superscript>st</superscript> October incremental date. However, 
    migration from current salary structure to the new one for serving 
    faculty is based on following three factors.</p>
    <p>i) Graduated increase to reflect supply inelastic disciplines 
    and supply inelastic status beginning with any Lecturer I and above 
    who has a Ph<punctuation>.</punctuation>D. This is applied across discipline.</p>
    <p>ii) Performance assessment graduated increase for every regular 
    staff recently appraised.</p>
    <p>iii) Cots of living pay rise for every faculty on regular 
    appointment.</p>
    <p>On recommendation of Management, the Chancellor has approved the 
    outcome of the consideration under above criteria as they concern 
    you and in line with the inputed grades.</p>
    <p>Consequently, you have been relocated to the new salary package 
    on <x-anonym-x/>. This amounts to a monthly salary of 
    <italics>N</italics> <x-anonym-x/>.</p>
    <p>Please note that this review and the pay increase was carried 
    out essentially to:</p>
    <p>- Motivate you into greater productivity in your core assignment 
    of teaching, research and community development.</p>
    <p>- Close financial gap suggested by living cost demands.</p>
    <p>It is hoped that this increase should galvanize you to a higher 
    productivity, greater commitment to your students as well as 
    generate an inner drive and a capacity-building urge that should 
    turn you to a global amazement in your discipline.</p>
    <p>Congratulations.</p>
    <p><signature /></p>
    <p><x-anonym-x type="first-name"/> <x-anonym-x type="family-name"/>
    </p>
    <p>Registrar</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
