<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2005-08-30</date>
    <place>Ota</place>
    <author><gender>m</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>Yoruba</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <p><object/></p>
    <p>OFFICE OF THE REGISTRAR</p>
    <p>Dr X<punctuation>.</punctuation> X<punctuation>.</punctuation> <x-anonym-x/></p>
    <p>August 30, 2005</p>
    <p><coll for="Department">Dept</coll> of English</p>
    <p>College of Human <coll for="Development">Dev</coll>,</p>
    <p><x-anonym-x type="organisation"/> University,</p>
    <p>Dear <x-anonym-x/></p>
    <p><italics>Re: End of Sabbatical Leave.</italics></p>
    <p>I write on behalf of Management to acknowledge receipt of your 
    notification of end of sabbatical appointment with the University. 
    We believe you had an interesting and a rewarding career experience 
    here. As a University, we deeply appreciate your interest and 
    commitment to the duties assigned to you in the course of the year. 
    Your dutiful and single-minded Secretariat Coordination of the 
    International Conference on Human Development (ICHD 2005) and your 
    excellent performance as the College Exams Coordinator readily 
    comes to mind among others. Please be assured that the doors of the 
    University are open to you if anytime in the future you desire to 
    be a part of the work here on full time basis and we really 
    encourage you to give it a thought. Your commitment, dedication and 
    vision alignment makes an invitation such as we are here extending 
    a cheerful and willing offer.</p>
    <p>It is our understanding that having shared so richly and having 
    been so connected with us, you have become a part of the 
    <x-anonym-x type="organisation"/> University vision and we expect 
    you to be an ambassador of our values and a marketer of our 
    products.</p>
    <p>May the good Lord uphold you in all your future endeavours. 
    Amen</p>
    <p>Yours faithfully.</p>
    <p><signature /></p>
    <p><x-anonym-x/> <x-anonym-x/></p>
  </text>
</annotated>
