<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>2006-01-31</date>
    <place>www</place>
    <author><gender>?</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>Yoruba</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <p>Dear ISIS Users,</p>
    <p>ATTN: Departmental Examination Processing Coordinators.</p>
    <p>This is to inform you that an update for the ISIS package is now 
    available for downloading. This update takes care of two issues 
    viz:</p>
    <p>1. Deactivation of the cancelled 2004/2005 session lest it is 
    used for computation of leading to mass withdrawals.</p>
    <p>2. Granting of special waiver to students who were on probation 
    (below 1<punctuation>.</punctuation>00) in 2002/2003 Harmattan semester and who, 
    because they did not have access to their 2002/2003 rain semester 
    results due to crisis went ahead to write the 2003/2004 Harmattan 
    examination achieved a CGPA of 1<punctuation>.</punctuation>00 through that 
    examination.</p>
    <p>You do not need to bring your CPU to the Computer Centre. Please 
    follow these steps for a successful downloading and updating:</p>
    <p>1. Using My Computer or Windows Explorer go to ISIS folder on 
    your PC and rename the present executable file (one with the icons 
    of 2 students) to ISIS2 or whatever.</p>
    <p>2. Go to this URL</p>
    <p><x-anonym-x/></p>
    <p>(Copy and paste in your browser and press ENTER)</p>
    <p>3. Click on the ISIS<punctuation>.</punctuation>EXE link</p>
    <p>4. A File Download dialog box will appear. Navigate to your ISIS 
    folder and download the new ISIS executable.</p>
    <p>4. Log in to ISIS package and proceed to Semester Initialization 
    as usual.</p>
    <p>5. If you have already moved to Harmattan 2005/2006 with the 
    previous version, you will have to select option 2 to initialize 
    the Previous semesters first. Do that successively until you get to 
    Rain 2003/2004. Then select option 1 successively to initialize to 
    Harmattan 2005/2006.</p>
    <p>If you however encounter any problem, feel free to contact the 
    following people at the Computer Centre:</p>
    <p>1. Mr<punctuation>.</punctuation> <x-anonym-x type="family-name"/> X<punctuation>.</punctuation> X. (Rom 
    M24)</p>
    <p>2. Mr<punctuation>.</punctuation> <x-anonym-x type="family-name"/> X<punctuation>.</punctuation> X.(Room 
    M27)</p>
    <p>3. Mr<punctuation>.</punctuation> <x-anonym-x type="family-name"/> X<punctuation>.</punctuation> X. 
    (Students&apos; Laboratory)</p>
    <p>Thank you.</p>
    <p><x-anonym-x type="family-name"/> X<punctuation>.</punctuation> X.</p>
    <p>Computer Centre.</p>
    <p>If you have already been given the new executable, please ignore 
    this.</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
