<?xml version='1.0'?>

<annotated version="1.0">
  <meta>
    <transcriber>ug</transcriber>
    <date>1998-04-02</date>
    <place>Ile-Ife</place>
    <author><gender>?</gender><age>?</age><ethnic-group>Yoruba</ethnic-group></author>
  </meta>
  <text>
    <p>Dear Mr<punctuation>.</punctuation> <x-anonym-x type="family-name"/>,</p>
    <heading>Admission to Postgraduate Degree</heading>
    <heading>Courses 1997/98 Session</heading>
    <p>I refer to your application for Postgraduate admission and I am 
    pleased to inform you that as of 3rd March, 1998 you have been 
    offered admission to the Faculty of Arts Department of English to 
    pursue a Ph<punctuation>.</punctuation>D<punctuation>.</punctuation> Degree in English with effect from 
    April, 1998.</p>
    <p>Your mode of study will be Full Time.</p>
    <p>You will be required to discuss your programme with the Head of 
    your Department and to comply with the attached procedure for 
    registration.</p>
    <p>Please note that you should also register for each semester 
    until the degree is awarded by the University Senate. This entails 
    your filling the appropriate forms and paying the prescribed fees. 
    Fees are expected to be paid at the beginning of each session in 
    accordance with the attached schedule.</p>
    <p>If you accept this offer, you should remit a non-refundable 
    deposit of N250 Bank Draft to the Secretary of the Postgraduate 
    College within a month of the receipt of this letter.</p>
    <p>All requests for deferment will be treated purely on their 
    merit. This offer of admission will lapse if you have not 
    registered nor requested for deferment within the University 
    approved for registration.</p>
    <p>Health Forms for your completion and submission to the Chief 
    Medical Officer must be collected during registration.</p>
    <p>Please accept my congratulations.</p>
    <p>Yours faithfully,</p>
    <p><signature /></p>
    <p>X<punctuation>.</punctuation> X<punctuation>.</punctuation> <x-anonym-x type="family-name"/></p>
    <p>Secretary</p>
    <p>Postgraduate College</p>
  </text>
</annotated>
